[GRUNTS]
MAN:
Psst.
LEE [lN CHINESE]:
[GRUNTlNG]
[SANG SHOUTS lN CHINESE]
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
[GUNSHOTS]
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
[BOAT ENGlNE CHUGGlNG]
MAN:
Forgive me, Consul Han...
...but l believe we can ill afford
to lose men of your high character.
And speaking as a friend...
...who's fought side by side
with you for 1 5 years...
...l will sorely miss
the unshakable support...
...you've given
the Royal Hong Kong Police.
And so on behalf of all Brits...
...who have ever carried the shield
in Hong Kong, we shall miss you.
We wish you happiness...
...as you take up your new post
in the United States.
Ladies and gentlemen, Consul Han.
GUESTS:
Consul Han.
HAN:
Thank you, Thomas.
Now, you know Thomas is not going
to make this evening easy.
[IN ENGLlSH]
Excuse me.
[WHlSPERlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
Commander Griffin...
...l am pleased to be able
to leave you and Hong Kong...
...with a special gift tonight.
Earlier this evening,
Detective Inspector Lee...
...and his special task force
have once and for all...
...crushed the Juntao criminal
organization and reclaimed artifacts...
...from 5000 years of China's heritage.
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
This is the kind of legacy I dreamt about.
Hong Kong forever.
To Hong Kong forever.
GUESTS:
Hong Kong forever.
[GRUNTS]
Soo Yung.
[IN CHlNESE]
[CAR HORN HONKS]
MAN 1 :
Stupid fool! Get the hell out of my way!
Man, are you crazy?
-Shoot!
MAN 2: You moron!
Clive, what's up, man?
-You're late.
-Huh?
You're late.
-l'm late?
-Yeah, you're late.
You're late, man. l've been waiting
in the back for over an hour.
-l was in the diner.
-Man, l told you in the back.
Think l would do this shit out front?
-l'm gonna get busted.
-You weren't in the diner.
I said in the back of the d--
It don't even matter.
I'm late, you late. Let's do this.
What's that, a gun?
Put that away.
How many people you killed this year?
-Stop it, man. Let's do it. Come on.
-Don't be late again.
I ain't gonna be late. Come on.
What we got?
Hoo-hoo.
That's tight. That's beautiful.
That's nice. What's that?
-That's C-4.
-That's C-4?
That's C-4.
-Oh, shit.
-What's the problem?
No problem. I been looking
everywhere for this shit.
Man, how the hell you find some C-4?
You don't know how you make me feel,
man. The lraqis can't even get this shit.
-Where'd you get this from?
-lt's a hot ticket.
CARTER: You don't know how happy
you made me.
You got what l want.
Let me go get that money, man.
Step away from the car.
Hey, officers.
OFFlCER: Put your hands above your heads.
Just do it now.
CARTER: Ain't no problem here.
Why y'all messing with us for?
All right, take it easy.
-You don't wanna do that.
-Yes, I do.
-No, he don't. He's playing.
-No, I ain't playing.
-Yes, he is, officer.
-No, I'm not. l'm not playing!
-Drop the gun!
-He's just my cousin. We're just talking.
Get back in the car and leave.
Can't do that, buddy.
I'll blow his head all over the parking lot!
-Get in the car and buy some doughnuts!
CARTER: See? You made him mad.
Let me just talk to him. All right?
OFFlCER 1 : Hey!
OFFlCER 2: Don't move!
All right. All right. Everything cool now.
He down. The gun down.
Now get back in the car and just leave.
-Put your hands on your head!
-Everything's cool, officer.
Do it now!
OFFlCER 2:
My arm!
Didn't l tell you to get in the car?
[GUNSHOT]
[CAR HORNS HONKlNG]
Man, stop it! l got C-4 in the trunk!
Yeah!
Hoo-hoo.
Clive, guess what, man.
I forgot to tell you. I'm L.A.P.D.
You under arrest.
HAN:
Soo Yung, come on, we're gonna be late.
Let's go.
WOMAN:
Excuse me.
-What?
-Telephone. China.
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
Soo Yung, I love you. Have a nice day.
[IN ENGLlSH]
Will you be home after school?
No.
I am going to pick you up myself.
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
-Bye.
[IN CHlNESE]
[IN ENGLlSH]
Hello?
[PHONE LlNE CLlCKS]
[MARlAH CAREY'S "FANTASY" PLAYING
ON RADIO]
[SINGlNG]
Oh, when you walk by every night
Talking sweet and looking fine
I get kinda hectic inside
Baby, I'm so into you
Darling, if you only knew
All the things that flow through my mind
WOMAN [SlNGING ON RADlO]:
But it's just a sweet, sweet fantasy, baby
When I close my eyes
SOO YUNG:
You come and you take me
On and on and on
WOMAN:
So deep in my daydreams
But it's just a sweet, sweet fantasy, baby
Is there a problem, officer?
No problem.
Just rush hour.
[SCREAMlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
SOO YUNG:
Help!
HAN: Security's in place?
WOMAN: Yes.
You're sure all the exhibits
will be ready this weekend?
Yes, sir. Your opening remarks
are scheduled for 7:30.
HAN: Fine.
-Excuse me, Consul Han.
I'm Warren Russ with the
Federal Bureau of Investigation.
This is Agent Whitney.
We need to speak with you in private, sir.
Excuse me.
I know this is difficult...
...but l want you to know
we'll get your daughter back.
Yes, but will you get her back alive?
We have the best agents in the world
in this house, on those streets.
I would like one of my people to help.
Let me assure you, consul,
the FBI considers this a top priority.
We have plenty of people on the case.
Mr. Russ, I am not an American.
My daughter, she is not an American.
-l understand that, sir, but--
-He's already on the plane.
I trust you will treat him
with the same courtesy...
...as you have shown me.
Yes, sir.
Ten people jumped out.
I started handling them.
Throwing them everywhere.
Then two stupid cops
came out of nowhere...
...messed everything up.
Had to save their life.
It might be in the paper. It ain't in there.
Anyway, I save their life.
I start running to get the bomb--
-l can't believe you went without me.
-l'll talk to y'all later, all right?
I'll tell you the best part after work.
This is why nobody will work with you...
...why you're the only cop in the
department without a partner.
Johnson, look, first of all,
if you wanna go out on a date with me...
...you have to wait
like every other woman.
And second of all, l work alone.
I don't need no partner
and l ain't gonna never have no partner.
-Did Kojak have a partner?
-The fat guy.
He wasn't never with him.
Look, did Columbo?
Captain ordered me
to go with you...
...because you needed
backup, but once again...
...you screwed me and screwed yourself.
Look, Johnson, it's dangerous out there.
It's safer for you to be behind the desk.
We were supposed to be
on the same team.
Team? Johnson, this is the L.A.P.D.
We the most hated cops
in the free world.
My mama ashamed of me.
Tells everybody l'm a drug dealer.
Ain't no team. This is a pit stop for me.
I'm on the verge of leaving you behind.
Actually, you're on the verge
of being suspended.
Have a nice day.
Johnson.
Somebody told you
I was being suspended?
[JOHNSON CLEARS THROAT]
Quit playing, girl.
I know you playing.
Who told you l was being suspended?
This is a problem. That's all l need...
...some foreigner getting his head blown off
and creating an international incident.
What can we do? He's on his way.
Call the field office.
Have them send a rookie.
We'll have him escort this guy
around a few days...
...pretend to follow leads,
show him some sights...
-...keep him out of our way.
-You want to do that to one of our men?
What do you suggest?
Well, as long as we're
gonna humiliate someone...
...might as well be L.A.P.D.
Even if l had an extra man, who would
want such a bullshit assignment?
Well, it's a disgrace to me.
It's a disgrace to my department.
It's a disgrace to--
Dan, I'm sending someone right over.
Captain, I know you read
the paper, but they lying.
I wouldn't do nothing like that. You know
how the paper is. They just want a story.
Two officers were shot.
One man lost a pinkie.
But didn't nobody die.
-You destroyed half a block.
-That block was messed up.
-You lost a lot of evidence.
-We got a little left.
What you did was dangerous
and completely against policy.
And not only that...
...you did a good job.
What?
Everyone here is so image-conscious.
Everybody's so afraid
of their own goddamn shadow.
It's nice to meet an L.A. detective
who's willing to lay it on the line.
Captain, that's the same way l feel. That's
what I've been trying to tell everybody.
Every so often, we have to let
the general public know...
...that we can still blow shit up.
You goddamn right.
That's the only way l work.
-Mm.
-So I ain't getting suspended?
-Are you kidding?
-l don't even know why l said that.
I just got a call from the FBI.
The daughter of a Chinese diplomat...
...was kidnapped this morning,
and they want you on the case.
-FBl want me?
-That's right.
-Stop lying.
-l don't lie.
-Tell the truth.
-l'm telling the truth.
Thank you, captain. Whoo!
Congratulations, Carter.
You are going to the show.
I'm gonna look out for you
when l go to the top.
-l'm gonna make you mayor. Whoo.
-l'd rather you didn't.
Hey, listen up! lf anybody need me...
...l'm gonna be working
a big, big case for the FBl!
Whoo.
Yo. Take care of that for me.
Carter.
Yo. l need one of those earpieces
immediately, all right?
Hey, how you doing?
I want consul's personnel
records cross-checked...
...with that new list
we received from lnterpol.
See if you can make
any matches or connections.
Okay, boys, what do we got?
Have we checked the personnel records?
I wanna know who's he been
talking with, dealing with.
Come on. Give me the story.
Any demands? Any fingerprints?
Have we interviewed his staff?
Whitney, who is this?
Give me a copy of that.
James Carter, FBl.
Warren, he's here
for the special assignment.
Oh.
I'm Agent-ln-Charge Warren Russ.
-Good to have you.
-Waited a long time for this.
You guys sure do take a long time
to process an application.
Well, Carter,
your particular assignment...
...is considered G-14 classified.
Now, why don't you and I
take a walk and I'll fill you in?
Okay, Warren.
G-14 classified.
That's good.
CARTER: You don't understand.
This is my dream.
I'm very excited
about working with the FBl.
Well, l'm glad. Listen, his name is Lee.
And the director considers this
a top priority.
No disrespect, but he's only
gonna get in my way.
I'm not used to having a partner.
If l'm handling the situation,
I'm gonna have to work alone.
Carter, he is the situation.
Must be-- Must be a misunderstanding.
I was sent down here for
the kidnapping. The little girl?
Forget the little girl.
Your assignment is Lee.
Who is Lee? What assignment is that?
Lee is a foreign detective
and a friend of the consul's.
Now, it's your job to keep him out of sight
and away from danger, you understand?
I understand you want me to babysit,
but I don't do that.
-l came here for the big assignment.
-The truth is, this is an FBl operation...
...and l don't need any help from the
L.A.P.D. or some Chungking cop.
You got it?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold, hold.
Why not use your men
for this top-priority case?
The hell I supposed to do with him?
I don't give a damn. l don't want to
see him or you till this thing is resolved.
Now, his plane arrives in an hour.
We want to make
a good impression, Carter.
It's his first trip to America.
Hey.
This is bullshit!
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
Please tell me you speak English.
I'm Detective Carter.
Do you speak any English?
Do you understand the words
that are coming out of my mouth?
I cannot believe this shit!
First, I get a bullshit assignment
now Mr. Rice-A-Roni...
...don't even speak American.
Come on, man. My ride over here.
Put your bag in the back.
Put your bag in the back!
No, no, no.
You put your own shit in the back!
I am not a skycap.
I'm FBl, you understand?
What the hell you think this is?
Captain, I don't think this is funny.
No, I'm serious, captain. I ain't playing.
Tell the FBI you made a mistake.
I can't do that, Carter.
I'm sure that you and Mr. Lee
will have a nice time together.
I'm warning you, you better call the FBl
or l drop his ass at Panda Express.
You drop this case, you're suspended
for two months without pay.
All right, well, you can forget
about being mayor then.
Congratulations, Carter. Looks like
you finally got yourself a partner.
[ALL LAUGHING]
One little pinkie get blowed off
and everybody tripping.
Chinese consul?
That's one of the places you can't go.
I ain't getting fired.
You gonna pay my bills?
LEE:
Soo Yung.
That's the little girl?
Huh? Huh?
Say something.
Y'all think this is real funny.
Give Carter the big G-14 classified case.
Gonna show the FBI
they don't know who they playing with.
I'll solve this case myself.
That's right.
CARTER: But l wanna show you
something first. Look familiar?
Just like home, ain't it?
Look. Just like home.
I ain't never been to China,
but it probably look like this.
Star maps! Get your star maps!
Look, look, look, John Wayne.
-John Wayne? You know John Wayne?
-John Wayne.
CARTER: Yeah, John Wayne, man.
Hang out with the Duke.
I'll be back.
You might see one of your cousins.
-Be right back.
STUCKY: Find them and stalk them!
Find them and stalk them! Star maps!
-Right here! Star maps, people!
-Stucky.
Stucky.
You got the address to Michael
Jackson's house? Neverland?
You can't be coming around my job!
That's harassment!
-l'm just checking up on you.
-l'm fully legit now. I'm selling star maps.
CARTER:
Yeah, legit my ass.
What you and your Asian gang friends
talking about? Know about a kidnapping?
I don't know nothing.
Give me one of them star maps...
...for $45, understand what l mean?
All right, man.
I don't know nothing about no kidnapping...
...but this dude's buying firearms,
explosives, and people...
-...like he's starting a war.
-His name?
-l don't know.
-You don't know?
For $45, l don't know.
-You better tell me something.
-Don't know nothing for $45.
Stucky, you don't--
-l didn't tell you nothing!
-Lee!
Lee!
Lee.
Didn't l tell you to wait for me? Huh?
What the hell you doing on this bus?
Think l'm playing with you?
I ain't playing with you. Sit down.
All right. lt's okay.
It's all right. FBl.
Take a picture. It's okay. Wait a minute.
[TOURlSTS MURMURlNG AND LAUGHlNG]
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
All right.
What? Get out of my way!
Watch out! Watch out!
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
FBI. Stop this bus.
BOY:
Hey, look.
[CHILDREN LAUGHlNG]
DAD:
Hey, kids, get back in here. Sit down.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
CARTER:
Stop!
-FBl, I need this motorcycle.
-No way.
Get off!
[HORN HONKS]
Get out of the car.
Get out of the car now!
Where you think you're going?
Didn't l say to stay by the Duke?
-Hey, what do you think you're doing?
-Mind your own business. Stay in the car.
Hey. What you doing? l was just trying
to find out where you was going, man.
-You thought l was gonna shoot you?
-Hey, what's happening here?
Put the gun down. Put the gun down.
I ain't playing with you, man.
-You think l'm playing with you?
-Don't move.
Drop your guns.
CARTER:
Hey, man.
Look. FBI.
[IN ENGLlSH]
I'm policeman.
I'm just showing him how
to take a gun from a suspect.
All of a sudden you speaking English?
-A little.
-A little, my ass. You lied to me.
I didn't say I didn't.
You assumed l didn't.
Assume I kick your Beijing ass right now.
I ain't scared of you.
I know you know that tricky shit.
I'm not responsible for your assumption.
You full of shit, you understand that?
Full of shit.
Not being able to speak
is not the same as not speaking.
You seem as if you like to talk.
I let people talk who like to talk.
It makes it easier to find out
how full of shit they are.
What the hell did you just say?
I let people to talk....
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
So l'm the one full of shit?
We both full of shit.
You full of shit.
I'm gonna kick your ass.
Don't nobody do that but me.
You want me to kick your ass,
don't you?
Take me to see Consul Han right away.
Man, just sit there and shut up.
This ain't no democracy.
-Yes, it is.
-No, it ain't.
This is the United States
of James Carter now.
I'm the president,
I'm the emperor, I'm the king.
I'm Michael Jackson, you Tito.
Your ass belong to me.
Why would they not want my help?
Because they don't give a damn
about you.
They don't like you. l don't like you.
I don't care. I'm here for the girl.
The girl don't like you. Nobody likes you.
You came all the way over here for nothing.
You ain't gonna be--
MAN [SINGlNG ON RADIO]:
At Waimea Bay
Beach Boys.
Oh, hell, no.
You didn't just touch my goddamn radio.
The Beach Boys
are great American music.
The Beach Boys'll get you
a great ass-whooping.
Don't you ever touch
a black man's radio, boy.
You can do that in China but you'll
get your ass killed out here, man.
Let me show you real music.
[HlP-HOP MUSIC PLAYlNG]
Yeah. That's real music. You hear that?
MAN [SINGlNG]: Bounce with me
Bounce with me
WOMAN [RAPPING]:
You ain't gotta be rich but bump that
How we gonna get around
On your bus pass?
'Fo l put this on your mustache
Can you afford me
My homies breadwinners?
Now can you do that to the Beach Boys?
Can you do that to the Beach Boys?
Hell, no.
WOMAN:
Better get up, get out, get some
l like a lot of Prada....
I must get to the consulate.
What are we doing here?
It's called a shakedown.
Very serious police work.
Just watch me handle my business
and control the space.
I want to help with the investigation.
This is my case.
[LAUGHlNG]
Your case? Look, you can back me up.
When we get in here, you follow my lead
and do what l do. Okay?
[BLUES MUSlC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
-What's up, my nigga?
-What's up?
-ls this weed?
-What?
You got a prescription for this?
Where is that?
-Uh.... lt's-- lt's--
-Where is that?
Where? Wh--?
-l left it--
-l-- l--
Uh, uh, where? Where?
-l should take your ass to jail.
-For what?
For what? Look at this!
-That's nothing but a cigarette.
-This ciga-weed!
It look like a cigarette.
-You better have glaucoma.
-l do.
CARTER:
What's up, my nigga?
[BUZZER RINGS]
LUKE:
Hey, hey, check that, baby.
What's happening, Carter?
[GRUNTS]
Put the guns down. Put the guns down!
MC Hammer there,
put the goddamn gun down.
I got some questions,
and l need some answers.
-Put them down. Down.
-Where the girl?
-What girl?
-The little girl.
-What little girl?
-Little Chinese girl.
-Don't know nothing about no Chinese girl.
-Don't act like you don't know.
I'll take your asses in
if l don't get answers.
-Carter, put the gun down.
-Don't act like you know me.
You don't know me.
I see what's going on here.
Y'all trying to play me like a fool.
All right, Lee, go outside real quick.
It's gonna get a little dangerous in here.
-l may have ques--
-Lee, go and wait by the bar.
Remember what I told you? Back me up.
Go outside. l'll take care of everything.
-You're sure?
-l'm sure. Now, go on now.
Go on!
Think l'm playing?
Hurry up!
[LAUGHS]
[SIGHS]
-Come here.
-Don't come up in my business...
-...scaring me like that. Goddamn.
-l was just playing. Man, give me a hug.
Schooling the rookie,
showing him the ropes.
Why you didn't come to church Sunday?
I had some things to take care of.
But l made the night service.
-Look, come here, l wanna holler at you.
-What's up?
I need to know who this guy is buying up
all these explosives and weapons.
-l don't know nothing about that, baby.
-Luke. Look, man, I know what you do.
Only reason why I ain't busted you because
you my cousin, and it'd kill Aunt Bootsy.
-Why you gonna put Aunt Bootsy in this?
-Luke, I ain't playing.
I know she got a bad heart,
but if l have to, l'll bust your ass.
Tell me something.
The word down in Chinatown is
there's this new dude in town.
Bad-ass dude out of Hong Kong
buying up every goddamn thing.
-What's his name?
-Don't know. He ain't buying shit from me.
-You don't know his name?
-No.
Nobody know his name.
What's up, my nigga?
What did you just say?
[GRUNTlNG]
MAN: Come here!
You better watch your mouth!
What you say, boy?
I don't want trouble.
Ow.
Please. I said I don't want trouble.
That's bad for you.
Carter.
-Where the little girl?
-What little girl?
CARTER:
You know what girl l'm talking about.
You better take
your goddamn hands off my suit.
Your mama bought me this for Christmas.
This is my favorite suit. Now, let me go.
I'll see you Thanksgiving, all right?
Appreciate it.
Hey, hey! Get your big
Happy-Meal ass over!
Get over in the corner!
I'm still the law around here!
Next time l come here,
y'all better clean this up!
And brush your teeth!
Let's go.
LEE: What are we doing?
CARTER: l'm getting something to eat.
You want anything,
like a Cup O'Noodles or something?
Carter, stop wasting my time.
I made a promise to Soo Yung.
You're right.
I have been wasting your time.
I'm sorry. Just let me
go in here and get something to eat.
When I come back out, l'll take
you wherever you want to go. Okay?
-Okay.
-Shake on it?
What are you doing?
You ain't the only one
with quick hands, are you? Wah.
I'll be right back.
Hey, man, l got you
a beef-and-bean burrito.
We have a taxicab approaching.
A man stepping out. Asian. About 5'1 0".
We've got someone approaching the gate.
Dropped off by a cab.
-Tell them to intercept.
-lntercept.
We will intercept.
Can l help you?
-Yes. I must see the consul.
-About what?
Please, it's very important.
Why don't you tell us why
you need to see the consul, huh?
-We'll tell you whether it's important.
-Do you have identification?
It's about his daughter, Soo Yung.
Hands above your head!
-He asked about the daughter.
You don't understand. I was invited.
[GRUNTlNG]
Don't move! Throw your gun away.
WHlTNEY: He's gonna kill them.
-ls everything all right?
WHlTNEY:
You'll be safer on the second floor.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry about this.
He went over.
GUARD 1 :
Let's go!
GUARD 2:
He's on the grounds! Come on!
WHlTNEY: Stay away from the window,
please. Right here.
[CLATTERlNG]
Get down! Now!
[GRUNTlNG]
Don't move!
HAN:
Lee.
[IN CHlNESE]
[IN ENGLlSH] Mr. Russ. l think
there has been a misunderstanding.
It's all right. lt's okay.
It's him. The guy from China.
-What?
-Come in, please.
Mr. Russ...
...l would like you to meet
Detective Inspector Lee.
Excuse me very much.
Oh, yes.
Your gun.
Where the hell is Carter?
Then l gotta put up with this.
Seen a little Asian dude
about this height...
...with a steering wheel on his arm?
Go screw yourself.
-What you say?
-l said go screw yourself.
Take your little sensitive ass
up there and let me in! Out of the way!
-Don't make me get up!
-Let this putz in.
CARTER: Man, when I get up in here,
I'm slapping somebody. l don't play that.
RUSS:
What happened, Carter?
CARTER:
It ain't my job to be jumping off of buses!
I do not do that! l am not Carl Lewis!
HAN:
Who is this man?
Sir, l can explain.
LEE [lN ENGLlSH]: Agent Carter
has been helping with my investigation.
He's upset that we have not
done our job.
Me and Lee are taking care of the situation.
We have everything under control.
We'll get your daughter back
safe and sound.
He is very passionate
about finding your daughter.
HAN:
I owe you my gratitude.
We wanted Detective Lee to have
one of our best men by his side at all time.
Agent Russ, maybe this is a good time to
tell the consul the details of my assignment.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
Carter, can I speak to you
for a moment?
You wanna speak to me?
For a moment? ln private?
Oh, l see. This must be G-14 classified.
FBI-type stuff.
Let me call my captain
and let him know what's going on.
We'll talk in a second. G-14.
[PHONE RlNGS]
-l love when a G-14 comes around.
MAN [OVER PHONE]: Hello?
Who's this? Hello?
Am l speaking with FBl?
-Give me the phone.
-FBl? Yeah, this is the FBl.
-You are FBI?
-Yeah, this is the FBl.
If you want the girl back alive,
listen and do not talk.
Okay, l'm listening. Let me get a pen.
All right. Cool.
The drop will be made tonight.
Eleven p.m.
The amount will be $50 million.
Fifty million dollars? Who you think
you kidnapped, Chelsea Clinton?
RUSS: Keep him talking.
SANG: In used currency.
Nothing bigger than a 50.
All right. Cool, cool, cool.
Fifty million dollars. No problem.
I want 20 million in 50--
Twenty million in 50s.
--20 million in 20--
Twenty million in 20s.
--and 1 0 million in 1 0.
And 1 0 million in 1 0s.
You want any fries with that?
What is your name?
What's yours? You called us.
Why you wanna know my name?
I want to be able to tell
the consul who is responsible...
...for his daughter's death
because he talk too much.
All right, look, man. Hold up. Calm down.
I'm trying to hook you up.
I'm on your side.
You will receive instructions for the drop
half an hour before it is to be made.
If it is successful, the girl will live.
I'm gonna make sure you get the money.
We can spend it together when you get it...
...because I don't
even really work for them.
We got it.
620 South Broadway. Downtown.
Tactical team one, proceed down
6th to 6th and Broadway.
Team two, I want you around
the back on 4th and Main.
Set up a perimeter.
WHlTNEY:
Take your team and cover the building...
...floor by floor all the way to the top.
Move.
AGENT: Two men around back.
-They must not go into the building.
Yeah, you right. Right.
Let's go tell them. Come on.
WHlTNEY:
Take positions on the corner.
Mr. Russ, you must pull your men back.
What the hell are you doing here?
Where's Carter?
LEE: Please, listen to me.
RUSS: Mr. Lee...
...you may be very competent,
but the mere fact...
...that you know this girl
compromises your judgment.
Sir, if you were asking for $50 million...
...would you be in a place like that?
Get this clown away from me.
Take a hike.
-Hey, man.
-Why were you hiding?
-What you talking about? I wasn't.
-You were hiding.
I bent down to tie my shoe.
Looked up, you're gone.
AGENT:
Sir, the area is secured.
- [OVER RADIO] Room's empty.
-Damn it!
[RlNGS]
[PHONE RlNGS OVER RADIO]
Everybody pull back!
Goddamn!
RUSS:
Get some paramedics down here now!
Evacuate the building right away!
Get fire crews here!
We got an explosion
at 6th and Broadway.
Lee!
That ain't far enough, man!
I ain't Kareem Abdul-Jabbar!
Push it down some more!
[GRUNTlNG]
CARTER:
Lee!
Hey, Lee!
-Carter, don't come any-- Stop!
-Hey!
Hey, man, what the hell you--?
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[TlRES SCREECHING]
[GUNSHOTS]
[GUN CLlCKlNG]
I think I done broke my shit.
Who was that you was chasing?
His name is Sang from Hong Kong.
-Because of you he got away.
-Why you didn't tell me about the bridge?
-l did.
-No, you didn't.
-No, you did not.
-l said stop.
-l don't understand what you be saying.
What?
You see what I'm saying?
What's this in your hand?
He dropped it.
Oh, shit.
-Come on.
-Where are we going?
I messed up my suit.
Fifteen seconds.
Make a decision.
[PANTlNG]
-Johnson!
-Huh!
Oh, shit!
Did I come at a bad time?
I got bad news for you, Johnson.
We're all dead.
I was distracted, sir.
Distractions can occur in the field.
That's why we call this practice.
If you can't handle
the pressure, then quit.
-Yes, sir.
-Hey, man, give her a break.
Don't worry about him. How you doing,
girl? What's going on? Give me some love.
-Why are you tormenting me?
-That any way to treat an old friend?
I came to see how you was doing,
and l need some help.
Help? Ha. Heh, heh.
I know that you have strong feelings
for me, baby, but we gotta put that aside.
A little girl's life is at stake.
Since when do care about
anybody else but yourself?
Please just take a look
at this for a second.
We found this on a kidnapper.
Tell me what this is.
Now you want me to work with you?
I don't have time for this.
I got my own shit to deal with.
Johnson. Johnson. Johnson.
-Who are you?
-Sorry we got you in trouble.
Yeah, he's sorry. Look, tell me something
about this l don't know.
A remote. Could be nitro cap,
could be cross-delayed...
...definitely not homemade,
not American.
It could open up a garage door,
or blow up some C-4.
C-4?
Yeah, C-4.
-Okay. Get out. Go, go, go.
CARTER: This means so much to me.
I'm sorry about
spreading all those rumors...
...on Christmas about us
sleeping together.
What?
He's just joking.
Bye.
CARTER:
Hey, Bobby, what's up, man?
-l need to see Clive Cod, man.
-Oh. No way, Carter.
It's lights out. They're locked down.
You want me to lose my job?
I'm the one that got you this damn job.
You better let me in here.
-Can't do it.
-Bobby.
Didn't l turn my back when
you bought that bag of weed?
I was splitting it with you.
But didn't l give you the bigger half?
Come on, Bobby. Now, do me this favor.
Shit. You got five minutes.
-Hey, Cod.
CLIVE: Huh?
Your two brothers are here to see you.
CARTER:
Hey, Clive, how you doing, man?
You got balls coming here.
I was just around the way.
Figured you'd be bored.
I came down here
to see how you was doing.
What the hell do you want?
I just came to bring you a gift.
I know you got time on your hands.
I brought you a toy.
-l don't want that.
-You don't?
Someone told me you like this stuff.
I don't like stuff like that.
I don't even know what it is.
-You never sold this to nobody?
-How could I, when I don't know what it is?
-Hold it.
-l don't want to hold it.
-Just touch it. Why?
-l don't want to touch it.
-You scared of it?
-You think l'm stupid?
-Stupid enough to get busted.
-You want fingerprints to frame me.
Clive, why would I do that?
Think l would try tricking you again?
Besides, l don't have to frame you.
You gonna do life for killing the little girl.
-l don't know anything about a little girl.
-That ain't what l'll tell everybody.
-l don't care. l don't know anything.
-l got a big mouth.
Let me tell you something. I don't know
anything, so you can kiss my fat ass.
Clive, it'd take me all day
to kiss your ass.
What are you gonna do? You want
some of this? l'll give you all you want.
-Give me a name.
-l ain't telling you shit.
She's only 1 1 years old.
I don't want her to die.
Look at the picture.
I don't care about him, I don't care
about you. l care about the little girl.
Give me the name.
The guy's name is Juntao.
I never seen him.
Where can I find him?
Foo Chow Restaurant. Chinatown.
CARTER:
Foo Chow Restaurant?
Get rid of this guy. He'll get you killed.
Clive, thank you, man.
I'm gonna come back next time.
I'm gonna bring your fat ass
some cookies, man.
That's it right there.
What are we waiting for?
We scoping the place out, man.
Ain't gonna run up in there.
That's how you get shot.
I'm falling asleep.
[EDWlN STARR'S "WAR" PLAYlNG
ON RADIO]
MAN [SINGlNG ON RADIO]:
War, huh, yeah
CHORUS:
What is it good for?
MAN: Absolutely--
CHORUS: Nothing
MAN: Uh-huh, uh-huh
CHORUS: War
[SINGlNG]
Huh, yeah
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
MAN: Say it again
LEE: You all
CHORUS: War
LEE: Huh
Absolutely what is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Sing it again, you all
War, huh, yeah
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
-You don't know nothing about no "War."
-Everybody knows "War."
[SINGlNG]
Huh, yeah
What it is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Good God! You all
It ain't you all, it's y'all.
-Y'all.
Y'all.
-Man, you sound like a karate movie. Y'all!
-Y'all.
Say it from here with soul. Y'all.
-Let me show your goofy ass how to do it.
MAN [SINGlNG ON RADIO]:
Huh, good God, y'all
[SINGlNG]
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Come on. Come on.
War, huh
-Yeah
CHORUS: What is it good for?
CARTER:
Absolutely nothing
Come on. Come on.
-War, huh
MAN: It ain't nothing but a heartbreak
CHORUS: War
MAN: Friend only....
Come on. Come on.
Unh.
CHORUS: War
MAN: It's an enemy
To all mankind
Do that again.
Do it again. Like this?
MAN:
War has caused unrest
Within the younger generation
Induction then destruction
Who wants to die?
Oh!
CHORUS: War, huh
MAN: Good God, y'all
CHORUS: What is it good for?
MAN: Absolutely nothing
Listen to me
CHORUS: War
MAN: It ain't nothing but a heartbreaker
MAN: It's got one friend
That's the undertaker
Oh, war has shattered
Many a young man's dreams
Made him disabled
Bitter and mean
Life is much too short and precious
To spend fighting wars these days
War can't give life
It can only take it away
Oh, war, huh
Good God, y'all
One will be inserted into the suitcase.
The other will be on you.
Now, when you make the drop--
[PHONE RlNGING]
Do we have it?
All right, pick it up.
Hello?
SANG: You have what I asked for?
-l do.
I hope now you realize how serious I am.
Take the money to the alley behind
the Foo Chow Restaurant in Chinatown.
You have 29 minutes left.
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
[LEE SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
Damn, Chen, this is some greasy shit.
You ain't got better food?
Chicken wings...
...some baby back ribs,
some fries or something?
Chinese food, no soul food here.
I didn't say soul food. l said better food.
I don't want that greasy shit.
How you gonna sell a big box of grease?
[MAN SPEAKlNG IN CHlNESE]
I'm chilly a what?
LEE:
Come on.
MAN: l'm no punk bitch.
CARTER: l ain't no punk bitch neither.
-l'm no punk.
CARTER: l'll knock your hat off.
LEE: Come on.
-Man, what you got me eating?
-That's eel.
-ls it good?
Very good.
What you got?
-Camel's hump.
-What?
Camel's hump.
CARTER:
Mm.
Kind of good.
Need a little hot sauce,
but it's kind of good, though.
-We still waiting?
-Yeah.
How we gonna go about getting Juntao?
How we know he exists?
Ain't nobody seen him before.
I know. He killed my partner.
I'm sorry about that, man.
That's one reason l have no partner.
That's one thing l learned from my daddy.
-Your daddy was a policeman?
-Fifteen years, L.A.P.D.
My father was also a policeman.
-Your daddy was a cop?
-Not a cop, an officer.
A legend all over Hong Kong.
My daddy a legend too. All over America.
My daddy once arrested 1 5 people
in one night by himself.
My daddy arrest 25 by himself.
My daddy saved five crackheads
from a burning building by himself.
My daddy once caught a bullet
with his bare hands.
My daddy'll kick your daddy's ass
all the way from here to China...
...or Japan or wherever the hell you from.
-Don't talk about my father.
-Don't talk about my daddy.
Hey, that your boy?
LEE:
Yes. Let's go.
I'll go in first.
Ain't nobody gonna recognize me.
Okay. l'll wait five minutes.
CARTER:
Hey, you take my ID.
If anything go wrong,
you bust in like you're L.A.P.D.
This won't work. l'm not 6'1 ".
Yes, it will work.
Look, man, it's all about attitude.
Flip it open, flip it closed.
Do it fast. Open, close. Do it fast.
You'll get it. Look.
Take this.
Hey, man, act like
you're from out of town.
I am from out of town.
Well, don't act like a cop.
Act like a tourist.
-Don't be so obvious.
-Okay.
-All right?
-Okay, no problem.
[HOSTESS SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
Hey, how you doing?
-For one?
-No, for two.
I'm here for a meeting with Mr. Juntao.
Oh. l'm sorry, l don't know Mr. Juntao.
You don't understand.
I'm Mr. Juntao's lawyer. Legal advisor.
He done got into some shit again.
I'm a very busy man.
I ain't got time
to be coming down here late.
My wife wants me to come home,
baby's shitting all over.
Would you please get Mr. Juntao?
-But l have already told you I don't know--
-You think l came here for nothing?
You gonna give me gas money?
You got $5 on you?
Would you please tell
Mr. Juntao to get his ass down here?
Thank you.
Can l sit right here?
-Right here? Thank you.
HOSTESS: Yes.
WAITRESS: Hi.
-How you doing. Y'all got any eel?
Sure.
How's your camel hump?
MAN:
Excuse me?
WOMAN:
Where is Roscoe's Chicken and Waffles?
-Uh....
MAN: Huh?
WOMAN:
This way?
Uh....
-l'm sorry. I'm from out of town.
WOMAN: Ah.
-Maybe this way. Yeah.
WOMAN: Thank you.
Welcome.
What's that?
No.
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
[IN CHlNESE]
MAN:
No, wait.
Get the girl out of here.
Make sure those two don't leave.
[BOTH SPEAKlNG IN CHlNESE]
[CONTlNUES SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
Juntao will see you.
It's about time.
[SOO YUNG SCREAMS]
SOO YUNG:
Stop it!
Let me go!
Oh, this is tight.
This ain't nothing like downstairs, y'all.
Y'all got it going--
What's up, man? What y'all watching?
Where Juntao at?
Why y'all so quiet?
[GRUNTlNG]
That was childish, man.
That wasn't even called for!
Now, l came down here to see Juntao...
...because he told me to come down here
because l'm his half-brother from Beijing.
Me and him got the same mama.
I'm Blackinese.
We all the same.
Oh, hey, man, wait a minute.
Okay, you gonna kill me?
Okay, put the gun down,
fight me like a man.
That's right, fight me like a man. Shit!
Anybody can shoot somebody.
That's what l'm talking about.
Back, back. Give me some room.
Don't know who you messing with.
I'll knock that yellow--
-Which one of y'all kicked me?
-Me.
Okay. All right.
[GRUNTlNG]
[LEE SPEAKlNG IN CHlNESE]
Hold on. Let's talk about this.
Let's talk about this, man.
Hold it, man.
[SANG SPEAKS lN CHINESE]
No, no. What that mean?
Hey, man, this is a misunderstanding.
Come on, let's pray.
FBI, huh?
CARTER:
No, I ain't FBI.
I'm a security guard, I work at the mall.
Now wipe yourself off.
You're bleeding.
Oh, hell no. No, he just playing, man.
Playing. He ain't mean that.
He meant cut me loose. Let me go.
Don't move!
L.A.P.D.
[GRUNTlNG]
Lee, what you doing?
Lee!
[CHATTERlNG lN CHINESE]
-Watch out!
Behind you.
Carter!
Freeze!
We kicked y'all ass. All y'all.
Y'all got your ass kicked. Ha, ha.
Carter!
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
CARTER:
Oh, shit.
[YELLING]
I'll kill your ass.
[GUN CLlCKS]
[SCREAMS]
CARTER:
Lee! Over here, man!
LEE:
Move! Move!
Is that my gun?
-lt is my gun.
-Let's go.
CARTER: Why you gotta drop
the goddamn badge, huh?
Then you threw the gun out the window.
Come on, this way.
[SIRENS WAlLlNG]
I got everything under control.
Don't worry about nothing.
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph!
CARTER:
It's cool.
RUSS: Why am l not surprised
to find you here, Carter?
Dan, I want these two back
at the consulate immediately.
Let's take a ride, gentlemen.
You better get your hand off me.
Hey, man, he with me.
Hey.
Just let me explain.
I'll start from the top.
We were making the drop.
Han was about to get her back...
...and you two screwed it up.
Wait, what you talking about?
-Didn't you hear what Lee said?
-Mr. Lee is on his way to Hong Kong.
Now get out of here before l file
obstruction ofjustice charges against you.
We was about to solve the case.
You're no longer
on this assignment, Carter.
Case closed.
[IN CHlNESE]
CARTER: Consul Han!
-Sorry, sir.
It was all my fault. Lee would never do
anything to jeopardize your daughter's life.
He loves your daughter.
[IN ENGLlSH]
It's a little too late for apologies.
RUSS:
Consul...
...you have a call.
We're ready.
Okay, pick it up.
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
[IN ENGLlSH] The ransom is now 70 million.
I will call tomorrow with instructions.
You deliver the money or pick up
the body of your daughter.
Please. You must understand.
What happened tonight--
SOO YUNG [OVER PHONE]:
Father!
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
Soo Yung.
[SOO YUNG CRYING]
Please tell them I will do whatever they--
Whatever--
Soo Yung!
Sorry, man.
[IN ENGLlSH]
Be sorry for Soo Yung.
No hard leads.
None.
Listen, we're doing
everything we can here, all right?
Tracing everything that's coming
into this compound.
Excuse me, consul. You have a guest.
Jack, let me get back to you, all right?
HAN:
Thomas.
I'm sorry, my friend.
I couldn't stand by and do nothing.
[KC & THE SUNSHINE BAND'S "GET DOWN
TONlGHT" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
CHORUS [SINGlNG OVER SPEAKERS]:
Do a little dance
[PHONE RlNGING]
Get down tonight
-Hello.
-Hey! What's up, baby?
Man, you got guts calling me.
I'm gonna hang up.
Hey, wait a minute. Don't hang up.
Look, you know what?
You was right about me, all right?
I'm sorry.
-Are you on drugs?
-You was right.
I was egotistic. l was inconsiderate.
-l was self-centered.
-Yeah.
I ain't used to working with partners but
it ain't about me now. It's the little girl.
She gonna die
if we don't help her.
You understand what l'm saying?
Not yet, but keep talking.
Look, l think something
big going down tonight, all right?
I need to find out
where the consul's gonna be.
You think you can help me?
I'll see what l can do.
No. I don't need you to see, Johnson.
I need you to do it. Can you do it?
Okay, Carter.
-All right, one other thing.
-Yeah?
What color panties you got on?
[PHONE LlNE CLlCKS THEN HUMS]
[RlNGlNG]
-Hello?
SANG: Consul Han, I want you to go...
...to the Chinese expo as you planned.
Have the money
in the upstairs control room.
Be sure to make no more mistake.
I understand, but I want
to speak with my daughter!
[PHONE LlNE CLlCKS THEN HUMS]
[WOMAN SPEAKlNG lN FORElGN LANGUAGE
OVER PA]
CARTER: Excuse me.
Who's the captain on this plane?
It don't matter.
You need to go up there...
...tell the captain we got
a problem on the left side.
Something with the engine.
Need a new alternator.
My supervisor said,
"Go on down there, put the alternator on.
Don't let it leave till I come down there."
I suggest you tell the authorities not to
move this plane before the FAA comes...
-...and we all in some shit. Go on!
-Yes.
What are you doing here?
Come on, Lee, get your ass up.
We got work to do.
Go away. I've disgraced myself.
Lee, what about the little girl?
Leave me alone. A man like you
could never understand.
-A man like me?
-You are devoted only to yourself.
You're ashamed of being a police officer.
You dishonor your father's name.
Look, you don't know nothing
about my father.
-You say your father is a legend.
-My father was a legend.
He was killed making a routine
traffic stop in daylight...
...by some punk
who didn't want no ticket...
...when his partner supposed
to back him up but never did.
My father was just as much devoted
as you, and now he's dead.
For what?
A traffic ticket and some punk?
You tell me, what's the honor in that?
You believe your father wasted his life,
that he died for nothing?
Prove me wrong.
For 1 5 years until China
resumed control of Hong Kong...
...Juntao was the most powerful
crime lord in Southeast Asia.
The British tried to close down
his operation, but we failed.
-But why the consul's daughter?
-Detective Inspector Lee helped me raid...
...every known asset
of Juntao's operation.
We confiscated millions
in weapons and cash...
...and a collection of Chinese art
that was unsurpassed in the world.
Then Juntao disappeared. No witnesses.
Do you really think he'll kill the girl?
My advice to you is...
...pay the money.
[CHATTERlNG]
Consul, l'm going upstairs
to make the drop.
Now, l want you to remain calm
as if nothing's wrong...
...and don't leave Whitney's
side for a moment.
I understand.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I'm am Consul Han.
On behalf of the People's Republic
of China, thank you for coming.
I am pleased to present 5000 years
of Chinese history and heritage...
...a collection which, until recently,
was thought to be lost forever.
Man, this is some nice shit.
That Buddha'd go good in my bathroom.
Hey. This is the history of my country.
Priceless pieces of Chinese culture.
If anything gets damaged....
Ain't nothing gonna happen
to none of this stuff.
And now we can pass them on
to our children.
Pardon me.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
I seen that guy
at that Chinese restaurant.
Consul Han has been fighting flu
for the past few days...
...so perhaps l should finish
what he started.
The first thing we gotta do
is clear out this riffraff.
If anybody stay behind, they got something
to lose. Wait here. l'll be right back.
GRlFFIN: --peaceful future between
our two countries.
The more we see the differences
and similarit--
CARTER:
Hey!
-Ladies and gentlemen!
-Damn it.
CARTER: l'm Detective Carter from L.A.P.D.
-Russ, we got Carter down here.
-What the hell's going on?
-We just received a threat on the building.
We ask that you exit the building...
...as soon as possible,
and please do not panic.
Didn't you hear what l said? Get your shit
and go! Get the hell out! There's a bomb!
I don't believe this.
Have the agents hold their positions.
WHlTNEY:
Everybody take care, hold your positions.
HAN: What is going on?
-Get out the building!
Lady, put the glass down
and get out of here.
Woman, the exit over there.
You gonna get your head blowed off!
Come on, come on, come on!
Titty, titty, titty.
Get them titties out of here.
Will somebody grab Carter?
Juntao. Juntao.
Juntao!
Consul Han, six blocks of C-4
are wired to your daughter in a car outside.
Before the changeover,
most of this exhibition...
...was in the hands
of a single private collector.
Me.
I worked most of my life
to acquire and catalog...
...these priceless pieces
that you see before you.
And then, in one fell swoop...
...it was taken away from me.
But tonight, I shall be paid in full.
Don't move.
She dies if l press this button.
Just be patient.
My transportation will be here shortly.
Stay calm.
Hey, I was just gonna tell you
you was in a red zone.
There's cops all over this place--
[LAUGHlNG]
You didn't know I could do that.
Put your hands up!
I ain't gonna kill you this time.
I'm just gonna kick your ass!
[GRUNTlNG]
You tell your friends about me.
Hey, how you doing?
We've been looking for you.
I'm Carter from the L.A.P.D.
Everything is okay now, okay?
I'll take you to your daddy, all right?
-First thing I'll do is take this vest off.
-No, don't touch it!
-l think it'd be safer if we take it off.
-No. I heard them say it will explode.
I think it'd be safer
if we leave it on, okay?
Don't-- Don't move.
Where are you?
[MAN SPEAKlNG IN CHlNESE
OVER RADIO]
-Don't move!
-Hold your positions, goddamn it!
Do not draw your weapons.
GRlFFIN:
Ladies and gentlemen...
...l think we'll call that an evening.
Thank you and good night.
[TlRES SCREECHING]
[RAPlD GUNFIRE]
CARTER:
Juntao!
I got something for you!
Got something you want.
I got your bomb right here.
-Soo Yung.
-Papa!
-No!
SOO YUNG: Papa!
CARTER:
Wanna blow something up? Huh?
Come on.
Push the button. Come on.
Push the button.
-What are you doing?
-l'm just playing. Play along.
Come on, push the button.
Yeah, come on, push the button.
CARTER: Blow everybody up.
-Yeah, blow everybody up!
-Push the goddamn button!
You heard what she said.
Come on! You got everybody excited
about something being blowed up...
...and look at your little punk British ass.
Come on! Push the button!
Deal with it, please.
Where you going?
Cover the consul!
-No. No.
-lt's okay. She's a professional.
You must take the vest off.
Yes, just give me a second.
Just give me a second.
There's a trigger on this vest.
It'll blow if l take it off.
[GUNSHOTS]
-Haven't you done this before?
-lt's a little different in the practice room.
Everybody take cover. Whitney!
We need more men down here.
Say again. Dan, do you read--?
Need some help down here, damn it!
JOHNSON:
Roses are red...
...violets are blue.
Sugar is sweet...
...and so are you.
The remote can still set it off.
Get rid of it.
-She okay?
-Yes.
I know that ain't the bomb!
Get that bomb away from me!
Take the bomb outside!
Take the bomb outside.
-Juntao.
-Yeah, take it over to Juntao. Go to Juntao.
-You go that way, l go that way.
-All right.
[GUNSHOTS]
Don't shoot!
[GRUNTlNG]
[RAPlD GUNFIRE]
Shit!
[GUNSHOTS]
Where are you going?
-Meet me on the roof.
MAN: Roger.
Juntao!
[GROANING]
CARTER:
Don't move, man.
Yeah, l been looking for your
sweet-and-sour chicken ass.
Your boys ain't here now.
Where they at? You all alone.
-l kill him.
-Go ahead.
-Yeah?
-l don't even like him. Go.
Put your gun down.
Fight like a man.
-What you say?
-Fight like a man.
Fight like a man?
All right, l'm gonna kick your ass.
Then l'm gonna take your ass to jail.
All right.
Come on, put the gun down.
Same time.
Wipe yourself off, man. You're dead.
[GUN CLlCKlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
[SCREAMS]
Thank you, God.
[LEE GRUNTS]
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
[SCREAMS]
Whoo. You know he dead.
Carter!
Help! Do something!
Hey, be cool, man!
Hang on!
I can't hold on anymore!
Hang on for about an hour.
I'm gonna go get the ambulance.
-What are you doing?
-Hang on, man. l'll be right back.
-Carter!
-l was just playing.
Do something!
I can't hold on anymore!
[BOTH YELL]
[SCREAMlNG]
Oh, shit!
[LEE GROANlNG]
Thank you! Thank you!
-What the hell you doing?
-l was just being polite.
Well, next time, be polite to my nuts.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Shit!
MAN:
Excuse me.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I owe you everything.
Only your friendship.
SOO YUNG: Papa.
-Soo Yung. Oh.
-Look who's here.
LEE: Unh.
What took you so long?
LEE:
I think this belongs to you.
[SPEAKS IN CHlNESE]
I think you should come with me.
Get on the plane when you get off work.
You fly for free.
-Hey, Carter.
-l'm just trying to expand my horizons.
-Travel a little bit. See the world.
-Carter.
I'm through with y'all, man.
I'm gonna go on vacation.
Now, hold on there.
We were just coming by...
...to tell you what a great job
you did yesterday.
And when you come back, there's gonna be
an FBl badge waiting for you.
-You serious?
WHlTNEY: Oh, yeah.
-Come on, man, don't be playing.
-No.
I don't know what to say.
It's like a dream come true.
I got an idea, though. l got an idea.
Why don't y'all take that badge...
...and shove it up your ass?
All up in your ass. I'm L.A.P.D.
Bitch.
First class. I like this. This is tight.
Can l take your jacket, sir?
My jacket? No, no.
You can take this bag, though.
How you doing? What's up?
What's up, man?
-You ready to go?
-Yep.
May I offer you some peanuts?
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
You never told me you spoke Chinese.
I never told you l didn't.
You assumed l didn't.
This is cool, man. Han's letting me
go to Hong Kong with you.
-l ain't been on no vacation in five years.
-We can hang in my crib.
I will show you my hood.
You can show me a couple Chinese girls.
I want a massage.
I'm gonna get buck wild.
No police work for two weeks?
How long this flight?
-Fifteen hours.
-Fifteen hours?
What are we gonna do for 1 5 hours?
[SINGlNG]
Huh, war
-Oh, hell, no! Stewardess!
-Huh, what is good for?
-Stewardess, get me another seat!
-Absolutely nothing
Listen to me, y'all!
CARTER:
Stewardess!
MAN:
Action.
It broke.
[PEOPLE LAUGHlNG]
Don't move! Don't smile!
[IMITATING GUNSHOTS]
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
[LAUGHS]
[PEOPLE LAUGHlNG]
What is this shit about your daughter?
Fifty million dollars?
Who you think you got, Kelsey Clinton?
Fifty million dollars? Who you think
you got, Kelsey-- What's the line?
Fifty million dollars?
You think you got-- ls it Chelsea or Kelsey?
Fifty million dollars? Who you think you got,
Chelsea Carter? Fifty million dollars?
Who you think you got,
Chelsea Grammer--? Chelsea--
Think you got Chelsea Clinton?
50 million? Who do you think you got,
Chelsea Clinton?
Keep him talking--
[LAUGHlNG]
MAN: Cut. Go back to the beginning.
-Was that it? Chelsea-- Did I get it?
[YELLS]
MAN:
Action.
[GLASS BREAKS]
[PEOPLE LAUGHlNG]
[GRUNTlNG]
[MOANlNG]
Yeah, right,
let me see your badge, buddy!
-This is a fucking joke.
-Show me your ass!
CARTER:
Show your ass? Y'all's the gayest--
MAN:
Cut.
[LAUGHlNG]
You know that other stuff,
but you don't know his name?
LUKE:
Man...
...people tell me shit.
[SNEEZES]
-What's wrong with you?
-Heh, heh. Man.
My daddy once caught-- Catch a bullet--
-Caught a bullet-- Catch a bullet--
MAN: Caught a bullet.
My daddy one caught a bullet
by his bare hand.
No bullshit.
[LAUGHlNG]
What's the honor in that?
You believe your father
wasting his life....
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[LAUGHlNG]
They must not-- Coo-- Bleh--
You're right, man. Let's go tell them.
Anything goes wrong, you bust in there,
act like you're L.A.P.-- Blah, blah.
[LAUGHlNG]
He cannot speak English.
Man, this is cool,
the hung sending us to Hong Kong.
What's that line?
[LAUGHlNG]
May I offer you some peanuts?
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
[LAUGHlNG]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY AND LAUGHlNG]
[SPEAKING IN CHlNESE]
[LAUGHlNG]
See, how difficult is that? My English?
-He even cannot say three words, Chinese.
-Offer me some lunch.
-You need some lunch?
-l got it before, Jackie.
See? Now you know how difficult l am.
Ha, ha, ha.
-Look at Jackie.
-Ha, ha, ha.