minions
Minions
Minions have been on this planet
far longer than we have.
They go by many names.
Dave, Carl, Paul, Mike.
Oh, that one is Norbert.
He's an idiot.
They're all different.
But they all share the same goal.
To serve the most despicable
master they could find.
BOSS!
- Boss.
Making their master happy was
the tribe's very reason for existence.
But that's not to say that
they didn’t have other passions.
- Hey, look. It's a banana.
- Move over.
Hey, I know. It's a banana.
Ha-hah-ha.
Yum yum.
Huh?
Finding a Boss was easy.
But keeping a Boss...
therein lies the rub.
Ow.
Owww.
Whoa!
Oh.
- Oop.
- Aw.
- Oh.
I am... oaf.
Aw.
Nope,
it wasn't easy for these guys.
But they never gave up.
With the emergence of the stone age
came the rise of a new species.
Man was very different
from the dinosaur.
He was shorter, hairier
and way, way smarter.
The minions took an instant liking to Man
and helped him as best they could.
Oh, no no...
Here. A present.
- This?
- Yes yes yes.
For hitting.
Ut-ut.
Aw!
Poor man.
So trusting, so fragile, so-so delicious.
Their quest for a boss put
the minions front and center
for some of the civilization
most historic moments.
Ancient Egypt held great promise.
Okay!
But it didn't last long.
Hmm.
Oh.
Here.
Yup.
Ow!
The dark ages
were actually fun times.
Their new master had a tendency
to party all night and sleep all day.
Ahem.
Yoo-hoo.
[Happy Birthday]
Oh.
But eventually
the party was over.
Achoo.
They bounced from
one evil master to another.
But they never seemed
to find their perfect fit.
One particular employer took
their failure very very badly.
Huh?
The Minions had no other
choice but to keep moving.
Oh.
Look.
And then,
when all hopes seem lost.
They found sanctuary.
The Minions were safe.
Years passed as the Minions
forged their own civilization.
They truly made a life
for themselves.
But something just wasn't right.
They felt empty inside.
Without a master, they had no purpose.
They became aimless
and depressed.
If this continue any longer,
the Minions would perish.
But all was not lost,
for one Minion had a plan.
His name was Kevin.
He was excited to share
his idea with the tribe.
He'd been preparing for
days, weeks, months.
But now he was ready.
Buddies.
Kevin would leave the cave,
go back to the outside world
and he would not return
until he had found his tribe
the biggest baddest villain deserved.
But he needed help.
Me! Me!
I will come.
Bob was eager to go.
- Kevin?
But Kevin felt he was just not strong enough
for the dangerous journey ahead.
Uh no.
One other Minion?
Me.
Choose me.
Me! Choose me!
Aw.
Me!
I will come.
Luckily someone stepped up.
- Huh?
- Stuart! Come here.
Huh. Me? Me?
Oh, thank you.
Truth be told. Stuart had no idea
what he was chose for.
Huh!
Wh-Why?
But was thrilled that made
people cheered for him.
Uh.
Stuart, Stuart.
One more?
ME!
I am strong.
See here.
See!
- Oh.
Uh... okay.
One more.
Kevin.
Choose me.
Please.
Choose me, Kevin.
Come here.
Huh.
Yeah! Ha ha.
Eventually, Bob's energy and enthusiasm
but mostly lack of other volunteers
changed Kevin's mind.
- Kumbaya!
Kumbaya.
Big boss!
The tribe said their farewells.
Kevin had given them something
they haven't had  in a long time.
- Hope.
- Kevin!
- Bob!
- (Big boss! Big boss!)
Hey,Tony.
Good luck to you.
Tom.
Take care.
And Chris.
See you later.
- Hey Bob, you coming?
- Yes, yes.
Big boss!
Bye bye.
Kevin felt pride.
He was going to be the
one to save his tribe.
Stuart felt,
hungry mostly.
He was going to be the one
to eat this banana.
- And Bob
- Oh.
Bob was frightened
of the journey ahead.
Okay. Okay.
Look for the big boss.
Ah. There you go, Bob.
Come on.
And they were off.
Off,
to find their new boss.
Come on, Bob.
Huh?
Kevin?
Oh.
- Hungry?
- Food?
There is no food.
Huh.
Banana.
Uh.
Stuart, What it it?
Banana.
- Banana!
- Aww.
- Stuart.
- Food.
Stop!
Bob!
Huh.
Oh. Land!
Bob.
New York 1968
- Oh, look at that one.
- Whoa!
Whoa.
Look at that one.
- Peace!
- Make love, not war!
Peace to the world.
Boo ya.
Boo Ya!
Boo ya, boo ya.
[Music Pad]
Banana.
- Hey! Hey, taxi!
- Hey! Hey!
Whoa.
OUT NOW
Songs of Aloha
Biggest Hit
of
Hey. Ba-Banana.
Hey. Hey.
Stuart. Hey, oh.
Bee-do.
Where is Bob?
- Kevin...
- Huh. Bob!
Oh.
Banana.
Bob!
( fancy's )
Huh.
Ah, Bob.
Whoa.
Women's bell bottoms
and tie-dye shirts marked down.
- Check out our wide selection
of go-go boots and miniskirts.
- Whoa.
Huh, Bob.
There's Bob. Come on.
Excuse me.
Coming through.
Ah... Okay.
You go right.
- And I go this way.
- Huh?
Bob!
The store is now closing.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Bob, where you?
- Give me that.
Oh, Kevin.
I am over here, Ke...
Oh.
Huh.
Hey, ha ha.
My buddies?
You are here.
You are here, my buddies.
Hey.
It's me, Bob.
My buddies.
Huh?
Oh.
Bob!
There you are.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
Oh.
There, here's Tim.
Oh, ha ha.
Me Tim. Thank you.
Hm?
Oh no.
They are closed.
Hey. Look at this.
Boing, boing,
Come on in.
- Let's have it, Stuart.
- Yes, yes. Just a second.
Ah.
How's this shows?
- Uh, nah. Try another channel.
- Okay, okay, changing.
Oh,
THE DATING GAME.
Okay,
Let's watch this.
And welcome back to
the Dating Game.
Well Jennifer.
Have you decided
which of these 3 gentlemen,
you'll go on a date with?
- Is it Bob?
- Yeah! Go Bob.
- Kevin.
- It's me, Kevin.
- Or will it be Stuart?
- Oh. Yo, Stuart.
Gosh. This is so hard.
They all sounded so cute.
I think I'm going
to go with...
Nobody panic, alright.
Now, now.
Calm down, Stuart.
VNC...
You're watching the top secret
Villain Network Channel.
If you tell anyone,
we'll find you.
Huh.
Don't move.
Sponsored by Villain-Con.
For 89 years straight. The biggest
gathering of criminals anywhere.
That-That's where we
would find the big boss.
Attend guest lectures
from esteem villains.
Make contacts in the
underworld community.
And, for the first time anywhere,
Scarlet Overkill !
Evil.
So evil.
- Criminal genius!
- Hey, a girl's got to make a living.
- Move aside, men.
- Make way.
- There's a new bad man in town.
- Excuse me.
And that man is a woman.
- Crime isn't pretty.
- It's red hot.
Get to Villain-Con this weekend.
Only at 545 Orange Grove Avenue,
in Orlando, Florida.
So much fun, it's a crime.
Heh-heh-heh.
Oh.
Villain-Con, Orlando.
- Woo hoo.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Hello.
Orlando?
Ah, buttocks.
Hey, greetings.
Orlando?
Ooh. Hello, Papagena.
You beautiful papaya.
- Do you know, Orlando?
- Oh. I think.
- That way.
- Uh huh.
- Ah, okay. Thank you, baby.
- Bye bye.
- That way.
- Ah.
To Orlando!
Ah!
Papagena!
[NEW YORK]
Hey, Stuart.
Do you best.
Oh yeah, far out.
Love is the way, brother.
No. No no no.
Kevin.
I'll do it. I'll do it.
You watch.
Ha-ha-ha...
"No no, no no.
I'll do it. I'll do it. You watch."
Yah, right.
Just you wait.
I'll show you.
Hey.
Stop! Stop!
Stop...!
Over here.
Stop! Stop!
Stop.
Ugh!
There.
You do it.
Stuart, that's him.
0RLANDO
Oh, Walter look. These adorable little
freaks are heading to Orlando too.
Yeah, I see that.
Hey, Walter Junior.
- What's happening?
- Tina.
- Hi.
Binky. What do you say
we give these fellows a ride?
- Yeah! New friends.
All aboard the Nelson Express.
You, one eye,
You're sitting next to me.
Okay.
I'm going.
Stuart.
Just get on.
Glad we came along before
some weirdos picked you up.
Who wants apple slices?
Ahh.
Apple.
Oh, you too.
Growing of a... boy like...
creatures need their strength.
Okay.
You want it?
Heck, yeah!
Thanks, man.
Alrighty.
Who needs to stretch their legs?
- Yeah!
- Yes. Me me me!
You guys wait right here.
We'll be right back.
Okay, Nelsons.
Let's do this.
Uh.
Protection?
Go go go!
Okey dokey,
on the road again.
Dad, we got company.
It's because I tripped the alarm.
- I stink.
- Hey.
We all make mistakes, sugar plum.
You're still learning.
Huh!
What!
- Your father's right, Tina.
-  Reload.
- He wasn’t this good at being evil overnight.
- Reload.
Your time is coming.
Ah!
It's jammed.
Huh?
- Give me.
- No.
- Give me. Give me!
- No no. No.
- Okay, who did that?
- It's Stuart.
- Huh? Me... me...
- That was great.
Ha ha ha.
Thank you.
Give me.
Give me. Give me.
Say, fellows. Can we get
personal for just a second?
Why are you
going to Orlando?
Come on, you can tell us,
You're going to Villain-Con, aren't you?
Yes, Villain-Con.
Villain-Con.
Wow, so many
bad guys in the car.
- What fun.
- I knew it.
I knew you were villains.
Didn't I, honey?
What a small world.
Hope we're not in rival gangs.
Heh heh heh.
Binky, joke.
Babies, huh?
Hey, everybody.
The boss.
It's big boss.
Let's go welcome him.
- Yah.
- Hoo hoo.
- Boss.
Boss.
The boss.
Sheesh. sheesh.
Sheesh, sheesh...
The boss will speak.
When we get to Orlando,
I'm going to get all my favorite
villains to sign my magazine.
Dumo, the Sumo.
Oh oh.
He's a boss.
Oh, Kevin! You don't
want to work for him.
He ate his last henchmen.
Frankie Fishlips.
He lives in the ocean.
- Ah. And he's the boss?
- Uh.
- Can you breathe under water?
- Bah... So so.
Oh oh oh.
Look at her, Scarlet Overkill!
The coolest supervillain,
like ever!
She started out as your average
little girl. Bracers, pig tails.
But, by the time she was 13,
She built a criminal empire.
If I was a Minion, that's who
I would want to work for.
Ah... Scarlet Overkill.
Whoa.
- Here we are, beautiful Orlando.
- Yeah, we're here!
Orlando
Coming soon!
Orlando.
[545]
[ BAIT SHOP ]
Hey gang, watch this.
Welcome to Billy Bob's Bait Shop,
how can I help you?
Yeah.
Hi.
We are here for...
"So much fun, it's a crime."
[PARKING ->]
Woo-hoo.
Yeh!
It's Villain-Con.
The Villain-Con!
LUV.2.ROB
NEW YORK
Alright, here we go.
Well, this is it.
I wanted to tell you and
I really I mean this.
I'm really appreciate what you did
back there with the cops. Really.
Dad!
It's Frankie Fishlips.
- I can smell him from here!
- Junior, get my camera.
Good luck in there, boys.
I hope you find what
you are looking for.
- Yeah, bye.
- Bye.
And here we come,
Villain-Con!
- Ha ha.
- Yeah!
- Villain-Con.
- Ya! Hoo.
[ Welcome to VILLAIN-CON ]
[FREEZE-RAY]
- Whoa.
Any evil talents?
Not bad.
What about you?
Any evil talents?
Hello. La la la.
La la la. Eh?
That's not evil,
or a talent.
Hello!
Ahaa! Ha ha.
No?
I'm sorry, but I'm not looking
for any more servants.
For I,
Professor Flux,
have invented the
world's first Time machine!
Every time I visit the future,
I bring my future
self back to help me.
Hello.
Who's that over there,
Professor Flux from 2 weeks from now?
As you can see,
I don't need any help.
Oh. Way to go, guys.
We killed the original.
- Huh!
- Aw!
Please.
Villain-Con,
I present our keynote speaker.
Scarlet Overkill.
The world's first female super-villain.
Appearing right now in Hall H.
- Bob, Stuart, buddies.
Buddies, let's go.
It's Scarlet Overkill.
- Scarlet?
- Come on. Come on.
Kevin.
Are you ready...
for
Scarlet Overkill.
Ha.
Doesn't it feel so good
to be bad?
- Scarlet-Scarlet-Scarlet...
- Yes!
- Hoo-hoo-hoo.
Ha-ha-ha...
- Whoa.
- Wow.
Scarlet!
Whoa. Ha ha.
What beauty.
Wow.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Okay.
Shh shh shh.
When I started out,
people said a woman could
never rob a bank
as well as a man. Well.
Time's changed.
I love you, Scarlet!
Look at all those faces out there,
we are all so different.
But we have
one thing in common.
We were born with flippers!
No?
Just me?
Okay.
We have big dreams, and we will
do anything to make them come true.
Have any of you ever dreamt
of working for the greatest
supervillain of all time?
Heh-heh-heh.
Well.
What if I were
to tell you,
that I am looking
for a new henchman!
Hey, big boss.
This is our chance.
- Yes.
- Ha.
I truly believe
somewhere out there
is a villain with the potential
to serve greatness.
- And it could be any of you.
- Whoa.
Although let's not kid ourselves.
Truly the only man for this job
are Kevin and his Minions.
10 times the evil in
half the package.
I'm just in awe.
Let's hear it for Kevin.
He saved his tribe!
Kevin!
- Kevin Kevin Kev...
- Hey, Kevin. Hey.
- Argh!
- Hey. Pay attention.
So.
How should we do this?
Hmm.
Oh.
You see this
tiny little trinket?
Well, just take it from my hand
and you got the job.
No big deal,
it's almost too simple.
Eh heh heh.
Oh, come on, don't be afraid.
Just take the stone and get that job.
- Come on.
- Oh, okay.
Let's go get our boss.
Come on.
- That job is mine.
- Ooh.
Now, go easy on me.
Heh-heh-heh-heh.
Aw!
Love the costume.
Ha!
So cool!
Wait
Wait.
Tim?
Tim!
Oh.
Oh no, Bob.
He's over there.
Ah.
Stop.
- Is no one good enough?
- Stop. Tim.
Bob!
Hi ya!
Tim!
There he is.
Bob!
Aw!
Didn't my speech inspired anyone
to rise up and prove
themselves worthy?
All these villains, and yet
I still have the- bear.
Stuffed bear.
Why am I holding a bear?
- Oh.
- Who has the ruby?
Wow.
Who-Who are you?
My... knights
in shiny denim.
- I'm Kevin. This is Stuart.
- Yo.
- And Bob.
- Minions!
- That was incredible.
Behold, the last creatures
you expect to win the day
have emerged victorious.
Everyone,
meet my new henchmen.
The Minions!
- Kumbaya! Ha ha!
- Kumbaya!
Kumbaya!
Hey! I know those guys.
I gave them a ride here.
Woo.
Hoo-hoo-hoo.
Buckle up, boys.
Next stop, England.
Ah.
Pick it up.
1, 2
1 2 3!
Hello.
Hey, Kevin.
Huh?
The boss, in England.
Nah. We found a boss.
Listen.
Ah. Uh...
Hello, Kevin.
Did-Did you say England?
Uh-huh.
The boss, yes.
Scarlet Overkill.
Ah.
Hello.
Hello?
Oh. He hung up.
Hello.
Wow.
Here we go.
Come here.
By the way.
I really like your bear.
- Herb, my baby.
- You know I am.
How did it go?
Were you evil?
- So evil.
- Oh!
A little bird dropped
this off today.
I Missed You!
♥ H.
It's me,
I'm the "H".
Also, there's no birds.
Also me.
Herb, seriously.
I want to dig up that
William Shakespeare,
so he can see
what true writing is.
I love it.
That works because I love you.
Well, I love you too.
Oh.
The love, oh.
Oh, boys.
Could you come here please?
Meet my husband, Herb.
Inventor, super genius, fox.
Herb, these are the new recruits.
Kevin, Stuart and
that cute little one is Bob.
Right on. You guys
are crazy little and
way yellow,
and I digged that.
Sweet, man.
- Wow.
- Cool house.
I know, right?
Just a few thing I stole
to help fill the void.
Whoa.
A mega ukulele.
Checking out my can?
We stole that because finally
someone expressed my love
of soup in painting form.
- Wow.
- Woo.
Okay, listen up.
It is time to get down to business.
Do you know who this is?
Uh.
The cockroach?
This is Queen Elizabeth,
ruler of England.
Oh. I love England.
The music, the fashion.
I'm seriously thinking about
overthrowing it someday.
- I'm so excited.
- Yes.
Anyway. This pale drink of water
oversees it all.
I'm her biggest fan,
love her work.
And I really really really
want her crown.
Steal me the crown and
all your dreams come true.
Respect!
Power!
Banana!
- Yeah!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Huh!
Henry!
The way to England,
is... is...
Ah!
Give me.
Uh. England is...
this way.
March on!
Eh!
Wait for me!
Wait for me! Ah!
Go back!
- Hm. What is this place?
- Hey. Over there.
- Whoa.
- Wow.
Whoa oh.
Uu la la.
No.
Oh, no.
Don't get too close, boys.
When it's completed, it will
be my ultimate weapon. But.
Right now, it's leaking radiation.
Like you would not believe.
So you're here
for gear.
Whoa.
- Bob, Robert, Bobby my boy.
- Yes?
You get my far-out
stretch suit.
Wow.
Kevin, Kevo, Seventh Kevin.
You are the proud owner
of my Lava Lamp gun.
This baby shoots actual lava!
- Woo, for me?
- Pretty cool, right?
And finally, Stu, Stu-art,
Stu-perman, Beef Stu.
I got you the coolest invention,
probably ever.
- Hypno hat!
- Uh, oh.
You can use it
to hypnotize anyone.
Anyone!
Oh, you look so great.
I feel like a proud mama
with 3 dashing evil sons.
Uh.
Scarlet. Scarlet.
There is something
wrong with this.
No, no, don't say anything,
I won't understand.
It's getting late, you had a big day.
You must be exhausted.
Boing. Boing.
Wow, these cats are pumped!
Well, maybe I'll settle them down
with a bedtime story.
How does that sound, Bob?
Bob? Bob?
Bob!
Oh.
Bedtime story?
That is a groovy idea,
I'll go get some
cookies and warm milk.
This is going to be so fun!
And the bedtime porry.
Oh, yes, I've got a really really
good bedtime porry.
Once upon a time,
there were 3 little pigs.
One fateful day, the pigs
encountered a big bad wolf,
who had a wonderful
surprise for them,
The wolf offered the 3 piggies and
all their friends a job working for her.
Everyone would be so happy!
All the 3 little piggies had to do
was just steal one little crown.
That the beautiful wolf
had wanted ever since
she was a penniless
little street cub.
Unloved and abandoned.
But that crown would mean
she was a princess.
And everybody loves the princess.
So, the wolf sent the
piggies to get that crown.
But the little piggies weren't
up to the challenge.
They failed their mission.
So the wolf huffed and puffed
and she blew them off
the face of the earth!
Yo, po, po!
The end.
Good luck getting the crown
tomorrow, little piggies.
I know you won't disappoint me.
Tower of London
Tower of London - LONDON
Okay.
[HOME OF THE QUEEN'S CROWN]
- Let's go get the crown, for Scarlet.
- Which way is the loo, please?
Ah, thank you.
Hello.
3 please.
You are not allowed
to enter without an adult.
Scram, hooligans.
Woo, a lad.
- What lad?
- Holah!
Pooff.
Stuart, that way.
How many tickets, please?
3, please.
One, please.
One.
- Enjoy yourself, love.
- Thank you.
It was nowhere near Hyde Park!
- That way.
- Okay.
[KEEP OUT]
Go!
Okay, we're in.
Okay, come on.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
Eating?
This is a restricted area!
- Hands in the air!
- No...
Let me do it.
Stop that!
Get back!
Hey-hey-hey...
Bob, Stuart, come on.
Stay back.
Leave this to me.
There it is, the crown.
Come on.
So.
You came for the
Queen's crown, did you?
Well, you're going to
have to get through me!
The Keeper
of the Crown.
You think it's funny to
mock the elderly, do you?
Uh.
Yes.
I've been up here
for decades.
Just waiting for someone to try
and steal the queen's treasure.
Okay.
Me will do it.
What are you saying?
Never mind, don't care!
Hee hee.
Ha ha ha.
Oh no, you don't.
Oh, flippin' heck!
Ow! Oof!
Ow!
For... god sake.
Quick, the crown.
After it.
Bob.
Open it.
Alright.
The crown.
Quick.
Hello.
Hey, look at me!
- Stone the crows!
- Stop him, lads!
- Go for the legs.
- Freeze.
Gordon Bennett!
Kevin!
The Queen's been kidnapped, Sarge!
Blimey!
Hyah!
Ha!
Boo-ya!
Hyah!
- What's going on?
- Hello.
- Oh, my goodness!
- Oh, the crown.
- Give me the crown. Now!
- No!
Ha-ha!
Beat that!
Gentlemen do not steal
ladies' crowns!
The coach.
Waa...
Oh, no no no...
Oh-Oh dear!
- Ahhh!
Yeah.
Ha ha ha.
You scoundrel.
After them!
Stop the blighter!
- Stop the blighter!
[SWORD IN THE STONE]
You're surrounded.
Huh?
Oh.
Oh, blimey!
One of England's most famous
myths has become a reality.
As a new king
has been crowned.
Bob, who appears to be
a bald, jaundice child,
has pulled the famed sword
right from it's stone
which, legend dictates,
makes him the new king.
Tiny yellow traitor!
Ah-ha-ha.
England!
England.
Eng... land.
- England.
[AUSTRALIA] ---  /INDIA\
Hey!
Help!
A studio.
Hello! Hello!
CUT !
AIR BRITANNIA
Hey, Bob.
Well done.
Hello, King Bob.
Welcome to Buckingham Palace.
Uh.
No.
Oh. What's the matter,
Your Majesty?
Whatever is bothering you,
we can make it right.
- Just name it.
- Oh.
Ha ha ha.
Buddies.
Ha, buddies.
Ha, buddy.
Ah-ha-ha...
King Bob!
- Yeh!
- Hurray!
- Long live the king!
- King Bob!
King Bob!
- Yeah.
Whoa, wait.
- Yee-ha!
- King Bob.
Grill chicken!
Yes, King Bob?
King Bob?
Ah, Claire.
Hm, Tiffany.
My beauties.
Ball!
Yah!
How dare you?
AW!
Scarlet.
Don't you "Scarlet" me.
You backstabbing little traitors!
Using Herb's inventions
to steal my crown!
I feel used,
not going to lie.
You stole my dream.
I was going to conquer
England some day.
There was going
to be a coronation.
And I was going
to be made queen.
Every moment was planned.
I would wear a dress
so sparkly, it glowed.
And everyone whoever doubted me
would be watching,
and they would be crying.
I was going to be the picture
of elegance and class!
And you pinheads
screwed it up!
No no no.
The crown, for you.
No, no no.
King Bob.
You cannot just
abdicate the throne.
Who invited the square?
And you definitely cannot just
give the job to this woman.
There are laws.
Laws?
What laws?
I give my place to
Scarlet Overkill.
King Bob has official
changed the law.
Clearing the way for Scarlet Overkill
to be crowned Queen of England.
She will be coronated at London's
historic Westminster Abbey.
If I'm wasn't so polite,
I'd say this spells certain
doom for the country,
if not, the world.
But, I'm so very polite,
that I shall keep my mouth shut.
But, seriously,
we are all in big trouble.
- Scarlet
- Ms. Overkill.
I don't have time
to answer any questions.
I'm just want to thank
the minions for
going above and beyond
the call of duty.
You are 3 tiny golden
pill shaped miracle workers.
And you have stolen not just England,
but my heart.
- Scarlet, over here.
- Over here.
Show her,
the buddies.
Pardon Me?
Wow, so many.
[ERiC], [NORBERT]
Good for you,
Well.
You'll all get what you deserved.
Serve.
We get to serve.
Woo hoo!
Oh.
Go ahead.
Buttocks.
I don't want you to
take this the wrong way.
But I hate you.
I thought I could
get over what you did.
But I feel so betrayed.
I think, yes, I think
we're gonna have to break up.
And it's not you.
Oh wait, hold on.
It is you.
It's a 100% you.
Huh.
No no.
So get comfortable, Minions.
Get real real comfortable.
Because this is where
you're going to spend
the rest of your
worthless little lives.
Alright, let's do this.
Look.
Look, it's Herb.
Who's this handsome "Herb" fellow?
No, My name is Blerb.
I'm a-a dungeon master.
Prepared for torture
which I do.
Alright, are we comfy?
Doesn't matter.
This is TORTURE!
- Oh.
- Uh, anything?
No no.
My sunshine.
Wow, harder than I thought.
Next machine.
Oh, welcome to hang town.
Population: You.
Cut it out.
This is really unprofessional.
No laughing in the dungeon.
I want to see tears and
I want to hear screams.
Or I'm going to get...
- Wait.
- Hey.
Oh, I've got a groovy idea.
Look at this.
Ah-ha-ha.
Hello, will the future King,
Herb Overkill,
please come upstairs to
prepare for the coronation.
Well, I hope you learn
your lesson for today.
And by the way, it was me,
Herb, the whole time.
I don't even know
anyone named Blerb.
I am hours away from becoming
the Queen of England.
I know,
it's a gas.
- I will finally get my crown.
- Yeah.
It's all I ever wanted.
I'm going to be so happy.
But, let me ask you
something, Fabrice.
Does that, look like
this to you?
Mrs. Overkill.
The hair in that picture,
it's just 2 wavy lines.
Oh. So what now,
you're an art critic?
I drew that when
I was 5 years old.
Get out of my sight.
Bye, Fabrice!
I liked him,
he was fun.
So, what do you think
of the dress?
Oh, it's so beautiful,
so fashion forward,
so Valentino.
Gave it a sweetheart neckline
because you're my sweetheart.
The high collar and cinched waist
reflect a simpler more violent time.
The material is a blend of taffeta
and high density body armor.
Fully armed and loaded.
And they glow.
That's nuclear.
Nice.
Just one more thing to do.
Got to look good
for the public.
- Do you mind?
- My pleasure.
A little tighter, sweetie.
Come on, I can take it.
A little tighter.
Tighter.
Must have tiny waist.
Seeing stars.
Losing feeling in my legs.
Perfect.
Tie it, tie it, tie it, tie it.
Huh?
Ah.
Bob, Stuart.
- Huh?
- Help me.
Lift up.
Help me.
Help me!
[CARNABY STREET]
Oh, hello.
Yoo-hoo.
[GOD SAVE THE QUEEN]
- Puchi, Puchi. Ku.
- Puchi. Ah.
Ah.
This way, let's go.
(SORRY)
(FOR YOUR LOSS)
This way, one more.
- Move. Move.
- Can we just go back.
Hey, Kevin.
Look. For Scarlet.
What do you think?
Ah.
That's it.
SORRY
FOR YOUR LOSS
SORRY SCARLET
Heh hey. Perfect for the boss.
Come on.
Oh.
Puchi, come.
Ah, okay.
This way out.
Ha ha.
Let's find Scarlet.
I love you, Scarlet!
Queen wave. Queen wave.
Queen waving.
I'm so-so excited.
This is perfect.
Everyone looks so nice.
Oh, you're just adorable.
Oh.
Yes!
And that music.
Eh.
Who is that organist?
She's good.
Right?
She looks like an Edna.
- Edna!
- Who's that?
- You're very good.
- Whoa!
Thanks for doing this, Padre.
Big fan.
Come here, let me squeeze you.
Woo.
You're so squishy.
There, Scarlet.
Go go go.
Whoa.
Arh!
Heh heh.
Move aside.
Oh.
Ouch.
Ouch...
Up there.
Up-Up there?
My Puchi?
Your Puchi, bye bye.
Come on!
Oh.
Bye, Puchi.
- Oh, Bob. Come on!
- Aww.
- Stuart!
- Yes-yes-yes...
Hello.
Yoo hoo.
Oh.
Bee.
Will you to your power cause
Law and Justice,
Come on.
It's Overkill.
Sorry.
Stop!
I am not a stupid.
in Mercy,
Oh.
No no.
Do you Scarlet Overkill
That's it!
Yeah!
No!
No. No.
Come on. Come on.
Grab my hand.
I'm stuck.
I proclaim thee, Scarlet Overkill,
the Queen of England.
Kevin!
Scarlet! Scarlet.
My queen.
Somebody help me!
Come on, come on.
Lift on 2.
1, 2!
Scarlet, you're okay.
He tried to kill me!
No.
I wasn't...
Villains. This is no
longer a coronation.
It is an execution!
Get them!
Whoa Nelly!
Run fellows, run!
Come back here, you!
In there.
- Guys.
- Kevin.
You are mine!
Stuart. Bob.
Huh?
Grill chicken!
Come on, Bob.
Come on.
Ha-ha-ha...
Oops.
- Oh.
- Rats.
Hey.
I've got one!
Look there.
Ha ha ha.
Tim.
Oh?
Aww! Oh!
Tim!
Stuart.
Bob.
Hope they are alright.
Hoy, buddies.
Mind the gap.
- England.
Mind the gap!
He won't get away!
He won't escape us!
Now, what about this one.
Why did the Queen
go to the dentist?
To get her teeth crowned.
Ha-ha-ha.
Ha.
The queen.
Tell us another one, Lizzy!
Uh.
Hello.
Oh, it's you.
Everyone, this is one
of the little fellows
who stole the monarchy from me.
And hows that
working out for you?
Oh, yes yes.
I saw what was going
on, on the telly.
Uh.
Telly?
What was meant to be the
coronation of Scarlet Overkill
has gone terribly wrong as...
Move!
Kevin. Kevin.
I know you're out there.
You think you've gotten away?
Well, what do we have here?
Hello.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Bob? Stuart?
Which one shall I kill first?
Little Bob.
Stuart?
Bob.
Stuart. Hmm.
I will do it, Kevin,
if you're not back here by dawn.
Oh my.
Huh, no!
I got to... my buddies.
Must find Scarlet.
Eh-ha-ha...
There he is.
Follow me!
Harder.
It's just my head.
- This way. Go get him!
- Go-go-go...!
DO NOT PUSH
THiS BUTTON ->
[DO NOT FLIP THIS SWITCH]
[DO NOT PULL THIS LEVER!]
[DO NOT BLOW IN THiS HOLE ->]
- Ultimate weapon initiated.
Activation in
1.
Hello.
Huh.
My buddies.
This is it, boys.
Things do not
look good for you.
Oh.
And I'm keeping the bear.
Huh.
Tim!
You're not going to need him
where you're going.
Heaven.
Huh?
Uh... Aah!
Shoosh, shoosh,
shoosh, shoosh! Oh!
Bye bye. Say bye bye, Bob.
Bye bye.
Ha-ha-ha...
Ha ha ha.
Come on, no worries.
Oh, whoa!
Wait, what?
How did he?
Hold my bear.
Ha ha ha.
Safe.
- Ha ha.
- Yippee.
- Kevin.
- Woo-hoo-hoo.
- Be careful! Be careful!
- Be careful.
So, that's your plan?
Make yourself a bigger target?
Ha-ha-ha.
- One more scone.
- Yes yes.
Huh?
Kevin?
Hey. It's Kevin.
Come on.
YAH!
Ha ha ha ha.
And so help me.
I never want to see
another one of your
goofy, bug-eyed
faces ever again!
Scarlet!
What?
Oh, you got to be kidding me!
Oh no, you don't.
Yah!
Whoa!
Wah!
And just for the record,
my little deviled eggs.
You can thank Kevin for
what I'm about to do to you!
Aww!
Ow!
Oww!
- Yeh!
- Buddies!
Bob!
Stuart!
Tony!
Hey hey.
Tom!
And Chris!
- Bodyguard!
- You're the man!
Ha ha ha.
Buddies!
- Hey, Kevin!
- Good to see you.
Yeah!
Ugh!
Eww!
Huh? Ah.
Kevin! Kevin!
Enough!
This... ends... now...!
KEVIN !!!
Ha-ha-ha, you imbecile.
Have fun exploding.
Baby.
- What's the rush?
- Got to get out of here!
Let... us... go!
Whoaaa!
No, no no no...
Ke-Ke-Ke
KEVIN!
Here.
Your Puchi.
Huh. Puchi!
You're alright.
Look!
- Kevin!
Ha-ha!
Whoo-hoo! Ah! Ah!
- Oh.
- Ooh.
- Woo hoo hoo!
- Yeah!
Yoo hoo hoo.
Ouch.
- Stuart.
- Hm.
- Bob.
- Yes?
Okay.
Ladies and gentlemen.
We are here today
to celebrate the Minions.
The country owes you a
great debt of gratitude.
Bob, you were a wise and
noble king for all of 8 hours.
So for you,
I offer this tiny crown
for your Teddy Bear, Tim.
Oh. Thank you.
Thank you.
Oh.
Very good, Bob.
Oh!
Oh, spectacular!
I'm so proud of you boys.
- Oh, Stuart.
- Ah. What's up.
For you, I have this beautiful,
super duper incredible
snow globe.
Snow globe?
And, look.
Look.
Hours of excitement.
Oh... Yippee.
Thank you.
Oh, Stuart.
We're just messing with you.
Don't be mad at me.
It was Kevin’s idea.
- Ha.
- Kevin!
We have a much
better surprise for you.
Here.
A Super Mega Ukulele.
Wo-Wow.
Cool.
Thank you.
Right.
Uh.
And finally, Kevin.
Yes, my queen.
You are a hero
of the highest order.
For your bravery and valor,
I am knighting you.
From here on out,
you are Sir Kevin.
Well done.
What a beautiful moment.
- Kumbaya!
The nation, nay, the world was
celebrating Kevin, Stuart, and Bob.
The last few thousand
years were rough,
no question, but things were
finally going their way.
Kevin had never been more proud.
But something was missing.
Ha ha, yes.
Good show Good show.
My crown is gone.
It's gone!
Blimey!
- She lost the crown.
- Oh my days.
Ha-ha-ha...
Scarlet?
Someone stop her.
Scarlet.
Hey!
They took everything from me.
My castle.
My reputation.
Things looked bleak, baby,
I'm not going to lie.
But now, at least,
I have my crown!
Child, give me that back.
No, I don't think so.
You have no idea
who you are messing with.
I'm the greatest
super-villain of all time.
Oh, were you?
Bud-Bud-Buddies.
Come here. Come here.
Lo-Lo-Look!
It's the boss.
The boss! Come on!
Get back her...Are you
really going to allow that
little penguin to make off
with my crown?
Oh, Herb.
I'm done.
Hey. Hey.
Scarlet.
Here.
For Me?
Oh.
Yes, for you.
Bye bye.
Big boss!
And that is how the Minions
found their new boss.
He was cunning.
He was evil.
He was perfect.
He was
despicable.
Subtitle by - Aorion -
- Banana.
Banana.
Hey.
Come on.
Shh.
Cheese.
- Gru. Gru. Gru.
- It's Gru.
- Gru.
Bob.
Go play outside.
Want one?
Hey!
Come back here!
Freeze ray!