I can't hold her much longer, Murphy.
Port bow is heeling.
She's taking on too much water.
What is going on back there?
Keep your pants on, Murphy.
Damn, Murphy, we blew
the starboard engine.
Port engine's running way too hot.
- Hold on.
- Shorten the tow.
Cut her loose.
Epps, get off my damn tugboat.
We don't have much time.
Move it, epps. Move it!
If she sinks, she's taking us with her.
Got a punch in the port floater.
I'll give it minutes before she floods.
You got less than that!
Get back here.
We're cutting her loose.
Cut her loose, Murphy.
That's it. Now, get back here.
Come on, epps! You heard the man!
Took us three months to
get her off the bottom.
I will not lose her now!
Goddamn it, epps!
You can't fix everything!
= Christ!
I'm telling you for the
last time, get back here!
She's taking on too much water!
Why do you always
have to break my balls?
I said get back here!
Do you want me to come down
there and kick your ass?
"Cause I'll do it.
Well, here's to the best damn
salvage crew in the business!
Yeah, we did it, guys!
Yeah, look at that!
All right! Nice work!
Here's to the fucking sea!
To the sea.
To a job well done.
Hi. Hi, Mr. Murphy?
I'm Jack ferriman.
I was wondering if I
could buy you a drink.
He doesn't drink.
Okay, think I talk
to you alone for a sec?
You talk to me, you talk to my crew.
That's the way it is.
Okay, I fly the arctic
weather patrol flights
out of MacKenzie bay. - Yeah?
And last month, I was out
in the middle of the strait
when I came across this.
Congratulations, you found a boat,
in the middle of the ocean, of all places.
Well, I did three flybys
and tried for radio
contact and got nothing,
so I figured she had to be adrift.
This was in the Bering strait?
Yeah.
That's 1000 miles from
the nearest shipping lanes.
Why didn't you alert the coast guard?
I did, but it's international waters,
so they noted it and that's it.
You get a name off this boat?
No, I put it out of my head
until about two days ago,
and I saw it again.
What are we talking about here?
What kind of tonnage is it?
Big, huge, could be military.
Okay, let's say that we're
a little bit interested.
What's your end?
What's in it for you?
I want 20% % finder's
fee, whatever she's worth.
Have you told anyone else about this?
Not a living soul.
Give us a minute, will you?
Okay.
So? What do you think, murph?
Who knows?
Could be full of shit.
I do know one thing.
I've seen strange things
happen in the strait.
I know something else.
If the sea gives you an
opportunity, you take it.
That's at least a week
out of our way, Murphy.
I mean, we've been out
for six months already.
I got my fiance waiting, remember?
I mean, I'm getting married in a month.
The plan was to go back to Anchorage.
Starboard diesel needs a total overhaul.
In our business, the only plan is...
There is no plan.
Listen, of you don't want
to go, that's fine with me.
Let's just tell him
we'll get somebody else.
No big deal.
No, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Let's not be hasty.
What do you think a ship
like that could be worth?
Who knows?
Millions? Thousands?
Could be worth nothing.
Depends on a lot of things.
Mainly, if we have the
right to salvage it.
That's a pretty big "if."
What's the split?
We split it even, six ways.
Even split?
Uh-huh, beats
me paying you overtime.
I'm good.
I'm in.
Greer? What do you say?
All right.
Hey, ferryman! Can you come over here?
Oi.
Okay, so this is the way it works.
10% 9% instead of your
20% 79% finder's fee.
I'm sorry, I can't let you
take advantage of me like that.
That's the way it is.
Take it or leave it.
Fine. But I go with you.
Not on my boat, you don't.
Look, I mean, do you
think I'm stupid enough
to tell you where a fortune
might be without some insurance?
There's five other
salvage boats on this dock
that would jump at what I got.
I come with you, so you
"take it or leave it."
Ow! Those things are dull!
Gonna love it. What do you think?
I think you took a little
too much off the sides,
but I think I can come up
with something she'll love.
Shave that yourself.
You sure you
don't want to help me out?
Who the fuck are you kidding, greer?
Everybody knows you Navy
boys take it up the ass.
Enjoying the ride, Jack?
No, sir.
Not the same as flying weather planes
over ice sheets, is it?
What's the appeal?
I could ask you the same thing.
You mean, "what's a
nice girl doing like me
doing in a dump like this
instead of raising a family?"
Simple, I own a third
of Murphy's operation.
I'm not that nice.
And these monkeys are my family.
Santos to Murphy, come in.
- Yep?
- Yo, murph,
I think you should get up here.
What is it?
I think you should see this!
Not a damn thing was
there a second ago, man!
10 miles to the northwest.
Would you turn off that fucking music?
Man, I'm telling you,
there must be some kind of
glitch with the machine.
It was there a second ago.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Glitch, my ass.
There's nothing there.
Give me a look at this thing.
There! Take a look!
There it is! Right in front of you!
Okay?
View it with our own eyes,
and tell me you don't see nothing.
Huh? Do you see what I'm saying?
Can't you see what I'm saying to you?
Dodge, could you get on the bow light?
All right, murph.
It's there, right?
There's something there.
Hey, murph, what's up?
Vessel at position seven-five north.
This is arctic warrior.
Come in.
This is tugboat arctic
warrior, do you read me?
This is arctic warrior.
Do you read me? Come in.
= shit!
Huh? Now do you believe me?
Holy shit!
An ocean liner?
Where did that come from?
The antonia graza.
Jesus Christ.
This is civilian tugboat arctic warrior.
Is there anyone aboard?
Is anyone aboard?
This is arctic warrior. Can you read us?
- You know her, Murphy?
- Only in my dreams.
Christ, she's beautiful.
These Italian liners, they
couldn't compete for speed,
so they built floating
art palaces instead.
She was reported missing
on the 21st of may, 1962,
somewhere off the coast of labrador.
Funny thing is, there
was no distress signal,
no contact, she just disappeared.
She was gone.
So ever since that day,
every captain and his
mother's been looking for her,
hoping she hasn't gone down.
Do you know what this means?
What?
It means, under the law
of the sea, she's ours.
Let's not keep a lady waiting, guys.
Santos, bring us alongside.
Greer, fire up the crane.
We got business to do.
Okay, when we get on board, stay together.
We don't know what kind
of shape she's in, okay?
Take us up, greer.
Aye, aye, captain.
Hey, Murphy, please remember
to keep all channels open.
Thank you.
They won't let me go.
Safety first.
That's why you go last, Jack.
Can you sit down, please?
I'm trying to keep this thing steady.
I just want... = sit down!
Get out of the way, man!
Get out of the way!
Okay. Fuck.
She's had some battering
over the last 40 years,
you can tell that.
Stand by, murph.
Setting you down topside.
Wow, she's still a beaut, eh?
= unbelievable.
Okay, guys,
you better stay alert.
Watch your step.
40 years of rust can turn
deck plates into quicksand.
We'll make our way in at the fore,
then check the bridge, okay?
This way. Be careful now.
Forward mast is history.
Epps and Murphy, are
they a couple or just...
Hell, no. She's like a daughter to him.
He'd be lost without her.
Well, the
superstructure's in decent shape.
No sign of damage here.
Lifeboats
are gone, stern to bow.
I see the life
preserver lockers are all empty.
You sure no survivors
ever turned up, murph?
Sure as we're walking
on the graza, dodge.
This way.
Let's go.
Jesus, she's no Fiddler's green.
You're wrong,
munder. She's beautiful.
Whoever was on here
originally sure left in a hurry.
Murphy, come in.
Whoa.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome aboard.
I'm Julie. I'll be your
hostess this evening.
J the love boat /
shh! Have some respect, okay?
Shh!
Hey, check out all
those champagne bottles.
It looks like we
missed one hell of a party.
- And one hell of a hangover.
- Shut up!
Shut up!
Let's go find the bridge.
- Such a manly man.
- What?
- What? All right?
- Shut up!
Come on, Mary, let's go.
Murph, how many
passengers did she carry?
= over 600.
The creme de la creme of
society from all over Europe.
Crew of 500 from Italy.
Talk to me, man.
How's everything going up there?
Okay, good.
This companionway should
get us to the bridge.
Here, epps, hold this.
What's going on?
- After you.
- No, after you.
No, no, no, no, no. After me.
Oh. Tough guy.
Don't let go!
= pull! Hold on!
Pull up!
Please, epps, don't let go!
Give me your hand. = pull us up!
= pull us back!
Oh, god!
I told you to
watch your fucking step!
- Oh, shit. Oh, Jesus.
- From now on,
you let me lead. Okay?
Okay - let's go.
I think I just shit my pants.
No, you always smell that way.
Compass is dead.
Helm's not responding, either.
Fuel tanks are empty.
She must've rode on full
throttle till she was bone-dry.
Epps!
I'm looking for the ship's log.
Let's get this documentation back...
Are you okay? = yeah.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
Let's get to it.
Hey, check this out.
Hey, it's a watch.
Congratulations, buddy.
No. Look again, you moron.
It's a digital watch. Do the math.
They didn't have digital watches in 1962.
But she's ours now.
Let's get a couple hours of sleep.
We'll have to tow her at dawn.
Let's hope there's no more surprises.
Amen to that.
Oh, god.
Epps, can I get some tea?
Any sign of what might've happened?
How she got here?
That's the $64 million
question, isn't it?
You ever hear of a ship
called the Marie Celeste?
No.
She was a twin-masted brigantine
out of Charleston, south
Carolina, during the civil war.
She was bound for London with
a cargo of cotton in her hull.
Thanks.
Anyway, two months after she set sail,
she was sighted by fishermen off Tripoli.
She was doing 12 knots an
hour in a stiff breeze.
Something wasn't quite right.
They didn't know what,
so they went on board.
You know what they found?
No passengers, no crew,
no captain, no sign of distress.
59 days after the last entry in the log,
that ship had traveled 4,500
miles across the open ocean,
past the rock of Gibraltar
and into the mediterranean sea
at full sail,
and nobody at the helm.
What do you make of that?
A ghost ship.
Hey, you smell that?
Ti smell bullshit.
Been on the sea a lot
longer than you, dodge.
T know.
I've seen things that
you can't even imagine.
Maritime history is
full of Marie celestes.
So, what's our plan?
Well, I think we should
do what we came to do.
Tie her up, tug her in.
What, you think our little tug
is gonna pull this entire ocean liner?
Yeah.
Not with the problems we got.
We could set her at anchor,
come back later with two or three tugs.
No, some Russian trawler
will come along, scoop her up.
I've already looked
for her anchors, anyway.
They're gone.
What do you think, greer?
If Santos gets the
engines working right,
it could take us two weeks minimum
to tow a vessel this size.
But for my share of what she's worth,
I'd drag her big ass
back to Anchorage myself.
Don't let go!
Help me! Don't let go!
Thought you might want a jacket.
Thanks.
Boy, do I miss that.
You okay?
You seem quiet since you came back.
I think I saw something I
couldn't possibly have seen.
Like what?
No, it's crazy. It doesn't matter.
No, I'm curious. Tell me.
I think I saw a little girl.
On, on the boat?
Yeah. Looking right at me.
And then what happened?
Nothing. She disappeared.
Sometimes, when I'd be
flying for hours on end,
I'd think I'd see stuff too.
It'd be there one second
and gone the next,
like a dream, you know?
Thanks.
- See you in the A.M.
- Okay.
Good night.
See you tomorrow. - Yeah.
She's got a big hole.
She's sinking.
This is where the damage is. See?
There's a breach in
the hull, about 10 by 20,
torn to the port collision bulkhead.
Did it hit an iceberg or something?
No, you don't need
an iceberg to rupture a hull.
I don't know, I was just...
Looks like she's been hit recently.
About a week ago, I'd say.
This is where we are.
The problem is this group of
islands 60 miles westerly,
nothing spectacular,
just a bunch of rocks,
a couple of thousand seals.
The antonia graza's caught here
in this really strong current loop.
And slowly but surly, she's
been pushed towards those rocks.
Last time she hit them.
What about next time”?
There won't be a next time.
We've got three days to fix it.
That's if the weather holds.
Why can't we tow it like it is?
It'd be like towing a '57 Cadillac
with four flat tires, man.
It's a bump in the road.
We can fix it.
Whoa, murph, bump in the road?
Look, you know, the breach
we can probably patch
if we can get to the inside.
Then we'll weld shut the
flooded compartments,
pump out the water through
the collision bulkhead,
run it right up to the aft peak.
On top of that, the rudder's jammed.
We Jerry-rig it, set a
38-degree current drift
to clear the island chain.
What does all that mean?
Well, I mean, that's
a lot of work for three days.
Yeah, but with the
gear we've got on board,
and with what's on that
ship, we can give it a shot.
We can do it, right?
Murph, with the gear we've got on board,
I can't fix our little engine problem.
Why don't you quit bitching
and just overhaul the
starboard engine, please?
So that's the plan? Right.
= just do it.
= I'll call it in.
Eh, I wouldn't do that
if I were you, greer.
Maritime law states that...
Yeah, I know what maritime law states.
We just don't want any unexpected guests.
Just leave it.
Your call, captain.
All right, you know the drill.
We do a complete recon,
just enough to make sure
we've got no more problems
before we get to work.
Stay right beside me, greer.
No wandering off, okay?
All right.
Dodge, munder, go to the
port collision bulkhead.
Jack and I'll work back from the fore.
And call me if you need anything.
How about a pizza?
You're so funny.
"The only plan in this business
is that there is no plan.”
I mean, what is that?
I mean, what these
people talking crazy for?
Why are looking at me like that?
That's not even good english.
It's okay.
Hey, you hang in there, okay, preciosa?
Because someday he's gonna
find some other genius
to fix his goddamn boat.
Hey, you want to play like that? Yeah?
That is still sweet though, huh?
Light coming up.
Oh yeah.
You were right. She is beautiful.
She sure is.
Epps, we're heading for
the main engine room. Epps?
Epps?
Yeah, all right, capitano.
Oh, shit.
J I'm just slippin" in the darkness j
We're gonna have to dive
to get to that tear.
Epps, the engine room is totally flooded.
Epps, can you hear me?
Wait!
What happened? You okay?
Come here.
What are you doing down there?
Did you hurt yourself?
The whole bottom's riddled with them.
Looks like someone used
it for target practice.
That's the happy version.
What's the not-so-happy version?
There were people in there.
I saw that little girl again.
What? Where?
I must be losing my goddamn mind.
Well, did she say anything?
Forget it. Come on.
Murphy, come in.
Dodge! Anybody!
Shit.
I think she's fucking with us.
Looks like central laundry.
This ventilation shaft
connects to the forward hold.
We need to see if it's flooded.
I might need help shutting it again.
So get ready.
Yoouu sure?
Murphy, where the hell are you?
How long do you think they've been here?
I don't know, a month, maybe less.
Well, what are we gonna do?
We're gonna call the coast
guard, get off this boat!
But the ship...
If it sinks, it sinks, Jack!
Come on.
You're right.
Stinks.
What the hell?
We came through here.
= no shit!
Come on!
This way. Come on, Jack.
What the...
When did you start wearing lipstick, epps?
Epps?
"Francesca." nice titties.
Not that you can hold a candle
to the future Mrs. greer, though.
Come on, Jack.
Stop dragging ass!
What's your problem?
What's this?
Forget it.
Let's go! Jack!
Hey!
This is '58 Jaguar x150.
I had dreams about this
car since I was a kid...
We have to get out of here now.
Do you understand me? Now.
Okay.
There's something moving in there.
Fuck!
Oh, oh my god! I hate rats!
What?
Oh, my god! Look at this!
I have to get Murphy.
Murphy!
Is someone trying to call me?
Dodge? Munder?
Maureen, Maureen...
Who is Maureen?
It's my first name.
It's cold, it's cold...
Did he say "cold?"
The galley.
- It's cold.
- Please help us.
Don't go in there.
You fucking assholes!
Fuck you!
Take it easy!
Come on. You were fucking with us.
We fucked with you.
Why aren't you laughing?
Do you wanna hear something funnier?
We found a bunch of dead guys
floating in the laundry room.
And this in the cargo hold.
Need some help there, skipper?
I'm sorry.
- Holy shit!
- Oh, man.
Yes!
Yeah!
We're rich!
You son of a bitch! = rich!
Come on. Let's go.
= let's move this shit out of here!
You fucking creep!
How much we figure it's worth, boss?
There's a lot of gold there.
Hard to know.
2, 300 million, maybe. Maybe more.
- Jesus.
- I don't know, Murphy.
Lock boxes with half of fort Knox in them?
They gotta be insured.
I mean, there's no way
somebody's gonna let
this amount of gold just float away.
Well, this has got something to with it.
The markings have been filed down.
What does that mean?
Well, it means that somebody
didn't want this traceable.
It's stolen.
It might have something
to do with the reason why
this ship disappeared when it did.
= wait a minute.
If the gold's got
something to do with 1962,
then what about those
guys that epps found?
I mean, they can't be
more than three weeks old.
Look, somebody's gotta say
it, and it might as well be me.
This ship is fucked up, Murphy.
Earlier when I was doing my recon,
I could swear I heard a
woman's voice singing to me.
It was like she was,
like she was coming on to me or something.
Oh, no!
It was the sexiest
voice I ever heard, man.
Hey man, she got any backup singers?
But, brother, whatever
you're on, give me some!
I think maybe you're not quite ready
to get married, greer.
- Fuck you.
- Okay, guys.
What about the coast guard?
No, if you call the coast guard, I mean,
what if the gold did
turn out to be stolen?
Okay, under international maritime law,
anything that's found
in international waters
belongs to the finder.
Okay? That is the law.
- Right.
- Finders keepers.
Hey, look, if we're gonna
do this, I say we do it now.
I say we get our boat
going, grab the gold,
and get the hell out of here.
Okay, we leave the boat, take the gold.
Who's with me?
I'm with the gold, man.
Gold.
The gold.
Epps?
I just want to get off this boat.
Okay. Let's go to work.
Okay. Warrior
is in position, murph.
Now, can we please get
the hell out of here?
Yeah, preciosa! Smell that money!
100 million, do you hear what I'm saying?
100 million!
Greer? Get those engines going.
I'm bringing the gold down.
Yes, sir, captain, sir.
Hey, Santos. Hurry your ass up, vato.
We almost got the gold on deck.
Andele! Andele!
I wanna see these gauges rocking,
because you just had a
overhaul from Santos, baby.
And you, I want you to give me some too.
Let's do this!
Hey, yo, greer! Fire it up!
We're gonna haul some ass out of here.
Bring it on!
We're gonna be so fucking rich!
Stop!
Stop! You don't know what you're doing!
Yeah, we're good to go, skipper.
Don't start the boat! He'll...
= shit!
Greer!
Greer! What the hell just happened?
= Jesus Christ!
Fire on deck!
Santos! Greer! Munder!
I got you.
Epps! I got munder!
Greer!
Greer! Come on!
Santos! Santos, answer me!
Santos!
I don't know what happened.
The engine room just blew.
I don't know, maybe
Santos rushed the engines,
didn't seal up the gaskets
right, I don't know.
Hey, Jack, did you find anything out
about this ship before
you sent us out here?
No, but I...
Look, I mean, we've got the
gold, and we are still alive.
Yeah, tell that to Santos, asshole!
Hey! Dodge, ease up!
Well, this is bullshit!
Hey, look, Santos came
here out of free will,
just like the rest of us.
What does that mean, huh?
What the fuck do you mean...
Hey! Enough!
Santos is dead because of you!
Come on, come on, come on.
That's not gonna bring him back.
Hey.
Murph, it's not your fault.
You know that.
Murph...
How is he?
All right, here's the plan.
The way I figure it,
we're professional salvors
with a fortune on board.
I say we do what we do best,
we fix this rust bucket.
Try and control her drift,
and clear those islands.
We can survive on here long
enough to get picked up.
Why is this even a question?
We have the materials.
We have the manpower.
Why don't we build a raft
and get off of this thing?
I told you guys earlier
that there was something
seriously wrong with this boat!
The longer we stay here,
the less chance we have of surviving.
You want to build a raft?
= I want to build a raft.
Epps, even with the warrior,
we were stretching to get
this done in three days.
We can't do this. I can't do it.
Munder, you're the
best spot-welder I know.
Come on. We can do it
right now, but I need you.
Okay, fine, whatever.
But, there's no way we're doing
a major patch-and-pump in the dark.
Even with the lights we have,
it'd be like going in blind.
Okay, fine. We'll chill
tonight and go in the A.M..
Greer? What do you say?
What, now you want to know
what the first mate has to say?
Well, I say go to hell, epps.
You're not fucking qualified
to get us off this ship.
And had Murphy let me do
it my way from the start,
we wouldn't be in this
situation right now.
And the coast guard, everybody's
so fucking worried about...
Right. So it's everybody
else's fault but your own, right?
We'd be on our way home, millionaires.
= that's bullshit.
Grow up, asshole.
- Hey!
- Fucking bitch!
Keep fucking talking!
Say another word!
Here it is.
Katie, b-deck.
You were alone.
100-to-1, somebody
poisoned the passengers
to get the gold.
Okay, okay, Sherlock,
if the passengers were poisoned,
why do you think these cans safe?
They're still sealed.
This stuff's been sealed for 40 years.
It's gotta be safe.
Okay, shoot
for it. Loser goes first.
Ah! Paper beats rock.
Best of three.
= bullshit! You lost.
Where's your empathy?
Winners do not empathize with losers.
Bon appetit.
I screwed up.
I should've called it in.
Damn! I knew better!
I'll make it home to you, baby. I swear.
What the hell are you looking at?
Mm, that's all right.
- No way.
- No, really, it's good.
Look, I'm not kidding.
- Are you serious?
- I'm serious. It's good!
Mm. Oh, wow!
You gotta try that!
That's good!
That's great!
Katie?
Can I tell you something else?
We get back, I'm gonna take my money
and I'm gonna buy you a bathtub.
I'm gonna get you a lifetime supply
of titty magazines and toilet paper!
I already beat you to it, bro!
There's something on your...
Katie?
Buonasera, capitano. Benvenuto.
Vuoi ballare con me?
Who, me?
Si.
Francesca, I know
all of this isn't real.
So I'm just gonna go with it, okay?
Can't cheat on your fiance
with a dead girl, right?
Her parents.
Please.
Don't close it.
I haven't seen them for years.
They moved to New York.
I was on my way to join them.
But they're dead now.
How would you know that?
When you're like this,
vou know these things.
My mother, she made me this dress.
Do you like it?
You remind me of her.
T don't think so.
Well, here.
You should have this back.
Oh, god, you really are a fucking ghost.
Where are you going?
Santos. Povero Santos.
Santos was my goddamn responsibility.
= the Lorelei.
= she was adrift. We rescued her.
I've heard the story of the Lorelei.
I didn't know the graza was involved.
The gold was on board the Lorelei?
It says here "may 19, 1962."
That's two days before
your ship disappeared.
There were no survivors
on board the Lorelei.
Jesus Christ!
Where you going?
Most spirits are free
to be with their families.
So why aren't you with yours?
- We're all trapped here.
- Who?
My shipmates and 1.
Even the ones who aren't marked.
Marked? Katie, what do you mean?
When the boat's full...
What? It's okay, you can tell me.
When he has all the souls he needs,
and has filled his quota,
we'll all be ferried to...
What is it? What's wrong?
What is it? Katie, what's wrong?
He doesn't want me talking to you.
He who?
= but I'm not like the others!
Katie, you need to tell me.
You must go at once.
Leave the ship while you still can!
Katie, what is it?
Katie! Katie?
Epps?
Come on!
We have to leave.
- Where you going, Murphy?
- What?
What's the matter, huh?
It's me,
Santos.
You know, it's no fun lying around
down at the bottom of the ocean.
No bright lights at the end of the tunnel.
Not for me, murph.
No 10,000 virgins at the pearly gates. No.
Because of the plan, I'm trapped
on this dreamboat of yours.
So you know what?
You're coming along for the ride.
No!
Benvenuto a bordo.
Murphy?
Murph?
You all right, murph?
You okay?
What's the matter, murph? Come on.
= it's Mel
murph!
It's Mel
do it, come on.
It'll make you feel good.
= come on!
Hey!
Murph!
Oh, god. Epps, are you okay?
He'll be safe if we
keep him in the aquarium.
No, listen to me. He was drunk.
He didn't know what he was doing.
Look, he just tried to kill you.
He stays in there.
Let's go find greer.
Any sign of him?
No, we looked all over.
The man is severely pissed off.
Seems to happen to everybody on this boat.
At least we weren't around 40 years ago.
Do you think somebody
poisoned the passengers
to get to the gold?
I know you think that's a little...
Extreme? Yeah, maybe.
But if the shoe fits...
I mean, look, next thing you know,
we'll be trying to kill each other.
What's with the heart?
Found it. Belonged to this little girl.
What girl?
She told me to get off this boat.
You mean she's talking to you now?
What the hell are
you guys talking about?
You're seeing ghosts, epps?
Anyway, just forget it.
So the ship's got a few kinks in it.
Look, I just say we
stick with munder's specs
and we try to fix the ship.
Well, there's like no way
five people and the gold
are gonna fit on any raft.
Murphy's not going anywhere right now,
and we're not leaving him here.
We stick with the plan. Fix the boat.
Let's get going, guys. Come on.
That's the
collision bulkhead hatch.
Wheel's busted.
It's not gonna open.
Arming the c4.
Dodge? - I'm good.
- Munder?
- I'm good.
Contact.
There's the tear, portside.
Looks bigger from here.
I'll shut her up, no problem.
Munder, rudder's fixed.
You all right? - I'm good.
What do you think, dodge?
She'll hold.
Okay, we're set
with the pumps down here.
Start 'em up.
Copy that, epps.
One and two, kicking in.
I give it 12
hours till she's bone-dry.
Both on full.
Get ready, epps. Here it comes.
Great work, guys.
Damn. Current's faster than I thought.
If we control her drift as much
as possible with the rudder,
keeping her headed in this direction,
we should just clear those islands.
We'll keep this sucker afloat
as long as it takes to get picked up.
Son of a bitch, we may
just get out of this yet.
Kazillionaires.
I want you to check on the
bridge when you're done here.
Watch our drift.
I'm gonna see if I can
find greer down below.
Greer?
Katie?
Greer? Jesus!
Aw shit!
Number two's clogged. Who's going?
You go.
Aw shit! Every single time!
Oh, my god.
Come with me.
I want to show you something.
No!
J silent in my sanity j
j I live safe inside my cell j
j in the darkness that surrounds me j
j I see my own special hell
j comfort in my suffering j
j; Feeling warm inside this pain j
j; Four walls coming down on me j
j come on down again
j you woke me out of my secret grave j
j you let your pretty world in j
j cradle falls
j sorry that it had
j to be this way j
j but you took me out of my skin j
j unholy walls j you woke it j
j out of my secret grave
j you let your pretty world in j
j cradle falls j
j unholy walls j
J now you're in my world j
j; Did you dream it'd be so small j
j my little box was perfect j
j until you destroyed it all j
j; My sanctity of sorrow gone j
j forever in it's place j
j; The saccharine sweet of you j
j is all that's left to taste j
I feeling claustrophobic /
j now my world is closing in j
j subtle retribution j
j where I am and where I've been
j I'll take you to a place j
j you never knew could be
j curled up, in my little box j
j cradle falls j
Murphy.
Murphy!
Come on! No!
Come on!
Come on.
You can't die on me!
Dodge, Murphy's dead.
- What?
- We have got to get off
this boat now.
You, me, and munder,
there is a reason you why the
three of us are still alive.
That's why he came after
us, to fix his ship.
I just saw Murphy.
What's happening?
T don't know.
But I want you and dodge
to stay on the rudder here.
Wait! But you just said...
Dodge, listen to me.
I'm gonna get munder.
We're gonna check and see
if the welds are holding.
I want you both to stay
here till we get back.
You understand?
I do not want you out
of each other's sight.
Take this.
Take it.
- Be careful down there.
- Ti will.
Munder! Munder!
That's it, then. We made it.
For now.
I'm gonna go check on epps.
No, you're not. She said to wait here.
Yeah, I know, but I just wanna make sure
she's okay.
Hey, she said to wait!
So wait.
You disgust me.
What did you say?
=- you heard me.
You're a pathetic excuse for a man.
She says "jump,” and you jump.
You're disgusting.
I don't have time for this.
Who the hell are you?
Don't worry about who I am.
The question is, who are you?
I've seen the way you look at her.
You worship her,
yet you've never had
the balls to tell her,
because you're a weak, cowardly child.
However, if you'll kindly
step out of my way,
I'll make your dream a reality.
You know, dodge, if you kill
somebody, you go to hell.
Well, you live for her.
You willing to die for her?
Epps!
I shot ferriman.
He's dead.
Yeah? Don't be so sure, dodge.
What are you doing?
Trip's over. I'm sinking the boat.
It's taken its last victim.
= but that'll kill us.
We're gonna have to take our chances.
What about the gold?
You fucking kidding?
We're not getting the gold off this boat.
Nobody ever does.
Wait, wait, wait!
That gold can give us
everything we ever wanted.
We could have our own boat, the two of us.
We could have a life together, you and me.
What are you talking about?
Dodge, we gotta get out of here, now.
Well, I can't let you do that.
So that's it, huh?
All right. Okay.
You win. All right.
All right! All right!
Fucking bitch!
All right, you win!
Go ahead, do it!
Go ahead. Blow it up!
Kill us all!
Hey, dodge, why haven't you
asked me where munder is?
Well, I suppose that's
because I already know.
You're not gonna pull
that trigger, Maureen.
Try me.
Dodge made the same mistake. He's dead.
Katie told you, didn't she?
You see, souls without
sin can't be marked.
Makes them tough to control.
But as long as I keep the boat afloat,
we'll all go down together.
What the fuck are you?
I'm a salvager, just like you.
You collect ships, I collect souls.
And when I fill my quota,
ti send a boatload home.
This will make management happy.
You see, it's a job,
given to me after a lifetime of sin.
So if I lose this ship,
management won't be happy,
which is not a good thing.
I don't seem to be getting through to you.
What I'm asking for is an exchange.
This ship for your life.
I want my crew back.
Sorry. Once a passenger's
marked, they're mine.
Then I guess it's over.
All you had to do was fix the ship!
I gave you a great opportunity.
All you had to do was take it.
What are you gonna do, shoot me?
Careful. Hang in there, ma'am.
No!
J; Always, known in, all my time j
I a little left of center now j
I reflect as I realize j
j that all I need is to find
the middle pillar path
j to sit like the sun by a
star in the sky and just be j
j sinners, casting stones at me
ji, istand
j not crawling j
j not falling down
j I, I bleed the demons /
j; That drag me down j
ji, istand ; J for nothing, j
I not crawling j j; The center j
j not falling down j
j of calm's within the eye
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j that pull me down [j
I! For me and no one else
j; Goodbye, sunshine j
j I've put it out again j
j; Sad j,
j I'm over, personalities conflicting j
j I don't need you, or anyone, but me j
j I'll just be, living my own life j
j I feel my glowing
center grow, infecting
j I feel alive j
j shovel dirt over lime j
j plant it in myself to sit like a seed /
j under covers of earth and just be j
j sinners, pointing fingers at me j
ji, istand j j for nothing
j not crawling j j by myself j
j not falling down
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j; That drag me down j
ji, istand j j for nothing
I not crawling j j; The center j
j not falling down j
j of calm's within the eye
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j that pull me down [j
I! For me and no one else
j come play kill ;
j; Refuse my body, refuse my shadow j
j stone cold will 2
j refuse to lead this, refuse to follow
j bitter pills j
j refuse to feed this, refuse to swallow j
j come play kill ;
j; Refuse my body, refuse my shadow j
j stone cold will 2
j refuse to lead this, refuse to follow
j bitter pills j
j refuse to feed this, refuse to swallow j
j I'm fueled godless
j come play j
j just be
Ji, istand j j for nothing
j not crawling j j by myself j
j not falling down
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j; That drag me down j
ji, istand j j for nothing
I not crawling j j; The center j
j not falling down j
j of calm's within the eye
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j; That drag me down j
ji, istand j j for nothing
I not crawling j j; The center j
j not falling down j
j of calm's within the eye
ji, I'll bleed 7 j for no one j
j the demons j j but myself j;
j that drag me down
I! For me and no one else