Everybody, heads up!
Keep it clear, now.
Keep it clear!
Stand back!
Bring it
forward, come on!
Slow it down!
- Pushing team, move in there.
- Move in.
- On your ready.
- I want Tasers on full charge.
Steady!
Go on. Step back in.
Ready. Move it.
And push.
Locked. Loading team,
step away.
Move it.
Jophery, raise the gate.
Block the opening!
Don't let her get out!
Somebody help him!
Work her back!
Shoot her!
I heard that Hammond's
not even here.
He sends his apologies.
There's a $20 million lawsuit
by the family of that worker
and you're telling me
that Hammond can't see me?
He had to leave early, his
daughter's getting a divorce.
I understand, but we need to
deal with the situation now.
The insurance company...
You okay?
The underwriters feel that the accident's
raised safety questions about the park.
That makes the investors
very anxious.
I had to promise to conduct a very
thorough, on-site inspection.
Hammond hates inspections.
They slow everything down.
I need to or they'll
pull the funding.
That'll slow him down
even more.
Watch your head.
If two experts sign off
on the island,
the insurance guys
will back off.
I've already got Ian Malcolm,
but they think he's too trendy.
They want Alan Grant.
Grant?
You'll never get him
out of Montana.
Why not?
Because Grant's like me.
He's a digger.
Dr. Grant, Dr. Sattler,
we're ready to try again.
I hate computers.
The feeling's mutual.
Take a look.
Did it work?
How long
does this take?
Should bring
an immediate return.
You shoot the radar
into the ground,
and the bone bounces
the image back.
Bounces it back...
This new program
is incredible.
A few more
years' development,
and we won't even
have to dig anymore.
Where's the fun
in that?
It's a little distorted, but I
don't think it's the computer.
Post-mortem contraction of the
posterior neck ligaments.
Velociraptor?
Yes. Good shape, too.
It's five, six feet high.
I'm guessing nine feet long.
Look...
What'd you do?
He touched it.
Dr. Grant's not
machine-compatible.
Hell, they've got it
in for me.
And look at the half-moon
shaped bones in the wrists.
It's no wonder these guys
learned how to fly.
No, seriously.
Maybe dinosaurs have more in common with
present-day birds than with reptiles.
Look at the pubic bone, turned
backward, just like a bird.
Look at the vertebrae, full of air
sacs and hollows, like a bird.
And even the word "Raptor"
means "bird of prey."
That doesn't
look very scary.
More like a 6-foot turkey.
A turkey?
Imagine yourself in the
Cretaceous period.
Here we go.
You'd get your first look at this
6-foot turkey as you enter a clearing.
He moves like a bird,
lightly bobbing his head.
You keep still because you think maybe
his visual acuity is based on movement,
like T-Rex and he'll lose
you if you don't move.
But no,
not Velociraptor.
You stare at him and he
just stares right back.
And that's when
the attack comes.
Not from the front,
but from the side.
From the other two Raptors you
didn't even know were there.
Because Velociraptor's
a pack hunter.
He uses coordinated
attack patterns
and he is out
in force today.
And he slashes at you
with this,
a 6-inch retractable claw, like
a razor, on the middle toe.
He doesn't bother to bite
your jugular like a lion. No.
He slashes at you
here or here...
Alan.
Or maybe across the belly,
spilling your intestines.
The point is, you are alive
when they start to eat you.
So, you know, try to
show a little respect.
Okay.
Alan, if you wanted
to scare the kid,
you could've pulled
a gun on him.
Yeah, I know. Kids.
You want to have
one of those?
I don't want that kid,
but a breed of the child
could be intriguing.
I mean, what's so
wrong with kids?
They're noisy, they're
messy, they're expensive.
Cheap, cheap.
They smell.
They don't smell!
Some smell.
Give me a break!
Babies smell.
Cover the site!
Cover up the dig!
Tell them to shut down!
Cut the machine!
Cover it all up.
Pull it over.
Just cut it, will you?
Shut it down!
What?
What the hell do you think
you're doing in here?
We were saving that.
For today, I guarantee it.
Who in God's name
do you think you are?
John Hammond.
And I'm delighted to meet you
finally in person, Dr. Grant.
So, I can see that my $50,000
a year has been well spent.
Who's the jerk?
This is our paleobotanist,
Dr...
Sattler.
Ellie, this
is Mr. Hammond.
I'm sorry about the dramatic
entrance, Dr. Sattler, but...
Did I say "jerk"?
...we're in a hurry.
Will you have a drink? We won't
let it get warm. Sit down.
Let me have this.
I'll just get a glass or two. I can do it.
There's samples
all over here.
I know my way
around the kitchen.
Now, I'll get right
to the point.
I like you.
Both of you.
I can tell instantly about people.
It's a gift.
I own an island off the
coast of Costa Rica.
I've leased it from the government
and during the last five years,
I've been setting up
a biological preserve.
Really spectacular.
Spared no expense.
Make the one I've got down in
Kenya look like a petting zoo.
And there's no doubt our attractions
will drive kids out of their minds.
And what are those?
Small versions of
adults, honey.
And not just kids,
everyone.
We're going to open next year, if
the lawyers don't kill me first.
I don't care for
lawyers, do you?
I don't really know any.
Don't really know any.
I do, there's a particular pebble in
my shoe, who represents my investors.
Says that they insist
on outside opinions.
What kind of opinions?
Well, your kind, not to put
too fine a point on it.
Let's face it, in your particular
fields, you're the top minds.
And if I could just
persuade you
to sign off on the park,
give it your endorsement,
maybe even pen a wee testimonial,
I could get back on schedule.
Why would they care
what we think?
What kind of park
is this?
It's right up your alley.
Why don't you come down, just the
pair of you, for the weekend?
I'd love to have an opinion
of a paleobotanist as well.
I've got a jet
standing by at Choteau.
I'm sorry.
This isn't possible.
We just dug up
a new skeleton...
I could compensate you
by fully funding your dig...
This is a very unusual time.
The timing is...
...for a further
three years.
Where's the plane?
Okay.
Three years.
Cheers.
Dodgson!
You shouldn't use my name.
Dodgson. We've got
Dodgson here.
See, nobody cares.
Nice hat.
What're you trying to look
like, a secret agent?
Well?
$750,000.
On delivery, $50,000 more
for each viable embryo.
That's $1.5 million if you get
all 15 species off the island.
I'll get them all.
Remember, viable embryos. They're
no use to us if they don't survive.
How am I supposed
to transport them?
The bottom screws open.
That's great.
Oh, my God.
It's cooled and
compartmentalized inside.
You guys.
That's great.
Customs can even check it
if they want to.
Let me see.
Go on.
There's enough coolant
for 36 hours.
No menthol?
The embryos have to be back
here in San José by then.
That's up to your guy
on the boat.
7:00 tomorrow night on the East Dock.
Make sure he gets it right.
How are you planning
to beat security?
I've got
an 18-minute window.
Eighteen minutes and your company
catches up on 10 years of research.
Don't get cheap on me,
Dodgson.
That was
Hammond's mistake.
So you two
dig up dinosaurs?
Well...
We try to.
You'll have to get
used to Dr. Malcolm.
He suffers from a deplorable
excess of personality,
especially for
a mathematician.
Chaotician. Chaotician,
actually.
John doesn't subscribe
to chaos,
particularly what it says
about his science project.
Ian, you've never been able to
sufficiently explain your concerns...
Because of the behavior
of the system in phase space?
A load, if I may say so, of
fashionable number crunching...
Don't.
Dr. Sattler, Dr. Grant,
you've heard of Chaos Theory?
No.
No? Non-linear equations?
Strange attractors?
I refuse to believe that you aren't
familiar with the concept of attraction.
I bring scientists.
You bring a rock star.
There it is.
Bad wind shears.
We have to drop pretty fast.
Hold on, this will
be thrilling.
But you need that piece over
here, and that piece...
We'll have landed
by the time you get it right.
Great.
The full 50 miles of perimeter
fence are in place?
And the concrete moats, and the
motion-sensor tracking systems.
Donald, dear boy, relax.
Try and enjoy yourself.
Let's get this straight. This
is not a weekend excursion.
This is a serious investigation
of the stability of the island.
Your investors, whom I
represent, are deeply concerned.
Forty-eight hours from now, if they're
not convinced, I'm not convinced.
I'll shut you down, John.
In 48 hours, I'll be
accepting your apologies.
All right, slow down.
Slow. Stop!
This shouldn't be here.
Alan, this species of
Veriforman has been extinct
since the Cretaceous Period.
I mean, this thing...
What?
Look at that.
It's a dinosaur.
You did it. Crazy son
of a bitch, you did it.
We could tear up the rule book on
cold-bloodedness. it doesn't apply.
They're wrong. This is
a warm-blooded creature.
This thing doesn't
live in a swamp.
This thing's got
a 25, 27-foot neck?
The Brachiosaurus?
30.
Thirty feet.
We're gonna make
a fortune with this place.
How fast are they?
Well, we clocked the T-Rex
at 32 miles an hour.
T-Rex?
You said you've
got a T-Rex?
Say again.
We have a T-Rex.
Put your head
between your knees.
Dr. Grant,
my dear Dr. Sattler,
welcome to Jurassic Park.
They're moving in herds.
They do move in herds.
How did you do this?
I'll show you.
Good day.
The most advanced amusement
park in the entire world,
incorporating all
the latest technologies.
And I'm not talking just about rides.
Everybody has rides.
No, we've made living biological
attractions so astounding
that they'll capture the
imagination of the entire planet.
So, what are you thinking?
That we're out of a job.
Don't you mean "extinct"?
Why don't you all sit down?
Donald, sit down.
Here he comes.
Well, here I come.
Hello.
Say hello.
Hello, John.
Yes, I've got lines.
Well, fine, I guess.
But, how did I get here?
Well, let me show you. First,
I'll need a drop of blood.
Your blood.
Right.
That hurt.
Relax, John. It's all
part of the miracle of cloning.
Hello, John.
Cloned from what?
Loy extractions never recreated
an intact DNA strand.
Not without massive
sequence gaps.
Paleo-DNA,
from what source?
Where do you get 100
million-year-old dinosaur blood?
What? What?
Well, Mr. DNA,
where did you come from?
From your blood.
Just one drop of your blood contains
billions of strands of DNA,
the building blocks of life.
A DNA strand like me is a blueprint
for building a living thing.
And sometimes animals that went extinct
millions of years ago, like dinosaurs,
left their blueprints behind for us to
find. We just had to know where to look.
A hundred million years ago, there
were mosquitoes just like today.
And just like today, they fed
on the blood of animals.
Even dinosaurs. Sometimes,
after biting a dinosaur,
mosquitoes would land on the branch
of a tree and get stuck in the sap.
After a long time, the tree sap would
get hard and become fossilized,
just like a dinosaur bone,
preserving the mosquito inside.
This fossilised tree sap,
which we call amber,
waited for millions of years
with the mosquito inside
until Jurassic Park
scientists came along.
Using sophisticated
techniques,
they extract
the preserved blood
from the mosquito,
dino DNA!
A full DNA strand contains
three billion genetic codes.
If we looked at screens like these
once a second for eight hours a day,
it'd take two years to look
at the entire DNA strand.
It's that long. Since it's
so old, it's full of holes.
Now that's where our
geneticists take over.
Thinking machine super-computers
and gene sequencers
break down the strand
in minutes.
And virtual-reality displays
show our geneticists the gaps
in the DNA sequence.
We used the complete
DNA of a frog
to fill in the holes
and complete the code.
Whew! And now,
we can make a baby dinosaur.
This score
is only temporary.
It all has very dramatic
music, of course.
A march or something.
It hasn't been written yet.
And then, the tour moves on.
Well, look here. Those
hard-working cowpokes you see behind us...
This is overwhelming, John.
Are these characters
autoerotica?
No, we have no
animatronics here.
Those people are the real miracle
workers of Jurassic Park.
...In unfertilized emu
or ostrich eggs.
Wait a minute. How do you
interrupt the cellular mitosis?
Can't we see
the unfertilized eggs?
Shortly.
Now a whole team of genetic
engineers goes to work on...
Can't you stop
these things?
I'm sorry.
It's kind of a ride.
One, two, three.
- You can't do that.
- What?
Can they do that?
The boat for the mainland
will be leaving at 1900.
All personnel be at the dock no
later than 1845. No exceptions.
Good day, Henry.
Good day, sir.
It's turning the eggs.
Perfect timing. I'd hoped they'd hatch
before I had to go to the boat.
Henry, why
didn't you tell me?
I insist on being here
when they're born.
Come on.
Come on, little one.
Come on, then.
Very good. Push.
- Very good.
- God.
Push. Come on.
Come on. Come on, then.
There you are.
They imprint on the first creature
they come in contact with.
That's it.
Helps them to trust me.
I've been present for the birth of
every little creature on this island.
Surely not the ones
that have bred in the wild?
Actually they can't
breed in the wild.
Population control is one
of our security precautions.
There's no unauthorized
breeding in Jurassic Park.
How do you know
they can't breed?
Because all the animals
in Jurassic Park are female.
We've engineered them
that way.
There you are.
Oh, my God.
Look at that.
Blood temperature seems
like about high 80s, maybe.
Wu?
Ninety-one.
Homoeothermic?
It holds that temperature?
Yes.
But, again, how do you know
they're all female?
What, does somebody go out in the park
and pull up the dinosaurs' skirts?
We control their chromosomes.
It's really not that difficult.
All vertebrate embryos are
inherently female, anyway.
They just require an extra hormone
given at the right developmental stage
to make them male.
We simply deny them that.
Deny them that?
John, the kind of control you're
attempting is not possible.
If there's one thing the history
of evolution has taught us,
it's that life will
not be contained.
Life breaks free.
Expands to new territories
and it crashes through barriers,
painfully, maybe even dangerously,
but there it is.
There it is.
You're implying that a group composed
entirely of female animals will breed?
No, I'm simply saying
that life finds a way.
What species is this?
It's a Velociraptor.
You bred Raptors?
Dr. Grant!
As I was saying, we laid on lunch for
you before you go into the park.
Our gourmet chef, Alejandro...
What are they doing?
Feeding them.
Alejandro's prepared a
delightful menu for us.
Chilean sea bass, I believe.
Shall we?
They should all be destroyed.
Robert Muldoon.
My game warden from Kenya.
Bit of an alarmist, but knows
more about Raptors than anyone.
What's their growth rate?
They're lethal at eight
months, and I do mean lethal.
I've hunted most things that can
hunt you, but the way these move...
Fast for a biped?
Cheetah speed.
Fifty, sixty miles per hour if
they ever got out in the open.
And they're
astonishing jumpers.
Yes. That's why we're taking
extreme precautions.
Do they show intelligence?
Was their brain cavity...
They show extreme
intelligence.
Even problem-solving
Especially the big one.
We bred eight originally,
but when she came in,
she took over the pride and
killed all but two of the others.
That one, when she looks at you, you
can see she's working things out.
That's why we have to
feed them like this.
She had them all attacking the
fences when the feeders came.
The fences are electrified,
right?
That's right, but they never
attack the same place twice.
They were testing the fences for
weaknesses, systematically.
They remember.
Yes. Well, who's hungry?
More
adventurous guests, of course,
can opt for our
jungle river cruise
or for a close-up look
at our majestic...
None of these attractions are
ready yet, but the park will open
with the basic tour you are about to take,
and then other rides will come on-line
six or twelve months
after that.
Absolutely spectacular
designs.
Spared no expense.
And we can charge
anything we want.
$2,000 a day, $10,000 a day,
and people will pay it.
And there's
the merchandise...
Donald.
This park was not built to
cater only for the super rich.
Everyone in the world has the
right to enjoy these animals.
Sure. They will. We'll have
a coupon day or something.
The lack of humility before nature
that's being displayed here staggers me.
Thank you. But things are a little
different than you and I had feared.
I know.
They're a lot worse.
Now, wait a second, we haven't
even seen the park yet...
Donald, let him talk. There's no reason,
I want to hear every viewpoint.
Don't you see the danger, John,
inherent in what you're doing here?
Genetic power's the most awesome
force the planet's ever seen
but you wield it like a kid
that's found his dad's gun.
It's hardly appropriate
to start hurling...
If I may.
I'll tell you the problem with the
scientific power you're using here.
It didn't require
any discipline to attain it.
You read what others had done,
and you took the next step.
You didn't earn the
knowledge for yourselves
so you don't take
any responsibility for it.
You stood on the shoulders
of geniuses to accomplish
something as fast
as you could.
Before you even knew what you had,
you patented it, and packaged it
and slapped it on a plastic lunch
box, now you're selling it.
You're going to sell it.
I don't think you're
giving us our due credit.
Our scientists have done things
which nobody has ever done before.
But your scientists were so
preoccupied with whether they could,
they didn't stop to
think if they should.
Condors. Condors are
on the verge of extinction.
If I was to create a flock of
condors on this island,
you wouldn't have
anything to say.
Hold on, this isn't some
species that was obliterated
by deforestation or
the building of a dam.
Dinosaurs had their shot and nature
selected them for extinction.
I don't understand this Luddite attitude.
Especially from a scientist.
How can we stand in the light
of discovery and not act?
What's so great
about discovery?
It's a violent,
penetrative act,
that scars what it explores.
What you call discovery,
I call the rape of
the natural world.
The question is, how can you know
anything about an extinct eco-system?
And therefore, how could you ever
assume that you can control it?
You have poisonous plants
in this building.
You picked them
because they look good.
But these are aggressive living things
that have no idea what century they're in
and they'll defend themselves.
Violently, if necessary.
Dr. Grant, if there's
one person here
who could appreciate
what I am trying to do...
The world has just changed so radically
and we're all running to catch up.
I don't want to jump to any
conclusions, but dinosaurs and man,
two species separated by 65
million years of evolution
have just been suddenly thrown
back into the mix together.
How can we possibly have the
slightest idea what to expect?
I don't believe it.
You're meant to come here and
defend me against these characters
and the only one I've got on my
side is the blood-sucking lawyer.
Thank you.
They're here.
You four are gonna have a spot
of company out in the park.
Spend a little time
with our target audience.
Grandpa!
Kids!
Wait! Careful with me.
We missed you.
Me, too.
We loved the presents.
They were great.
Did you enjoy
the helicopter?
Yeah, it went down
and we all went right up.
Now, kids, come away.
Not too close to the cars.
Aren't they lovely?
Aren't they glorious, though?
These will be your transports
for the afternoon.
No drivers?
No. No drivers.
They're electric.
They run on this track in the
middle of the roadway here.
Totally non-polluting. Top of the line.
Spared no expense.
It's an interactive CD-ROM!
You touch the right part of the screen
and it talks about whatever you want.
Lex, you're all right in there.
Dr. Sattler, come with me.
Dr. Grant, come in
the second car.
I'm gonna ride
with Dr. Sattler.
I read your book.
That's great.
Do you really think dinosaurs turned
into birds and that's where they went?
A few species may have
evolved along those lines.
Because they sure don't
look like birds to me.
I heard that there
was this meteor,
hit the earth someplace down in
Mexico, and made this big crater.
Listen...
Tim.
Tim, which car
were you planning on?
Whichever one you are.
Then I heard about this thing in Omni
about this meteor making all this heat.
It made diamond dust and
that changed the weather.
They died because
of the weather.
My teacher tells me about this book
by a guy named Bakker. He says...
She said I should ride with you
'cause it'd be good for you.
The boat is now loading.
Everyone must be on the dock
for the 1900 departure.
National Weather Service
is tracking a tropical storm
about 75 miles west of us.
Why didn't I build
in Orlando?
I'll keep an eye on it. Maybe it'll
swing south like the last one.
Ray, start the tour program.
Hold onto your butts.
And why did
they put the fiberglass thing?
I know.
You want to
join the future, right?
God help us when
the hands of engineers...
During your tour,
the appropriate
information will be
automatically selected
and displayed for you.
Look!
Touch the area of the screen
displaying the appropriate icon.
Are we gonna hit that?
Welcome to Jurassic Park.
What have they got
in there, King Kong?
The voice you're now
hearing is Richard Kiley.
We spared no expense.
If you look to the right,
you'll see a herd of the first dinosaurs
on our tour, called Dilophosaurus.
Dilophosaurus!
Shit!
One of the earliest
carnivores,
we now know Dilophosaurus
is actually poisonous
spitting its venom at its prey,
causing blindness and paralysis,
allowing the carnivore
to eat at its leisure.
This makes Dilophosaurus a
beautiful but deadly addition
to Jurassic Park.
Alan?
Where?
Damn.
Vehicle headlights are on
and not responding.
Those shouldn't be running
off of car batteries.
Item 151 on
today's glitch list.
We have all the problems of a
major theme park and a major zoo
and the computers aren't
even on their feet yet.
Dennis, our lives are in your
hands and you have butterfingers?
I am totally unappreciated
in my time.
You can run this park from this room
with minimal staff for up to three days.
You think that kind of
automation is easy? Or cheap?
You know anybody who can
network eight machines
and de-bug two million lines
of code on my salary?
If so, I want to see them.
Sorry about your financial
problems, I really am.
But they are your problems.
You're absolutely right.
Everything's my problem.
I will not be drawn into another
financial debate with you.
I really will not.
There's been hardly
any debate at all.
I don't blame people
for their mistakes.
But I do ask that
they pay for them.
Thanks, Dad.
The headlights.
I'll debug the tour program
when they get back, okay?
It'll eat a lot of
compute cycles.
We'll lose part
of the system.
There's a finite amount of memory,
you can't use it for everything.
Are you gonna compile
for a half an hour...
Quiet, all of you!
They're approaching
the Tyrannosaur paddock.
God creates dinosaurs.
God destroys dinosaurs.
God creates man. Man destroys God.
Man creates dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs eat man.
Woman inherits the earth.
We'll try
to tempt the Rex now.
Keep watching the fence.
What's going to happen
to the goat?
He's going to eat the goat?
Excellent.
What's the matter, kid?
You never had lamb chops?
I happen to be
a vegetarian.
T-Rex doesn't want to be fed.
He wants to hunt.
You can't just suppress 65
million years of gut instinct.
Eventually you do plan to have dinosaurs
on your dinosaur tour, right?
Hello. Yes?
I really hate that man.
The Tyrannosaur doesn't obey any
set patterns or park schedules.
The essence of chaos.
I'm still not
clear on chaos.
It simply deals with
unpredictability in complex systems.
The shorthand is
the Butterfly Effect.
A butterfly can flap
its wings in Peking
and in Central Park you get
rain instead of sunshine.
Was I going too fast?
I missed it.
I did a fly-by.
Give me that glass of water.
We'll conduct an experiment.
We should be still.
The car's bouncing.
That's okay.
It's just an example.
Put your hand flat
like a hieroglyphic.
A drop of water falls
on your hand.
Which way will the drop roll off?
Which finger?
Thumb, I'd say.
Freeze your hand.
Don't move.
I'll do the same thing, start
with the same place again.
Which way, now?
Let's say back
the same way.
It changed. Why?
Because tiny variations,
the orientation of the hairs
on your hands...
Alan, look at this.
...the amount of blood distending your
vessels, imperfections in the skin...
"imperfections in the skin"?
...just microscopic,
never repeat and vastly
affect the outcome.
That's what?
Unpredictability.
There. Look at this.
See? I'm right again.
Nobody could predict that Dr. Grant would
suddenly jump out of a moving vehicle.
And there's another example.
See, here I am now by
myself, talking to myself.
That's Chaos Theory.
Stop the program.
I told you, how many times, we needed
locking mechanisms on the vehicle doors.
Stopping park
vehicles and rebooting program.
We're on.
Will notify for resume.
I'll switch it
over to TelePrompTer.
What about
the circuit integrities?
Screen says faulty sensor.
I'll call security.
We're at full go
on that and it looks good.
Like I said, there's this other
book by a guy named Bakker
and he says dinosaurs
died from diseases.
Where are we going?
He didn't say
they turned into birds.
Anyone else think
we shouldn't be out here?
And his book was a lot fatter
than yours. Like this.
Really? Yours was
fully illustrated.
You Okay?
Look at this.
Wait. Watch.
Come on. Watch this.
Whoa.
Everybody stay here.
Wow.
Okay?
Of course.
Don't be scared.
Come on, it's okay.
Muldoon tranquillized her
for me.
She's sick.
Oh, my God.
Hey, baby.
She was always my favorite
when I was a kid
and now I see she's the most
beautiful thing I ever saw.
It's okay.
Microvesicles.
That's interesting.
Thanks.
What are her symptoms?
Imbalance, disorientation,
labored breathing.
It seems to happen
every six weeks or so.
Six weeks.
These are dilated.
They are?
Take a look.
I'll be damned.
That's pharmacological.
From local plant life.
Is this West Indian lilac?
Yes. We know they're toxic,
but the animals don't eat them.
Are you sure?
Pretty sure.
There's only one way
to be positive.
I'd have to see
the dinosaur's droppings.
Dino droppings?
Droppings?
Yeah, I got that.
That storm center hasn't
dissipated or changed course.
We're gonna have to
cut the tour short.
We'll pick it up
again tomorrow.
Are you sure we have to?
It's not worth
taking the chance.
Sustained winds at 45 knots.
Tell them when they get
back in the cars.
Ladies and gentlemen, last shuttle leaving
for the dock leaves in five minutes.
Drop what you're doing
and leave now.
Damn!
That is one
big pile of shit.
You're right. There's no
trace of lilac berries.
That's so odd, though.
All right, she's suffering
from Melia toxicity
every six weeks.
Let's see, rats.
She's tenacious.
You have no idea.
You will remember to wash your
hands before you eat anything?
Doctors, if you please, I have
to insist that we get moving.
I'd like to stay with Dr. Harding
and finish up with the Trike.
Sure. I'm in
a gas-powered jeep.
I'll drop her off at the
center before I make the boat.
Great. Then I'll catch
up with you later.
You sure?
Yeah, I want to stay
with her a little longer.
Okay, then.
There's nothing I can do. The captain
says we got to go, we got to go.
You've got to
give me the time.
I did a test run, it took me 20 minutes.
I think I can push it to 18
but you've got to give me
at least 15 minutes.
No promises.
Visitor vehicles are
returning to the garage.
So much for our first tour. Two
no-shows and one sick Triceratops.
It could've been worse.
A lot worse.
Anybody want a soda or something?
I'm going up to the machine.
I thought maybe
I'd get somebody something.
I've had only sweets and I'm
gonna get something salty.
I finished
debugging the phones.
I was going to, so I did.
So I debugged the phones.
And I thought maybe
I should tell you the system
will be compiling
for 18 to 20 minutes,
so some of the minor systems,
they might go on and off for a while,
but it's nothing to worry about.
DO you got any kids?
Me? Hell, yeah.
Three. I love kids.
Anything at all can
and does happen.
Same with wives,
for that matter.
You're married?
Occasionally.
I'm always on the lookout
for a future ex-Mrs. Malcolm.
Five, four, three,
two, one.
- That's odd.
- What?
Door security systems
are shutting down.
Nedry said a few systems
would go off-line, didn't he?
By the way, Dr. Sattler,
she's not available,
is she?
Why?
I'm sorry. You two are...
Yeah.
What'd I touch?
You didn't touch anything.
We stopped.
What the hell?
What now?
Fences are failing
all over the park.
Find Nedry. Check
the vending machines.
Just look at this
work station.
What a complete slob.
The Raptor fences
aren't out, are they?
No, no. They're still on.
Why the hell would he turn
the other ones off?
Access main program.
Access main security.
Access main program grid.
You didn't say
the magic word.
Please! God damn it.
I hate this hacker crap.
Phone Nedry's
people in Cambridge.
Phones are out, too.
Where did the vehicles stop?
Their radio's out, too.
Gennaro said to stay put.
Kids okay?
I didn't ask.
Why wouldn't they be?
Kids get scared.
What's scary?
It's just a little hiccup in the power.
I'm not scared.
I didn't say
you were scared.
I know.
Boo!
Hey, where did
you find those?
In the box,
under my seat.
Are they heavy?
Yeah. Then they're expensive.
Put them back.
Don't scare me.
Cool. Night vision.
Did you feel that?
Maybe it's the power
trying to come back on.
What is that?
Where's the goat?
Jesus!
He left us.
Where does he think
he's going?
When you got to go,
you got to go.
Dr. Grant.
I hate being
right all the time.
Keep absolutely still. its
vision is based on movement.
Turn the light off.
Turn the light off!
Hurry! Turn it off!
I'm sorry!
You're the one
who turned it...
Ian, freeze!
Get the kids!
Get rid of the flare!
Hail Mary,
full of grace...
No!
Dr. Grant!
I'm stuck.
The seat's got my feet.
I'll get you next.
You're okay.
You're all right.
Tim!
Don't move. He can't see
us if we don't move.
Lex, you're choking me.
Grab the wire.
"Keycheck space minus 0. Keychecks
off, safety space minus 0."
He's turning the safety systems off.
Doesn't want anybody to see.
Look at this next entry. It's the kicker.
"White rabbit object."
It did it all.
With the keychecks off,
the computer didn't
file the keystrokes.
The way to find them is to check the
computer's lines of code one by one.
How many lines of
code are there?
About two million.
Two million?
Yeah.
Robert, I wonder if perhaps you would
be good enough to take a gas jeep
and bring back
my grandchildren.
Sure.
I'm going with him.
John.
I can't get Jurassic Park back
online without Dennis Nedry.
Should have been
there by now.
Damn it!
There's the road!
Winch this sucker off the thing and
then I tie it to that thing there.
I'll pull down this thing here,
and pull it back up again.
My glasses. I can
afford more glasses!
You've got time. You can do it.
Do it. Come on, Dennis.
Hello.
Yeah, that's nice.
I've got to go.
Nice boy.
Nice dinosaur.
Thought you were one of your big brothers.
You're not so bad.
What do you want?
A little food?
Look at me.
I just fell down a hill.
I'm soaking wet. I don't have any food.
I have nothing on me.
Go on. Play fetch?
Look, stick.
Look at stick.
Stick, stupid. Fetch the stick, boy.
Look at the stick.
You like the stick?
Go on and get it.
No wonder you're extinct.
I'm gonna run you over
when I come back down.
Timmy!
Now, Lex. Listen.
Lex, I'm right here.
I'll look after you.
I have to help your brother.
Stay right here
and wait for me.
He left us.
But that's not what
I'm going to do.
Okay?
Stay here.
You hear me?
I'm coming up.
I hate climbing. I hate
trees, way too high.
You Okay?
I threw up.
That's okay.
Just give me your hand.
Tim, I won't tell anyone you threw up.
Here, I've got you.
Okay.
That's good.
Over the rail.
Don't pull me too hard.
Stand on the door.
Hang on to me.
That's not too bad, right, Timmy?
Yes, it is.
It's like a tree house.
Your dad ever build you one?
No.
Yeah, me, too.
The thing about climbing is,
you never look down.
This is impossible.
How am I going to do this?
It's about...
I'm going to help you
with your footing.
Oh, no.
Tim, go.
Go, Tim, go!
Faster, Tim!
Tim, jump!
Go, Tim.
We're back
in the car again.
At least
you're out of the tree.
Where's the other car?
Alan!
Dr. Grant!
I think this was Gennaro.
I think this was, too.
I think it's ahead of us.
It could be anywhere.
With fences down, it can wander in
and out of any paddock it likes.
He's put
a tourniquet on. Ian.
Remind me to thank John
for a lovely weekend.
Can we chance moving him?
Please chance it.
Ellie, come on!
It's the other car!
Dr. Grant?
They're not here.
Anybody hear that?
It's an impact tremor,
is what it is.
I'm fairly alarmed here.
Come on. We've got to get
out of here. Now! Right now!
Let's go.
Must go faster.
Here it comes!
Stand on it! Fifth gear!
Get off the stick!
Bloody move!
Look out!
Think they'll have
that on the tour?
Are you hearing this?
Come on, Tim.
Hurry up.
Let's get up this tree.
Come on, Tim, it's okay.
Listen. Try up here.
Oh, man.
I hate trees.
They don't bother me.
Yeah? Well, you weren't
in the last one.
Look at the Brontosauruses.
I mean, Brachiosaurus.
They're singing.
Don't let the monsters
come over here.
They're not monsters, they're animals.
These are herbivores.
They only eat vegetables. For you,
I think they'd make an exception.
I hate the other kind.
They just do what they do.
What's that?
What are you and Ellie going to do now,
if you don't dig up bones anymore?
I don't know.
I guess we'll just
have to evolve, too.
What do you call
a blind dinosaur?
"Do-you-think-he-saurus."
What do you call
a blind dinosaur's dog?
You got me.
A "Do-you-think
- he-saurus rex."
Alan?
Yeah?
What if the dinosaurs come
back while we're all asleep?
I'll stay awake.
All night?
All night.
They were all melting.
Malcolm's okay for now. I
gave him a shot of morphine.
They'll be fine.
Who better to get the children through
Jurassic Park than a dinosaur expert?
You know, the first
attraction I ever built when
I came down from Scotland
was a flea circus,
Petticoat Lane.
Really quite wonderful.
I had a wee trapeze
and a
carousel
and a seesaw.
They all move motorized,
of course.
People said they saw the fleas.
"I can see the fleas.
"Can't you see the fleas?"
Clown fleas, high-wire fleas,
and fleas on parade.
With this place,
I wanted to show them something
that wasn't an illusion.
Something that was real.
Something that they could
see and touch.
An aim not
devoid of merit.
But you can't think through this
one, John. You have to feel it.
You're absolutely right.
Hiring Nedry was a mistake,
that's obvious.
We're over-dependent on
automation, I can see that now.
Next time,
everything's correctable.
Creation is an act
of sheer will.
Next time,
it'll be flawless.
It's still the flea circus.
It's all an illusion.
When we have control...
You've never had control!
That's the illusion.
I was overwhelmed
by the power of this place.
I made a mistake, too.
I didn't have enough respect for
that power, and it's out now.
The only thing that matters
now are the people we love.
Alan and Lex and Tim.
John, they're out there,
where people are dying.
It's good.
Spared no expense.
Go away!
It's okay.
It's a Brachiosaurus.
It's a "Veggie-saurus", Lex.
"Veggie-saurus."
Veggie.
Come on. Come on, girl.
Come on, baby.
Go.
I'm not letting go.
It looks like
it has a cold.
Yeah. Maybe.
Can I touch it?
Sure.
Just think of it
as kind of a big cow.
I like cows.
Come on, girl.
Come on up here, girl.
God bless you.
Yuck.
Great.
Now she'll never
try anything new.
She'll sit in her room, never
come out, play on her computer.
I'm a hacker.
That's what I said.
You're a nerd.
I am not
a computer nerd.
I prefer to be
called a hacker.
God.
You know what this is?
It's a dinosaur egg.
The dinosaurs are breeding.
But my grandpa said all
the dinosaurs were girls.
Amphibian DNA.
What's that?
Well, on the tour,
the film said they used frog DNA
to fill in the gene-sequence gaps.
They mutated the dinosaur
genetic code
and blended it with
that of frogs.
Some West African frogs have been known
to change sex from male to female
in a single sex environment.
Malcolm was right.
Look.
Life found a way.
No. That's crazy.
You're out of your mind.
He's absolutely
out of his mind.
Wait. What exactly
would this mean?
We're talking about
a calculated risk,
which is the only
option left to us.
We'll never find the command Nedry used.
He's covered his tracks far too well.
I think it's obvious now
that he's not coming back.
So, shutting down
the entire system...
Get somebody else.
I won't do it.
Shutting down the system is the only
way to wipe out everything he did.
Now, as I understand it, all the
systems will then come back
on their original
start-up mode. Correct?
Theoretically, yes. We've never
shut down the entire system before.
It may not come back on.
Would we get
the phones back?
Yes, again, in theory.
What about
the lysine contingency?
We could put
that into effect.
What's that?
That's absolutely out
of the question.
The lysine contingency prevents
the spread of animals,
if they ever get
off the island.
Wu inserted a gene that creates a
faulty enzyme in protein metabolism.
The animals can't manufacture
the amino acid, lysine.
Unless they're supplied with lysine
by us, they slip into a coma and die.
People are dying.
Will you please shut
down the system?
Hold on to your butts.
It's okay.
Look, see that?
It's on. It worked.
What do you mean it worked?
Everything's off.
Shutdown tripped
the circuit breakers.
Turn them back on,
reboot a few systems:
telephones, security doors, half
dozen others, but it worked.
System's ready.
Where are the breakers?
Maintenance shed
at the end of the compound.
Three minutes, I'll have the
power back on in the park.
Just to be safe, I want everybody
in the emergency bunker
until Mr. Arnold returns, and the
whole system's running again.
I'm tired.
I'm dirty.
I'm hot.
Looking at the map, I'd say the
visitor's center is just a mile
over that rise there.
Just keep...
What is that?
Tim, can you tell me
what they are?
They are
Gallimimus.
Are those meat-eating?
"Meat-asauruses"?
Look at the wheeling.
Uniform direction changes.
Just like a flock of birds
evading a predator.
They're flocking this way.
I want to go now.
Just look how it eats.
Please.
I bet you'll never look at
birds the same way again.
Yes.
Go now.
Okay. Keep low
and follow me.
Look how much blood.
God. Something went wrong.
Something's happened.
Something's wrong.
This is just a delay.
That's all it is. All major
theme parks have delays.
When they opened Disneyland
in 1956, nothing worked.
If the Pirates of
the Caribbean breaks down,
the pirates don't
eat tourists.
I can't wait any more.
Somethings wrong.
I'm gonna go get
the power back on.
You can't just stroll
down the road, you know?
Don't be too hasty.
I mean, it's only been gone...
I'm going with you.
Okay.
Sorry.
Now, this isn't going to be just
like switching on the kitchen light.
But I think I can follow this
and then talk you through it.
Right.
But it ought to be me,
really, going.
Why?
I'm a... And you're a...
Look.
Come on, let's go.
We can discuss sexism in survival
situations when I get back.
You just take me through this
step by step. I'm on Channel 2.
Right.
The shutdown must've
turned off all the fences.
Damn it, even Nedry knew better
than to mess with the Raptor pen.
Come on, this way.
I can see the shed
from here.
We can make it if we run.
No. We can't.
Why not?
Because we're being hunted.
In the bushes,
straight ahead.
It's all right.
Like hell it is.
Run. Towards the shed.
I've got her.
Go. Now!
Mr. Arnold?
John, I'm in.
Great.
Ahead of you is a metal staircase.
Go down it.
Okay. Going down.
After 20 or 30 feet you come
to a T-junction. Take a left.
Have her follow
the main cable.
I know how to read
a schematic.
I guess that means
the power's off.
That's not funny.
That was great.
Well, maybe we, we could...
Damn it. Dead end.
Wait a minute.
There should have been a right
turn back there somewhere.
Look above you.
There should be a bundle of cable and
pipes all heading in the same direction.
Follow that.
Okay.
Following the piping.
I bet I could climb over to the other side
before you could even get to the top.
What would you give me?
Respect.
Come on, guys,
it's not a race.
I see the box.
It says, "High Voltage."
Yeah.
Okay.
Good. Here we go.
Over the top.
Take your time.
Good. Come on.
Find your footing.
You can't throw
the main switch by hand.
You've got to pump up the primer
handle in order to get the charge.
It's large, flat, and gray.
All right,
here I go. Okay?
One, two, three, four.
Okay, charged.
Under the words "Contact Position,"
there's a round green button
which says "Push to Close."
Push to close.
Push it.
The red buttons turn on
the individual park systems.
Switch them on.
Get down now!
You're gonna have to jump.
You crazy?
I'm not gonna jump.
Do what Dr. Grant says!
Let go.
I'll count to three.
One, two, three!
Four. Five.
I'm coming up to get you.
I've got to get Tim.
Okay. I'm gonna
count to three.
One.
Two...
He's not breathing.
I think we're back
in business!
No!
Mr. Arnold.
Clever girl.
No, Tim!
Good boy.
Three.
Hello?
Okay. I'm gonna have
to find the others.
Get you to a doctor.
Lex, you look after Tim.
Yeah.
Your hair is
all sticking up.
Big Tim, the human
piece of toast.
I'll be back soon.
I promise.
Run.
Just the two Raptors, right?
You sure the third
one's contained?
Yes, unless they figure out
how to open doors.
What is it?
It's a Velociraptor.
It's inside.
Follow me.
It's in there.
Control room.
We can
call for help?
We've got to reboot
the system first.
The door locks!
Ellie, boot up
the door locks!
No, boot up
Get back! Boot up
the door locks.
You can't hold it
by yourself!
It's a UNIX system.
I know this.
It's all the files
of the whole park.
It tells you everything. I've
got to find the right file.
Try to reach the gun.
I can't get it
unless I move.
This is it. This might
be the right file.
This isn't the right file.
Come on, Lex!
You got it!
Yes!
Did it!
What works?
All security systems
are enabled. We got it.
Grant.
Mr. Hammond,
the phones are working.
The children all right?
The children are fine.
Call the mainland. Tell them
to send the damn helicopters.
It's gonna cut
through the glass!
Move!
Tim, let go. Yeah!
After careful consideration, I've
decided not to endorse your park.
So have I.
Come on.