This is Jim Cameron.
I wrote and directed this film back in '83,
and directed it in '85 through '86.
It was released in the summer of '86.
July 1 7th, if l'm not mistaken.
It started as a treatment.
I was having a meeting with David Giler and
Walter Hill, talking about another project,
and that pitch was not going very well.
I could tell by their sagging expressions
that they didn't like any of my ideas.
But they had read my Terminator script
and wanted to work with me on something.
I was getting up
and making my way toward the door
and David Giler,
one of the producers of the first film,
said "We do have this other thing",
and I said "What's that?"
He said "Alien 2."
And all the pinball machine lights
and bells went off inside my head
but I maintained a straight face
and said "That could be interesting."
And I suggested that I write
a quick treatment, a quick outline,
just to give them an idea
of what I might do with it.
So I raced home and stayed up for three days
straight, drank about eight pots of coffee
and wrote a 40- or 50-page treatment.
Really what I did was I adapted a story I had
already written, which was called Mother,
which was an "alien on a space station"
kind of story.
It had the power loader machine in it.
I had written this treatment
a few months earlier.
So I adapted it, dropped Sigourney's
character and a bunch of marines into it,
and in that one quick stroke
created all the character names -
Gorman and Hicks and Vasquez
and all those folks -
and dropped it on them
a couple of days later.
I think they felt like they'd hit the jackpot.
That was the film they wanted to make.
So they authorized me to go ahead and start
writing the script. The problem was, that day
I landed the job to write the script
for the second Rambo film.
So I called them up
and asked David Giler what l should do.
And he said "Don't be stupid.
Take both jobs." So I took both jobs.
I also had to do a rewrite of my Terminator
script to start production in February,
so I had a three-month period
where I had to write three scripts.
So I decided that each script was gonna be
two hours long, so it'd be 120 pages.
So I figured out the total page count,
whatever that is - I guess 360 pages.
I divided the total number of waking hours
I had during that three-month period by 360
and figured out how many pages
per hour l had to write,
and then I just wrote
that many pages per hour.
I'm Gale Anne Hurd. I produced Aliens.
I'm Stan Winston. I created the creature
effects and the alien effects for Aliens.
(Hurd) I remember Jim trying to figure out
how he could make the beginning
of this movie impressive.
He said he wanted to use a robotic laser.
It was an afterthought
and it wasn't in the budget
and I remember having the gall to say to him
"If you wanna use it, you have to pay for it."
- And he did.
- (Winston) Is that right?
(Hurd) This robotic arm and the laser
came out of his pocket.
(Cameron) I wanted a seamless blend
from the end of the first film
into the beginning of the second film.
I certainly wanted to honor all the things
that were good about the first film.
So I went to school
on Ridley's style of photography,
which was quite different from mine,
cos he used a lot of long lenses, much
more so than I was used to working with.
But the smoke, the backlight, the textures,
the way he forces the frame
by putting a lot of equipment, machinery and
foreground pieces, I really studied all that.
I wanted there to be a
stylistic continuity.
I also wanted to have
my own style grafted onto that
so that I felt enough of a sense of
authorship to make it worth doing.
This is Robert Skotak. I was
the visual effects supervisor on the film.
My name is Dennis Skotak. l was supervising
director of photography on this project.
This is Pat McClung. I was the
model-shop supervisor on the film.
(Robert) They're wearing
modified costumes from Outland,
or the basic suit is from Outland and it's been
redesigned and they put some stencils on it.
This is microglitter
and fuller's earth blown on there.
(Hurd) I remember in this scene the batteries
in the flashlights kept going out.
You would think
this would be an easy scene to do,
but, as with everything in this movie,
it was harder than it looked.
(Winston) There are no
easy scenes with Jim.
(Robert) There's that nice dissolve,
the contour of the earth matching her face.
(Dennis) When we shot this, a matte painting
combined with miniature and perspective,
there are some perspective gags
going on there.
We used a clip of Sigourney's face
in the viewfinder
to line up the curvature of the earth,
so we had a nice match.
(Cameron) I wrote the piece obviously
with Sigourney in mind for the character.
I was told she was on board and I should
just toddle off and write the film
when in fact no deal
had been made with her whatsoever.
So here was a script that was written
that everybody wanted to make,
in which she was in every scene,
and they hadn't made a deal with her yet.
That's why she got her first big payday
of her acting career.
She got a million bucks,
which was a big deal.
She might have been the first actress to get a
million dollars for a movie in movie history.
It was all because it was mishandled
by the producers.
She was the main character
and they hadn't made the deal.
She was worth every penny of it and more.
When people saw the film, they realized that.
I knew what a phenomenal actress
she was.
I'd never met her. I had her picture up
while I was writing the script.
I went off the character that
had been created in the first film,
took her much further.
Of course, this is Paul Reiser.
I certainly had no idea what a great
comic actor he would prove to be,
and certainly that's how people think
of him, not as a dramatic actor.
I just read him in a lineup of actors
in the normal casting methodology,
and I thought he was really interesting,
that he could play this really sincere
but slightly smarmy guy
who could then turn evil.
This is a dream sequence,
but you don't know that yet.
I remember from
the premiere screening of the film
that the incomplete chestburster scene here
really got people cranked up and on edge,
set the tone for the whole movie,
that you were here to be messed with,
which is a good way to start off, l think.
The way you get a cat to hiss like that
is you put another cat close to it.
I had no idea. I didn't know
what you did to make a cat do that.
But that's standard procedure. Bring a cat it
doesn't know close to it and it'll do that.
This scene was shot really quickly.
It was pretty much all handheld,
48 or 60 frames a second. I think 48.
Then Sigourney had to loop all her lines
at slow speed, which is always odd.
(Winston) Our first effect in the movie.
It's great, because it's what you expected
to happen and then it's not what you expect.
She was actually under the bed
for that sequence.
We built an artificial body from her neck
down. Someone is under the bed with her.
I can't remember who the lucky guy was that
created the illusion of the chestburster.
- Pushing its way through her.
- It sets up the character.
This is her nightmare.
You know that she never wants
to have to face it in real life again
because she's haunted by it
in her dreams and her nightmares.
(Robert) This effect is
as if you're outdoors.
When the camera dollies over,
you see it's just a video projection.
The idea was that in outer space
there would be places you could go to get a
feeling you were in a natural environment.
So that plate behind her was shot
out in the garden at Pinewood Studios.
It was a VistaVision plate.
Originally, there was supposed to be a
birdhouse in the background in that garden,
and she would have Jones on her lap
and a bird would fly in
and Jones would jump up
and hit the screen
and that's how the audience would find out
that she wasn't actually on the earth.
This scene was cut
from the release version of the film,
which became the source
of some controversy with Sigourney.
She later said in print that she had based
her entire character on this scene,
and she was devastated
when it was removed.
At the time she first screened the film,
she told me she didn't like the scene,
and then we wound up reading interviews
where she had a big problem with that.
We didn't have a chance to talk about it
because of the postproduction schedule.
We were working in England,
kind of in isolation.
Even though I liked the symmetry of the fact
that she had had a daughter and lost her -
that's Sigourney's mother,
so there's an interesting inversion here.
She's looking at the face of her mother
but playing it as her daughter.
As an actor, it allowed her
to work the connection.
All my movies are love stories.
This one is about parental love,
protectiveness and a sense of duty,
and the ultimate sacrifice that a person
would make, given that sense of duty.
That was a nice touch.
That was Sigourney's idea.
(Hurd) This was one of
the seminal scenes in the movie
and was one of the ones
that had to be deleted and omitted
from the theatrical version
because of length.
We didn't have multiplexes,
and there were only so many showings
a day that you could have of a film,
and we had to get it
no more than two hours ten minutes
in order to get the maximum number
of screenings per day.
(Cameron) Peter Lamont came up with a simple
and austere look for our future sets.
I watched this film recently
and I was amazed at how little we see
of the conventional future world,
as opposed to the spacecraft interiors.
She's actually on Gateway Station here.
She hasn't returned all the way to earth.
She never sets foot on earth in the whole
series of films, which is interesting.
This is as close as she gets
until the end of the fourth movie,
where she's re-entering the atmosphere.
But this is earth
for all intents and purposes.
This is everyday life
circa a couple of hundred years from now.
And Peter came up
with a very spartan look.
It's not overworked at all,
which I think was quite clever.
We wanted to do it minimalist. We didn't
have her walking around corridors.
We didn't create a world
because we weren't interested.
We were interested
in the through-line of her story
and her character's
dilemma and problems,
the fact that she's not believed, that she
understands there's this great threat.
The same applied to the costumes.
We didn't wanna suggest a wildly
separated future from our present one.
This might be one of the first science fiction
movies where men still wear coats and ties.
The thinking was
people will still wear coats and ties.
They may not look exactly the same.
We turned up the collar on the jackets.
It's no big deal but it's a subtle change.
We wanted to have a place to go.
We wanted the space environment once
they get to the colony planet to be exotic
and so we didn't wanna overwork earth.
We also wanted to understand who these
people were, and a suit is a suit.
These characters are suits
and we wanted to reinforce that.
If everybody's in Star Wars type costumes,
it's harder to relate to them as characters.
I was thinking more of a writer
than a designer
when l was making my picks
of what things should look like
from amongst the suggestions
made by the costume designer.
(McClung) Denny, did they shoot
at 25 frames per second
for all the video playback stuff?
Do you remember?
(Dennis) They did.
The 24-frame issue was messy.
It can be done,
but it's such a big procedure.
Shooting 25 frames per second
on the camera
puts the video in sync
with the film camera very easily.
There's a slight speed differential
but it's almost impossible to perceive.
(McClung) In Britain they have
a different television system,
a 25-frame-per-second system.
(Robert) 625 resolution instead of 525.
(Dennis) Later in the film
there's some video footage that was used,
appearing on video monitors.
But the PAL system is better than NTSC,
which is our system here
in the United States.
It almost looked like a slightly too fuzzy
version of film, sort of in between.
It's not as good as it should be for film,
but it wasn't obvious it was video.
Jim realized and made
the video images noisier
or break up more often
so it was more obvious.
(Cameron) The tag of this scene
is gonna be a throw to this big sequence
that takes place on the colony
which is before the aliens attack.
That's cut out of the release version,
so coming up is the biggest single change
from the release version of the film.
It's an entire reel. I'll never forget Gale
Hurd, who was my wife and producer at the time,
trying to shorten the film by 20 minutes.
I just could not see how it was possible
to do a cut here, a cut there, a few seconds,
a bit of a scene, the tag of a scene maybe.
She said "I've been thinking
about this for days." I said "Go ahead."
She said "Reel three." Which starts here.
"You can take out reel three."
I immediately rejected that
as completely absurd.
Then I thought about it.
Reel three ends with Newt's scream
when her father
has the facehugger on his face.
It works flawlessly. It's a brilliant cut
and I have to credit Gale with that.
I had poured a lot of energy into the design
of these scenes and the alien derelict ship.
The problem for me
was that I couldn't imagine this film
without the cognitive tether
to the first film of the alien derelict,
but it turns out that it works perfectly.
A little dialogue bridge and it works fine.
I like this tractor a lot, this tractor
with this articulated leg design.
(Dennis) This is one of my favorite
effects. You see the big tractor driving by
and in the background you see these people
struggling to put a tarp over that tractor.
That was done in perspective.
There were full-size people back there,
and a miniature in the foreground
with distance between.
It put everything in camera all at one time
without any opticals or anything beyond that.
The trick was that the actors had to act
at double their normal speed of acting,
because the camera
was running at 48 frames per second.
(Robert) We had a Ritter fan on them
to really kick those tarps around
in excess of what it would be in real time,
but because we were overcranking,
that motion would then look normal.
(McClung) The multi-wheeled vehicle at the
beginning is a fifth-scale miniature,
radio-controlled, that Jim designed.
On the airplane coming over from
Los Angeles to London he just doodled it.
Ron Cobb, I believe, fleshed it out.
(Cameron) I always liked these guys.
I always liked this
"I'm just trying to do my job.
I'm a working stiff in a situation."
"The guys back home never know
what we're going through."
We wanted the idea
that there were kids around,
that the colonists had come
with their families.
This is a connection to the first film.
The Weyland-Yutani Corporation
was the big, bad, evil company
that was responsible for everything
that went wrong in the first movie.
So we just carried that tradition on.
Ultimately, l think
that what this scene shows
is that at that time I was not
- maybe never -
as good as Ridley Scott
at what he does best.
The suspense and the creation
of the atmosphere of this planet
is done so much better by him in his film,
and so, in a way, the removal of this scene
makes the picture stronger
because it puts it more on its own turf.
We tried to recreate the alien ship but I don't
think we were quite as successful as he was.
In his film it was a major set piece.
In ours it was just a stop along the way.
(Dennis) This derelict ship
had been in Bob Burns' driveway.
He'd been given it by Fox
and it was starting to fall apart.
We had to put it back together
and fix it up.
Fortunately, though, it existed,
so it saved us a lot of model work
because it was there and mostly intact,
rather than building from scratch.
My name's Carrie Henn and I was Newt.
My name's Chris Henn
and I was Tim Jordan.
(Carrie) It's cool to see
what James Cameron had in mind,
cos at the time
we didn't really know what was going on.
Little did we know at this time
that our life would change
when they came back from inside.
(Chris) That was the first time
we saw the facehugger,
when we opened the door and we saw it
on Jay's - who played our dad - neck.
(Carrie) I was really sad for my brother
that this got cut out,
and for everyone watching it,
because it shows everyone why I can't
stand the aliens, pretty obvious anyway,
but you find out that my dad was the one
who brought it back to the colony.
(Chris) It shows how Sigourney and Newt get
the connection, too, as mother-daughter,
and they have the same enemy.
(Carrie) This was interesting,
cos it wasn't something we saw filmed.
When it happened, they just got
out of the car and that was it.
(Chris) It ties it to the first one. It's the
same place they went in the first movie.
(Winston) We have another one
of our first creature effects
that is like the introduction
of the facehugger.
All of these things were so daunting
to me psychologically,
because these had now
become iconic characters,
the facehugger and the chestburster
and the warrior aliens.
Of course, the queen was brand-new,
but we also wanted each of these
to have their own life in this movie
and at the same time
be legitimate to the original.
So, to the very discerning eye, if you look at
the facehugger from the original, from Alien,
and you look at the facehugger in Aliens,
there are subtle differences in the detail,
more attention to detail
as far as the creature itself.
- (Carrie) That was genuine scare.
- (Chris) That freaked us both out.
(Carrie) This is where James Cameron
asked me to scream for the first time ever
and I screamed
and everyone stopped and stared.
(Cameron) Could shatter glass
with her scream.
I always liked that sound cut. We spent
a lot of time on the sound on this picture.
The picture was mixed by Graham Hartstone
at Pinewood Studios in England.
I remember mixing it for a long time,
I think seven weeks.
There's some really nice sound work
and I learned a lot.
My only prior experience with a mix was on
Terminator and that was done really rapidly.
I'm thinking it was done
in four or five days.
Not a sophisticated mix
and I knew nothing about it,
so I learned an awful lot
from Graham and the Pinewood mixers.
This is Bill Hope. He's a Canadian actor,
working in England at the time.
So, again, here you see her whole world
is created by a pretty simple little set
of a corridor and her little
efficiency apartment on the space station.
It's not specifically stated,
but she's never made it back to earth.
She's stayed on Gateway Station and got
a job as a dock worker, machine operator.
(Winston) Foreshadowing.
"Running loaders and forklifts."
What does that mean?
- (Hurd) I guess we'll see if we watch.
- This is exciting.
(Cameron) I think the intention was that...
I am a child of the '60s,
and the prevailing myth at that time
was that the Vietnam War was all about
protecting American business interests in
Asia. We wanted the evil corporation here.
The idea is that the corporation
has the contract
to establish colonies much in the sense
that the Dutch East India Company
might have controlled
that whole area of the world
and that colonial marines
don't work directly for them
but are called in as a security force
whenever the interests of the parent country,
wherever Weyland-Yutani is,
although it's probably a multinational.
Your model for that is colonial America,
or the Caribbean,
where the military were sent
as security for the corporations
who were bringing back the wealth
to the parent European countries.
So it's probably
a very entangled relationship.
The marines don't report to the company.
You can see there is
a separate chain of command.
They don't take orders from Burke, but Burke
makes very strong recommendations to them.
So they definitely have a lot of clout.
At the time I made the movie, I knew
diddly-dick about how big corporations work,
so to me they were just
this big, shadowy entity.
I know an awful lot more about it now.
And I actually nailed it,
I think, pretty close.
I think that if you look at places
of major corporate culpability,
like, say, the Bhopal disaster in India,
where 3,000 people were killed
because a major international corporation
cut corners on safety...
There's many instances throughout history
where, just by negligence,
corporations have been responsible
for many, many deaths,
but always in distant, remote places.
So if it's gonna happen,
it's gonna happen on a colony.
Obviously, this is the heart and soul of the
movie, which is Ripley's internal demon.
I think Sigourney's just great
in these scenes.
Interestingly, Sigourney herself
had an issue with my take on her character.
She didn't think that Ripley
hated the alien.
We had a long creative dialogue
and I said "No, she hates him."
She hates the alien
that killed her crew members
and put her through the most traumatic event
of her life, and wants to see them destroyed.
But I think the way I finally sold it to her
was - because Sigourney's very liberal -
that Ripley would want to prevent the trauma
she went through happening to anybody else,
and she knows
there are colonists on that planet.
So I displaced it outside of her,
when in reality I saw it
as a very straightforward revenge story.
But I think that was beneficial, because
that creative tug of war between us
actually caused me to think outside
of my limited box as a writer at that time,
and see that her motivation
was on a higher plane as well,
she was acting out of a sense of duty.
That spoke to some of the themes
I already had in the story
with respect to her relationship
with Newt.
Once she finds out that the colony is lost
and that battle is lost,
she really only has one thing to fight for,
and that's the little
girl, the one survivor.
Her mission has been to help these people
avoid what happened to her and her crew.
(Robert) The Sulaco. This was a Syd Mead
design that was fiberglass body.
Some of the detailing
was based on that Syd Mead sketch
and then Pat and Dennis and myself
did a lot of the fine detailing
for the front, the side, the top,
all the microscopic detailing.
This was not a particularly large model.
It was about five or six feet long.
The detailing we would do after hours
because we had to be on the stage to shoot
all this stuff, get everything organized,
and once everybody went home,
we'd go up to our little effects office
and start another shift of microdetailing.
It was so cold,
we were wearing our winter coats.
It was hard to move around
and use these tiny little Exacto knives,
and these pieces of plastic that were maybe
half the size of a comma on a textbook,
sticking them on meticulously,
one after the other.
(Cameron) So this was our biggest set,
I guess.
Or the biggest volume, I guess.
The hanging chains,
these little widgets and things,
this was all inspired by the tone and feel
of the opening scenes of Ridley's film.
We were trying to create that same sense
of the ship having its own life
and being an eerie, interesting place.
We had a big budget cut, or we had to save
money, and the budget for this set got cut.
Peter Lamont came up with a great idea.
There's a mirror at the end of the set
and another mirror behind the camera.
I think we only had three
of those hypersleep capsules.
I think we might have had four. We mirrored
them out to make them into 1 2.
If you're clever you can see where
the mirror is but I can't see it right now.
You can see there's two Vasquezes.
(Winston) Another wonderful thing
about Jim and a Jim Cameron film
is this wonderful loyalty that he has
with people who have worked with him,
actors that have worked with him.
(Hurd) Carpenters. Bill Paxton was
a carpenter on Battle Beyond the Stars
and then one of the punks who loses his
clothes to Schwarzenegger in Terminator.
- Lance was going to be the Terminator.
- (Hurd) And then became the detective.
And Michael Biehn, of course.
Kyle Reese.
My name is Michael Biehn.
I played Hicks,
or if you've seen the DVD extended version,
that's Dwayne Hicks.
I'm Lance Henriksen. I played Bishop.
I'm Jenette Goldstein.
I played Private Vasquez.
And I'm Bill Paxton
and I played Private Hudson.
I just wanna say,
it's great to see you guys.
It's fun to get together every 20 years
and look at movies we were in.
- (Biehn) I'm sure they'll put that on the...
- (laughter)
(Paxton) Seriously,
great camaraderie making this film.
- (Biehn) Look at Ricco.
- (Goldstein) He's putting you all to shame.
(Paxton) I gave up early on trying
to have a physique against you guys.
That would have cut into my drinking time.
(laughter)
- I was doing those.
- Were you standing on a box?
- No. I'll say this once and for all.
- (Henriksen) Look at that.
(Biehn) Spunkmeyer.
(Paxton) "In the pipe. Five by five."
I always liked the way she said that.
(Goldstein) Actually,
those are the hard ones.
(Biehn) What did Mark have on there?
- I don't remember him wearing all those...
- (Paxton) Scars and bones.
(Goldstein) I think Jim had put
the chin-up bar up there
to make the line "Anyone ever mistaken you
for a man?" work, cos in the T-shirt
no one would have mistaken me for a man.
He said "How can we make this line work?"
So he said "Can you do
behind-the-neck chins?" I said "Yeah."
(Biehn) Is this the scene
where you guys do the thing with the knife?
I remember saying at the time
"Jim, what about...?" "Shut up, Michael."
Why did he put your hand on top of his?
(Henriksen) What happened was that Jim had
wanted me to do it like a demonstration.
And we got right to the moment and I said
"Jim, this is really gonna be boring."
I said "What if l put my hand
on Billy's hand?"
And since I won't hurt anybody,
I would never hurt him,
it would make it more interesting.
(Biehn) I never understood what Bill was so
scared of, because his hand was underneath.
(Henriksen) After the movie was done, we all
went out and partied and drank a lot of beer,
and I remember a voice
in the middle of the night saying
"You gotta come back because when
they sped up the film it looked phony."
Remember? We had to come back.
And that's when I caught
your pinky by accident.
Just barely touched it and he almost died.
(Paxton) I had to have
reconstructive cuticle surgery.
(Henriksen) But, anyway,
it was more interesting on his hand.
(Winston) This effect was one of the first
uses of this camera with a variable speed.
- (Hurd) Magic Cam?
- Yeah.
Which is used a lot now,
but it was a first here.
(Hurd) What's great about it is that
you could start out at 24 frames per second
and then the camera, without having to cut
and set up a separate camera,
would automatically adjust for a faster
or slower frame rate and then go back.
(Winston) Change the aperture
while it was changing its speed.
(Hurd) Do you remember
Lance brought over his knives?
(Winston) No.
(Hurd) I met Lance Henriksen at the airport
when he was coming over from the US.
They have much stricter
weapons laws in England.
He'd packed the knives that he'd been
practicing that effect with in his suitcase.
He said "I'm always the one
that they check to do the luggage search."
Going through customs
he said "Stick with me."
It was the first time
he hadn't had his luggage searched.
I thought "That's great. An actor
coming over here with concealed weapons."
(Cameron) Bishop, if you watch
the film again knowing the outcome,
he plays it completely innocent.
He plays it as this very helpful,
compassionate guy,
but he looks so sinister,
and you know enough about these synthetics from
the first film that you never believe him.
And the interesting thing is
he is playing it on the square
the entire way through the film.
So this starts off with a miniature
and pans off onto the full-size.
There's a foreground set piece
on the left that's a miniature.
It's another Skotak shot.
A forced-perspective shot.
I knew nothing about
the US Marine Corps at the time.
Although, while I was making this film,
my brother joined the marines
and was in for six years.
I now know a lot more about the marines and
they are more disciplined than these people.
I would like to apologize to any marines
listening that we did not get that part right.
These guys are definitely
Vietnam-era regular army,
toward the end of their tour kind of motif.
The film is obviously informed
by imagery from Vietnam,
the idea that they put painted flowers
on their helmets and things like that,
and there was a real discipline problem.
That was also amongst
a lot of draftees at that time.
So we're mixing our metaphors
a little bit here.
- (Biehn) Do you chew gum in every scene?
- (Paxton) I tried to.
If you watch my performance,
I'm always doing something.
It's all I could do in those days.
Everybody's archetypical in this thing.
(Biehn) I don't remember all the stuff
hanging off of Mark. Chicken bones.
- (Goldstein) I look like a boy.
- (Biehn) That's what we liked about you.
(Paxton) Was this the day, Michael,
you were passed out by the lockers
and Sigourney walked by
and said "There's my leading man"?
Am I mistaken with another day?
(Biehn) Somewhere around in here.
- (Henriksen) I had to audition.
- (Biehn) They made you audition for Fox.
(Henriksen) No, it wasn't for Fox.
They had a limit on how many Americans
they could bring over.
So they auditioned
a lot of Englishmen for that role.
(Hurd) The casting director,
Mary Selway, and l had to meet
every member of the North American
registry from British Actors' Equity
who was interested in being in this film
before we could bring anyone from the US.
I think we must have met
and auditioned 3,000 people.
(Cameron) I encouraged the actors to
customize their own costumes and armor,
to give the impression they had been
out a lot, that they were seasoned,
that they had been away
from command authority on their own a lot
and were good enough at their jobs that
they were allowed these kind of latitudes.
This is a continuation
of the motif from the first film,
where they're wearing Hawaiian shirts
and all kinds of strange stuff,
all of which was a new idea
in science fiction.
People always wore uniforms on spaceships.
That's how it worked from Star Trek on.
Every science fiction film ever made,
there was the general-issue uniform.
Alien broke that mold
and it just seemed so right to people.
They recognized the archetype instantly.
"Oh, these guys are truck drivers."
"They dress however they want.
There's nobody to tell them not to."
And so the idea here
was extrapolated to a military unit
that's worked at the extreme fringes
of human civilization.
The power loader was not designed
by anybody in drawings per se.
I had done some preliminary drawings,
but it evolved basically from trying
to figure out how to make it work.
We built full-size mock-ups
of the arms and legs in foam core.
There's a guy inside that thing,
a big, strong English stunt man moving it.
It's supported by cables.
It's completely an on-set gag.
The English visual effects guys thought
we were crazy the way we wanted to do it.
I said "It's the gag where the dad
lets the daughter walk on his feet,
his three-year-old."
So standing behind Sigourney right now
is this big 270-pound
body-building English stunt man.
He's raising the arms himself
and he has in his hands
a control that allows him
to raise the forearm of the power loader.
And then when they walk,
they have to walk together.
The weight of the machine
is held by a crane which is off-camera,
or some kind of overhead track rig -
we had two versions of it.
If we didn't need the machine to turn,
we mounted it on a pylon, a boom-arm thing,
and if we needed it to pivot
we hung it on wires.
(Winston) My kids remember all the dialogue
and one thing they did was "Bay 1 2, please."
And Newt's line:
"They're dead, all right? Can I go now?"
(Hurd) How about
"Get away from her, you bitch"?
(Winston) The most classic
line in the movie.
(Hurd) And obviously this was
another interesting idea that Jim had,
which was to use a Steadicam harness
that's normally used for holding a camera
to make a futuristic weapon out of.
Everyone said it couldn't be done, which is
at least at the beginning of Jim's career
typical of the response to Jim's ideas,
and then, of course, it worked beautifully.
(Winston) These were aircraft vehicles.
(Hurd) They were the tow vehicles
that were used to bring jumbo jets, 747s,
to tow them in to the Jetways
at Heathrow Airport.
And then the skin was fabricated
by metalworkers locally in Slough, England,
which is near Pinewood Studios.
(McClung) The basic framework
was an airport tug,
a vehicle that had four-wheel steering.
It weighed I don't know how many tons,
so they had to strip the body off
and strip a number of tons.
(Dennis) I think it was 72 tons.
It wound up being 28 tons when it was done.
(McClung) The whole thing
was full of mechanisms.
When they open the door, there's nothing
inside. Now we cut to an interior set piece.
(Robert) This interior is a cheat
because it's larger on the inside.
This amount of set wouldn't
have fit inside there,
but it's a movie cheat that works well.
(Hurd) Do you remember
when the ceiling of this collapsed?
I'm not sure if it was this scene
or one of the scenes later on,
but there was so much set dressing
hanging from the roof of the APC set
that at one point it collapsed.
- (Biehn) Look at Bill.
- (Paxton) This was my big speech.
- My big speech.
- (laughter)
(Paxton) God, I stayed up late
trying to learn this thing.
- (Biehn) You used to work hard, Bill.
- (Paxton) I worked so hard.
I killed myself to make it work.
I guess it has to do with Jim
and my relationship with Jim.
- (Goldstein) Your work ethic.
- That too.
But with Jim, it's peaked. You want it
right for him because he's a perfectionist
and you see how hard he's working.
(Cameron) These are all miniatures
built by Bob and Denny Skotak.
Fairly large miniatures.
When we shot this scene, Bill said "We're
on an express elevator to hell going down"
and the grips shook the set and the set
collapsed on us and split open my scalp.
So I'll always remember that line.
(Biehn) It caught fire and the roof came in
all on the same day.
(Paxton) And it hit Jim in the head.
I saw blood spurting out of his head.
It was where Sigourney was supposed to be
sitting, so it was good it hit Jim and not her.
- We'd have gotten a day off.
- (Henriksen) Think they did that on purpose?
- No.
- I'm just asking.
(laughter)
(Goldstein) At that point,
maybe they would've.
(Paxton) "In the pipe. Five by five."
My favorite line.
(Cameron) These shots, it's just me shaking
the back of the magazine of the camera.
The poor camera operator
had a bruise around his eye,
cos sometimes I'd whack the magazine too,
just to give it a sharp jolt.
This is all my shake of the camera.
The operator can't do it himself.
It just gets into this bouncy rhythm
if the operator tries to do it.
It has to be imposed from the outside and then
they fight it, which is the natural reflex.
(Winston) Such a wonderful sound design
in this movie.
(Hurd) Much of which was generated
in our living room in England.
At the time, people really
weren't using synthesizers in England
to create sound effects for films, and we had
a Fairlight synthesizer in our living room.
A lot of the sound effects were generated
by Bob Garret, Randy Frakes and Jim
in our living room near Pinewood,
including the sound of the alien queen.
It really was a home movie.
(Cameron) The dropship evolved
in its design as it went along.
I came in on a Sunday during preproduction
and bashed a kit together out of a bunch
of model parts and pieces of foam core,
and spray-painted it gray
and gave it to Ron Cobb to draw up.
We had brought Ron Cobb to England
to help with some of the designs.
So Ron packaged it, as he called it. He
made it look better. This is a good scene.
One theme of the film
is that these soldiers
succumb to a technologically inferior enemy
that they don't know how to fight,
which is really a Vietnam metaphor,
where US forces got their butts kicked
by barefoot guys running through the jungle
because they didn't understand how to fight
that war, they didn't understand their enemy.
So Hudson's bragging scene here
plays into that.
They're cocky. They think they can handle
anything because they've got the fire power.
(Winston) Bill was so wonderful in this,
such a memorable character.
(Hurd) And when you think
about all of this exposition
that's being delivered
in a really entertaining way.
All of this military jargon.
Because the characters are so distinctive.
They don't just go right past you.
(Cameron) We were trying to go for
a transformer effect here,
where it deploys these weapons pods.
More handheld rear projection
to put you there.
What I had noticed from a lot of science
fiction films, even the first Alien,
was that you've got all this handheld,
claustrophobic stuff
and then you cut to the window shots and
they're just these static cutout mattes,
and it violates the flow.
So we wanted to have
continuity across those cuts,
so we decided to do all the views out
the windows as rear-projection handheld.
This is just
a regular Handycam, a regular 8 Handycam,
whatever the standard was at that time.
(Robert) This landing
of the dropship was complicated
in terms of trying to hit a mark
while shooting at high speed.
The dropship was shot overcranked,
so the model had to be really moving fast
and those landing legs were fairly frail.
We would do take after take
and the landing legs would get crushed.
(Cameron) This film is
not a wide-screen film.
If I did it again, I'd shoot it wide-screen
to be consistent with the first picture.
But I didn't like anamorphic
for the visual effects problems it created.
I'd had a bad experience
on Escape From New York
trying to do anamorphic visual effects,
so we decided to shoot 1 .85.
I almost shot the film in Super 35,
but I got talked out of it by somebody
that didn't understand that format,
and then I wound up shooting
all my subsequent films in Super 35.
I still don't care for anamorphic.
You have problems with lenses shooting
miniatures, with depth of field,
there are problems in composite.
On Escape From New York
we didn't have much money
and we were inexperienced
in anamorphic,
so I didn't really have an alternative
that I considered viable at the time.
But now when I see the two pictures
back-to-back screened -
it doesn't make
too much difference on video -
I actually like the look of Alien better
because I just like the aspect ratio.
And I've come to know and love
the 2.35:1 aspect ratio.
The interesting thing
is that the first film was anamorphic
so it used more of the negative area.
This is a 1 .85 picture.
In this exact year Kodak was in transition.
They were changing their emulsions.
This was a higher-speed negative
than had been used previously.
They hadn't worked out
their T-grain emulsion.
So it turned out grainier than I wanted.
But this was actually the standard,
just what that stock was that year.
Because we weren't using the full negative,
like with an anamorphic film,
we weren't getting
quite as much image quality.
If I had shot Super 35, it would have
looked terrible because of the graininess.
By the time I got ready to do The Abyss
a couple of years later,
they had improved the emulsions enough
that Super 35 looked pretty great.
I was surprised recently
at how grainy it was.
Nobody noticed the grain at the time
cos most films frankly looked like that.
(Biehn) Bill, isn't there dialogue
that you have on this
that people have used in video games?
(Paxton) Yeah, I think so.
"Game over, man" and things like that.
- You get anything for that?
- I don't think so.
I'm not even getting anything to sit here
and do this commentary.
They expect us to do it for no money.
(Henriksen) You got a beer out of it,
though.
(Paxton) No, it's just fun.
I got a beer out of it, so that's cool.
This was an amazing set, this concourse A.
And it was long.
And later on when all hell's breaking
loose, Jim had that little video camera.
He had everybody on the crew
having coffee
while we would run at him
and do different things.
It was so amazing to see this gigantic set,
one of the biggest sets I'd ever seen,
and there's Jim by himself
with this little camera.
(Henriksen) When did the bust-out almost
happen? He was gonna move the movie.
When did that happen?
(Paxton) I remember
there were some problems.
There were some union problems. The crew
weren't used to working the same way.
- (Biehn) With Jim.
- (Goldstein) They weren't used to working.
(Paxton) That's unfair.
They were craftsmen,
but they had an indentured way
of doing everything.
Jim needs something, he just grabs it. If he
needs a light moved, he'll grab it himself.
We punched a hole through somewhere
cos he needed to run a line.
He didn't wanna wait around.
He just said "Give me a hammer."
But this was an ambitious schedule.
Jim was running from stage to stage.
I think we had about three
big sound stages with giant sets.
And then there were two
sound stages with miniatures.
And then there was a stage
with all those tunnels.
I remember them putting you
in that damn tunnel.
(Henriksen) That pipe.
(Cameron) We had gone to the power station
to shoot the atmosphere-processor scenes
and come back to the set
after it had been wrecked.
So we're into Adrian Biddle's
photography here. He was the second DP.
I encouraged Adrian, to save time, to use
as much built-in lighting as possible.
This is lit by the fluorescents in the set,
with just a little additional lighting.
Adrian liked to work on a raw and edgy look and
work with the practical lights a lot more.
(Hurd) This is another thing
that is important.
With a lot of science fiction movies
that are all interior,
you often lose track geographically of where
you are and it becomes incredibly confusing
and it's hard to build
the tension and the suspense.
Jim was aware of this from the script stage
and made sure that we established
through the helmet cams, through the
motion trackers, where they are,
and then ultimately, later on,
where the aliens are.
(Cameron) Even in this version,
you're left to fill in what happened.
We don't see the battle.
We'll see plenty of battles later
and this is promising you that.
(Robert) We have a shot coming up here
where there were acid holes -
acid... holes...
eaten into the floor
by these so far unseen aliens.
And, of course, these sets
were not double-deck sets.
Jim wanted a scene where a character
looks down through one of these holes.
I think Bill spits down into it
to give some perspective.
So this down-view
we shot on our miniature stage.
We layered the set
and photographed that.
(Henriksen) This is where you spit
and they did it in miniature.
- They even did a miniature spit.
- (Goldstein) Is that what that is?
(McClung) To get that spitting effect,
it was actually not spit.
It didn't work very well,
so it was a combination of milk...
(Robert) Milk and water in an eyedropper
right underneath the lens.
(Cameron) The complaint
from the studio was that
the film went on too long
without anything really happening.
I was winding
the suspense tighter
before you actually saw anything.
The studio said we were just jerking
around. Too many movies that I see now,
it's all upfront. You start seeing stuff
right away and there's no sense of a build.
So this is the miniature APC
that was built by Bob and Denny Skotak.
Pretty good size.
I remember it being five or six feet long.
Most people don't twig that as a miniature.
That's the real APC pulling in.
They matched the lighting pretty nicely.
(Dennis) I think Jim did
some of his live-action stuff undercranked.
He ran the camera slightly slower
on the APC
so that it felt slightly more
as if it were a miniature
but you knew it was real because
you could see people interacting with it.
So if any of the miniature stuff
didn't quite work for whatever reason,
it took the curse off that cos it felt
that the two were blended together.
(Robert) I think he wound up undercranking
because the APC, the full-size one,
didn't move as fast as he wanted it.
(Dennis) I think it could only go
eight or ten miles an hour.
(Hurd) One difficult thing about making this
movie was Terminatorwasn't out in England
and the perception of Jim Cameron, who
looked about 20 when he directed this movie,
and myself as the directing-producing team
was met with a great deal of resistance
because back then the system in England
was that you had to put in years and years
to rise up to the level
of being a producer or a director.
And we were simply not treated
with a great deal of respect
and it was very hard
every day of the shoot.
We were being second-guessed
and every decision we made was questioned
and the tremendous thing, of course,
having Stan on the film was that...
- (Winston) I was old.
- No.
..was that you were
a cheerleader for both of us.
By demonstrating the respect
and enthusiasm that you did,
I think other people gradually relented.
(Winston) I knew it was the best thing
for me and for everybody on that set.
There are people that you know, no matter how
they do it, what they're doing is special.
This particular directing-producing team
had been a win for me in my career
and stayed that way.
(Cameron) I never thought our facehuggers
looked as good as the one in Alien.
We had to make lots of 'em
and they had to run around and do things,
but, texturally,
the one in the first film looked great.
It really held up. The bits of oysters
and stuff inside it looked great.
But I did wanna see the disgusting thing
that had been down the inside
of Kane's throat in the first film.
You never see it in the movie, in Alien,
so I figured we'd gross everybody out.
All of Giger's designs
have a real sexual undercurrent to them.
And that's what horrified people
about the alien as much as anything,
is it worked on a kind of
Freudian subconscious level.
And Ridley and Giger knew that
and they went for that.
This film was never intended to be
as much of a horror film as the first one.
It was working on
a different thematic level
but I still wanted to be true to some of
those ideas, some of those design concepts.
It would be natural to assume
I'd wanna work with Giger,
but it just didn't occur to me at the time.
Maybe it was because we really only needed
to design one new creature
and I had already designed her by the time
I wrote the script. The alien queen.
I guess maybe
it was my own ego as an artist.
I just felt like he'd made his stamp
and I knew from what I'd read
that he had to do everything his way
and I had a very specific idea
for the alien queen
to extrapolate beyond
what had been done before.
I got the impression from what l read
that I wasn't gonna get
the dynamic character that I wanted.
In a funny way, part of what
attracted me to doing this film
was the opportunity to do
cool design stuff.
So maybe I was just a little bit
too in love with the idea
of designing the creatures and the weapons
and doing all that stuff.
(Dennis) These shoulder-mounted lights
were not practical.
They'd go through batteries quickly and they're
delicate, but they served the purpose.
I assume at this point in the future
they'd work more efficiently.
(Hurd) When we were crewing up,
the department heads would meet with me
before they met with Jim.
It was a two-tier process.
A number of them came in and said
"Who's really producing this movie?"
And I'd say "I am." And they'd say
"No, you're the director's wife."
"You get the credit
but who's producing the movie?"
It was really difficult for me
to maintain a sense of calm.
(Winston) I never worked
with a better producer.
And a great directing-producing team.
Cos you're one of the few people
that actually stands up and talks to Jim.
There's an intimidation factor there.
I feel fortunate that I had
that relationship with him and you
for the films we've done together
but I've never worked
with a more diligent and intelligent
and, unfortunately,
tough producer as you.
- Thank you.
- Beat me down financially, I tell you.
"This is what we need."
"This is what you got, dude."
(Hurd) Carrie Henn, who plays Newt,
was an astonishing find.
Mary Selway, our casting director,
and her associate, Sarah Jackson,
searched throughout England and, in
fact, I think the entire British Isles,
trying to find a young girl
who could portray this character.
And we had every young girl
who wanted to be an actress,
or whose parents wanted them to act,
to come in and audition.
Almost all of them
had done commercials,
and every time
they delivered a line they would smile.
Of course, this is a little girl
suffering from traumatic stress.
She's watched her family wiped out,
every other person on
the mining colony wiped out,
and I think we probably had
500 little girls on tape.
And Carrie was found
at a US Air Force base in England.
Her father was a US serviceman
serving there.
And she came in and auditioned,
never having acted even in a school play,
and was dead on
from the very first reading.
(Winston) She's such a good little actress.
Has she done anything since this?
(Hurd) She has a normal life.
She did not pursue acting as her career.
One of the things
that we were very concerned about
was whether or not this film
would traumatize her.
It's very intense and unlike now, where
we could composite creatures in seamlessly,
or create one digitally,
she really was terrorized
by the alien warriors in the film,
and she understood it was make-believe.
Her parents were tremendously supportive
and she really had her feet on the ground.
This really is acting.
(Cameron) Carrie had never been
on a movie before,
but she started to enjoy it
and liked working with everybody.
It was a big adventure.
She started to become an actor.
She understood her character.
There was one day when she was sick
and they didn't want her to work.
She was devastated that
we were gonna do the scene with a double.
She pitched such a fit
that she came back.
I wound up doing one little shot with her
so she'd feel better, so she could go home.
I worked with her a lot. I'd give her
eye lines. I'd make a mark on the wall.
In this scene,
she was supposed to stare off into space.
I had to unwire her from the normal response
to somebody sitting there talking to you.
So I gave her a mark on the wall to
look at, told her to blank her mind,
and that seemed to work pretty well.
(Carrie) This is one of
my favorite parts of the movie.
I guess cos Sigourney and I
had bonded so much
and this is where in the movie
our bonding does start.
She was determined
to get that dirt off of me.
They didn't really want her
to wipe my face clean,
and she was really determined
to get it off of me.
She didn't think it was very fair
that I was that dirty and nobody else was.
So it was nice that I didn't have to worry
about so much dirt later on.
She was really nice.
She was always helping me.
(Cameron) Sigourney and Carrie
got to be pals and they'd hang out.
I think Sigourney felt
very protective of her.
Sigourney didn't have
any children at that time.
There was a real bond
that was very maternal, l think, there.
And I think Carrie thought
Sigourney was pretty cool.
Carrie's pretty good in this scene.
She really got it.
(Paxton) Sigourney was so nice.
I thought I must be screwing up
cos she was so nice to me all the time,
but I realized she was just
really genuinely a nice person.
(Henriksen) She really is. Gentle.
(Paxton) She was the leader
of the cast, absolutely.
She took a lot of punishment in this thing.
(Henriksen) Her back was hurting her, too.
They had to make a dummy of Newt.
- (Paxton) For her to carry.
- (Henriksen) Cos her back was killing her.
(Goldstein) A lot of crawling around
and crouching.
(Paxton) It's interesting to note that
she was nominated for an Academy Award
in a genre that the Academy never recognizes
- science fiction, fantasy and horror.
(Biehn) It does now but it didn't then.
(Paxton) It does now
but it certainly didn't then.
(Cameron) I love the idea of this little
girl who feels more secure by herself,
away from the adults, with these aliens
around, than when she's with them,
and the foreboding potential of that.
She looks at the marines and says "You guys are
all gonna die and I'll be on my own again,
but I'm more at risk when I'm with you
than doing my thing that I know works."
I really thought that was a cool idea.
(Henriksen) This is where I was gonna use
the two pupils in each eye.
And I did it and when the guy
interrupted me,
I turned and looked at him and Jim said
"It's so scary, I can't use it."
(Cameron) Lance loves to create a character
through some kind of physical totem.
In characters he's done for me,
it could be a pocket knife...
I'm talking about a rabbit's-foot
kind of thing.
He looks for some way
into the character.
So he, on his own, made up these
sclera lenses that had double pupils.
They were really creepy. It was a really
cool idea, but I felt it was too overt.
I felt it was too on the nose.
We wanted to go for an ominous thing,
but I think Lance underestimated
his own onscreen power,
and I knew that he could do
a great ominous moment.
(Robert) Here's a panning shot
of the armored personnel carrier.
This was done with the twelfth-scale
armored personnel carrier.
We had the camera flat on the ground and at
the beginning of the shot, behind the APC,
is the fiftieth-scale colony complex.
Because we're flat on the ground,
the audience doesn't see the scale
differential that's going on there.
Literally, the bumper of a twelfth-scale
was next to a fiftieth-scale.
The shots of the APC
driving into the atmosphere processor
were also done as miniatures.
There was no full-size entryway
that was built for the film.
That's why we built one as a miniature.
(Dennis) The sequence inside
the atmosphere processor
is a location that was
a decommissioned power station at Acton,
inside London or just outside of London.
Rather than building a set from scratch,
they used what was there
and then added the alienesque bits to it.
- (Henriksen) Look at that.
- (Goldstein) This was my first day.
- (Biehn) At Acton?
- First day ever on a film.
- (Biehn) You won't see me there.
- (Goldstein) Ever on any film.
I'd no idea what "back to one" meant
or anything.
(Biehn) What does it mean? 30 years later
I'm still trying to figure it out.
(Henriksen) That's a real gun.
That's a German Sten gun.
(Paxton) It was cool
until we started firing the weapons
and then this fine snow
started raining down on everybody.
- I think they checked it out.
- (Goldstein) It was just asbestos.
(Paxton) We had to practice
shooting flame-throwers.
We did the close-quarter battle stuff.
Approaching a building or going down
a hallway, you leapfrog along. We did that.
Al Matthews who plays Sergeant Apone
had some kind of military background.
I think he had served in the Vietnam War,
and after the war he had come to England,
where he'd become
a radio disc jockey, I think.
He was either really good at bullshitting us,
but he seemed to know what he was doing.
His orders were so authoritarian
that we followed him.
(Winston) Another technique that's not used
any more to create the size of that set.
A hanging miniature
that was the previous shot,
where you saw the expanse of the
inside of this alien virtual universe,
which is what you're seeing here,
setwise,
the cocoon aspect
of what these aliens do.
A hanging miniature,
which is a technique,
is a small set piece
that hangs in front of the camera
and then the full-size set is behind it
and the actors are behind it.
The illusion is that the set is huge
and expanding up and over everyone,
when, in fact, the foreground
of the set piece is a miniature,
the background of the set piece
and all the actors is normal size.
It's basically a forced-perspective shot.
(Paxton) This is my first
on-camera line coming up.
(Goldstein) This was the first day.
(Paxton) We started at Acton.
We started here.
(Biehn) I thought you guys
had already been shooting.
- (Goldstein) They had to reshoot.
- (Paxton) We went back and picked up here.
(Biehn) I see.
(Paxton) And Dick Bush,
the cinematographer,
was replaced by Adrian Biddle
somewhere in this area at the same time.
A few changes were made in the lineup
about two weeks in.
(Robert)
I heard that some of the studio execs
were screening footage
back in the States,
and they were a little perturbed and asking
"Where's the effects shot?"
Gale Hurd said
"You just saw an effects shot."
She was referring
to that perspective shot.
They were completely fooled by it.
They thought nothing had been shot.
(Dennis) They thought they were spending
huge amounts of money on these sets.
(Robert) They said "You spent so much
and there's no miniature."
She said "No, that is the miniature."
(McClung)
It was a smart move on Cameron's part,
to do it that way very quickly in the film,
so the studio wasn't worried
quite as much
about what was going on
5,000 miles away in London.
(Dennis) It does make it
a bit tricky to shoot, though.
If anything goes wrong, you're stuck with it or
you have to fix it later but with a reshoot.
You can't really fix it later.
So that worked out quite well,
but with actors and everything
there's a lot on the line.
(Robert) Something we've lost sight of over the
years is that with this era of filmmaking,
not only for live-action
but for miniatures,
there wasn't much ability
to go back and fix something.
Now, digitally, you can change
an actor's face, you can get rid of wires,
do all kinds of tricks, split-screen,
take elements and change shots.
But at that time you had to plan these things
and make it work within a narrow tolerance,
otherwise that was it,
that's what wound up in the film.
(Dennis) It reminds me of a stage play.
You're doing it live, in a sense.
What was on film was it. There was no going
back. You could only do it so many times.
There was a limited budget to work with
and it had to work on film, no matter what.
(Winston) My crew actually helped
dress this whole set
because it had to be cocooned bodies,
and so we created all these bodies
and all the dressing over it,
to help out the art department.
(Hurd) I remember being terrified
that the set wouldn't be ready in time.
Because it was very complicated.
(Winston) Everybody had to pitch in
and make the movie work.
It was a lot to do in a
short period of time.
No one else would have
really been able to do it, even this stuff.
(Hurd) I even doubled for Vasquez.
(Winston) Did you?
Do you remember the shot?
(Hurd) Of course I remember the shot.
I'll show you later on.
(Winston) Our homage to what
everyone needs to see
in this movie is about to come up.
This was a very tough scene to create,
which was the chestburster scene.
Again, a duplication of
head and entire body
and then we built an entire puppet of her
for the chestburster and the burn sequence.
(Cameron) James Horner
came up with this music sting here
and I always thought
it was totally over the top.
When I saw the whole film put together
with the score,
I thought "No, that's what we need."
I thought "How can you sting somebody
opening their eyes?" But it works.
(Paxton) Oh! Mm-hm.
She shouldn't have had
the bangers and mash.
Kill it. Fry it. Come on.
What are you doing, Hicks?
(Biehn) Bad-ass nasty shot.
That's a nasty shot of that thing.
(Paxton) That's a good shot
of it there getting fried.
Gosh.
Here they come.
(Cameron) I think our chestburster looks a
little cooler than the one in the first film.
Stan Winston's guys
really did a good job on it.
John Rosengrant and Shane Mahan.
(Hurd) Look who's back.
(Winston) Another one of our problems
to solve for this movie
was creating the whole army of warrior aliens
and being legitimate to the original movie
but having to improve on it for movement and
for the look of being able to study them.
In the original Alien
they were rubber suits
and very difficult
for the actor to move around in.
(Hurd) And yet he was
very tall and very skinny.
(Winston) And Jim wanted to do a lot of very
interesting moves with the warrior aliens,
so we came up with a technique
to create the suit
that really involved
a lot of spandex and pieces on it.
And then we designed the set pieces
for the aliens to fit into the walls,
like the one that is behind him there,
so that the camouflage would work.
An enormous amount of wirework
for all of these stunt alien performers,
which required that the alien costumes
be extremely user-friendly.
(Cameron) This was inspired
by the scene in the first film
where Dallas is in the air vents and they see
the signal moving and get a little freaked,
and Veronica Cartwright says
"Get outta there"
and he makes the wrong move
and gets killed.
That's one of the most
suspenseful scenes in the first film.
I took that idea that they're getting these
readings that are getting them spooked
and then they make some bad moves.
(Hurd) Form follows function.
This is a perfect example of it.
You start with what it is you wanna achieve,
and once you have that, you can design it,
so the actions and the performance
is consistent with
what you want in the finished film.
Believe it or not,
very few people work that way.
They just wanna come up
with something that's cool,
and then you spend hours and hours trying
to get it to work for the ultimate film.
(Winston) I happen to agree with Gale.
My background is as an actor.
I really come from a place
where the creatures and the characters
are wonderful to look at,
but it's always about their performance.
We have to figure out
how they're gonna be able to act,
and create a good performance,
or it's a waste.
And so that's really always at the top
of the priority list
when we're creating any creature -
what is it gonna do
and how is it gonna do it?
(Hurd) What he does is create a character, and
that's why I think his work is so unique.
When you look at a film, you can always
tell who's done the creatures,
if they actually have a character.
Because he creates a character
that can act and perform.
(Cameron) The whole film
builds to this moment,
where the power transfers
from the authoritarian structure
to the individual who takes action.
Ripley's not supposed to do anything.
She's just there as an observer.
(Robert) We're coming up to a sequence
where Sigourney takes control of the APC
and this sequence is comprised
of live-action shots,
but as it comes down this hallway and is
banging into pipes and walls and sparking,
that's all done in miniature.
In some cases, the cameraman -
cos the set was mounted at an angle -
was on a cart, a wheeled cart,
and was rolling backwards as the
radio-controlled APC was coming at camera.
There was a point when he was just put
into free fall, rolling backwards downhill,
photographing what was in front of him
as he went backwards.
- (Winston) Here we go.
- (Hurd) This is the shot.
(Winston) This is also miniatures.
(Hurd) There was a shot with the full-size
when the brakes didn't work,
and took out the camera, and luckily
it was a remote-operated camera.
(Winston) It was the shot where
we were actually crushing an alien warrior,
when it broke through.
This is the shot, actually,
when it took the camera out.
Then there's another shot
where it takes down an alien.
(Cameron) These shots of the aliens hanging
from the ceiling are just shot upside down.
It's just guys standing there
in an alien suit.
And we set up some alien puppets
made out of foam
and filled them with gak and guts
and yellow goo,
and blew the hell out of them, as I recall.
Made a big mess.
(Winston) Miniscule things we had to do,
like creating burn appliance make-up
for when the acid would hit.
Here's a case right here.
Alien comes up, splats,
and the blood is right here.
- (Hurd) Quick cut.
- (Winston) Quick cut. But prosthetics used.
(McClung) John Richardson
was the physical effects supervisor.
I was at his shop on the lot, and they were
testing one of these flame-throwers
and it was a real flame-thrower
that they had built.
This thing would go about 20 or 30 feet.
So every time you see flames coming out,
it's the real thing. It was a little scary.
(Cameron) When we did the fire in the APC,
there was something used to age the set,
some kind of wax-based substance
that the art department had dabbed on
to make the set look more like
a used military vehicle.
And the heat caused it to vaporize
and the actors got this strong sense
that they couldn't breathe.
It caused their throats to close up.
Bill tells the story
Jenette is going "Ugh!"
And Bill remembers thinking
"She's coming up with some great stuff."
And she really couldn't breathe.
I don't remember what we did.
Probably just kept shooting.
I think we just kept the fire
out of the inside, kept going.
(McClung) Because the full-size APC
was incapable of spinning its wheels,
all those shots of Ripley
when she hits the gas and you see the wheels
spin and smoke are all the miniature,
because the full-size vehicle again
weighed some 20 or 30 tons.
(Robert) We had put A-B smoke... A
solution on the wheel and B on the ground.
And as the tire turned, it would mix
that A and B together and give the smoke.
We had somebody holding back
the front of the APC for a moment,
so that the tire'd spin,
then we'd let it go.
(McClung) That A-B smoke is really toxic.
We don't like to breathe that stuff.
(Cameron) We had different kinds of smoke.
We had some really nasty smoke
that I think is illegal to use now,
titanium tetroxide stuff that created
that really nice coherent smoke,
but that was only used
for some of the alien acid stuff.
And then you just used a regular mole fogger.
We used A-B smoke for a couple of things.
Some of the acid hits were done
with A-B smoke, which is pretty caustic.
(Biehn) In Jim's movies - I think of it
the same way with The Terminator -
there's not one shot in it that you go
"That's bad" or "That doesn't work."
It just seems like every single shot...
(Paxton) He knows how to put all the shots
that really make the whole sequence
snap, crackle and pop, that's for sure.
There's not many directors
who are fluent in the language of film.
Jim comes to it intuitively.
- (Biehn) What are you crying about here?
- (Paxton) Something.
(Biehn) Somebody was always
telling you to relax.
(Paxton) It was a character where I felt the
audience is gonna be so ready for him to die.
(Biehn) You got
a good death scene, though.
(Carrie) This was weird at first cos I wasn't
quite used to all the cussing around me.
Hudson tended to say a lot.
Every time when we'd cut,
he'd look at me - "I'm so sorry."
I didn't care,
but I kind of felt bad for him.
And at this time, you never really realize
what a bad guy Paul Reiser was.
(Winston) Paul was so good in this.
You so wanted him to get killed.
(Hurd) I love that in a villain. Hudson,
the character that Bill Paxton plays,
is the voice of the audience in this.
He's saying the things
the audience would say
and asking the questions
the audience would ask.
(Cameron) You could tell
when we started screening the film...
We didn't screen it in the way they do now.
We never did a test screening.
But at the premiere, let's say, which is the
first time I saw the film with an audience,
which is unthinkable these days,
we could tell the audience
really liked Hudson, really connected.
I like this scene cos, again,
it's the transfer of power.
Sigourney has made Burke
as a guy she can't trust.
Ripley has figured out Burke's agenda,
and she's created
enough of a bond with Hicks
that she knows she can get him
to do what needs to be done,
take command
even though he's a corporal.
(McClung) Having been in the army
myself in the '70s,
Jim really nailed army life for the
military, and he was never in the military.
- (Dennis) Jim wasn't.
- That's how guys acted.
(Dennis) Rear projection is an older technique
that's been used in a lot of films.
It's basically having a projector
a distance away from a translucent screen
that's behind the actor.
The image of the scene they're supposed
to be standing in front of is projected -
previously shot footage - and that method
tends to look like what you're doing,
unless, as Jim shoots it,
the camera's moving a lot
and there's a lot of things
to obscure the straight photography of it.
Front projection uses a material that
is made by 3M and some other companies
that is related to the material
used for traffic signs.
When your headlights hit the signs,
they kind of glow back.
It's very similar to that, except
it's an even more extreme version of it.
An image is projected...
(Robert) From the camera
rather than behind the set.
(Dennis) It's projected
from near the camera,
hits the screen and it comes
right back at the camera.
The shadow that you would expect to see
is hidden by the object or person in the
foreground. It's self-hiding, in theory.
(Robert) Front projection produces
a more photographable image.
It retains the illumination level
better than rear projection.
We did a number
of these dropship crashes,
four or five of these things
to finally get the plate right.
(Dennis) Jim was specific about
how the dropship would hit.
This whole ballet of it
rolling and so forth.
(Robert) We had to design that in
so that the pods hit a certain way,
the landing leg shears off by hitting a rock
which sends it skewing slightly sideways
which dovetails into
this tumbling action.
This has become
a famous shot in the film.
(Cameron) Every film is a snapshot
of the technical capabilities of its time.
Even though at the time you feel like
you're moving things forward a little bit,
you look back on it now, 1 8 years later,
and it just seems quaint.
(Carrie) This is one of the scenes
I don't particularly like.
There's a line in here
and it seems to be the only line of mine
that everybody I ever run into remembers.
Anyone who ever wants to irritate me,
any of my friends, they just say this.
They say it with everything. The line was
"They mostly come out at night. Mostly."
My friends'll be like "We mostly
go to the movies at night. Mostly."
They come up with whatever
they can possibly come up with.
It's probably the one scene l don't really
particularly like in the whole thing.
(Robert) This shot with Ripley and Newt
looking back at the burning,
damaged atmosphere processor
was done with doubles
months after live action had wrapped.
(Henriksen) I never realized
I had such a small part in this.
(laughter)
(Biehn) You come in big
at the end, though.
(Cameron) A typical group scene.
My challenge was almost every scene
was a group scene.
Most scenes had seven,
eight characters at one time,
so there were a lot of camera axes.
In Terminator every scene
had two or three people in it.
It was no problem.
But almost every scene in this
had multiple characters,
a Gatling gun of dialogue
going around the room,
and I found that challenging at first
till I got it all straight in my head.
I wasn't that experienced.
This was my second film.
- (Paxton) I wanted to be cool like Michael.
- (Biehn) I was cool in that shot.
(Paxton) I wanted to be the cool guy,
not the guy bellyaching.
- (Biehn) This movie made you a star.
- I wanted to be Michael Biehn in this movie.
- (Biehn) So did l.
- (Henriksen) I wanted to be Sigourney.
(laughter)
- (Paxton) "Why don't you put her in charge?"
- (laughter)
(Henriksen) There it is.
That's a classic, man.
(Cameron) Actor dynamics are tricky,
cos actors are all gonna peak
at different moments,
and it's impossible
not to go through a power hierarchy.
The group always knows
who's getting the close-up.
There's this sense that I should do a close-up
on everybody so nobody feels left out.
There's a whole political side to doing a
group scene. They all see what's going on.
Eventually I dispensed with that
and went for Sigourney's close-up.
Fortunately, Sigourney always
liked to go last, which was good.
She liked to build and have the time
before the camera got in tight on her
to really pick
how she was gonna do her moments.
(Henriksen) Here goes. "I'll do it.
I'll go."
"Send the doll."
That's what Bill's whole thing was.
- (Biehn) Send the doll?
- (Henriksen) "Send the doll out there, man."
I was so hurt.
(Paxton) Yeah, man. Hudson should go.
I mean Bishop should go.
(Henriksen) There's a pipe.
Send him down the pipe.
My favorite thing was Bill wanted
to use me as a training toy.
"Let's chase Bishop around
and shoot at him."
(Paxton) The processing station.
(Biehn) You were so into your character,
we'd ask you for a coffee,
you'd run for it, go clean up our trailers.
(Henriksen) I was absolutely selfless.
That was embarrassing, man.
(Cameron) I never liked that shot because
she keeps pointing at the same spot.
I think that was a second-unit shot
that was done while I was in another room
shooting something else.
I was never happy with it.
The whole idea was she's supposed to be
showing the whole area.
The floor diagram
didn't resemble the set either.
You gotta remember,
this is a low-budget film.
Got to cut it a little slack.
I like these really
advanced laptops they have.
We thought we were
being so advanced here.
This is an added scene
with these sentry guns.
This is a scene that got the ax
as a result of the studio's idea
that we were wasting too much time
not really getting on with the story.
I actually think this stuff really ups
the ante and increases the fear a lot.
(Hurd) Because The Terminator hadn't come
out yet, there was the perception that Jim
was somehow not up to
the creative responsibility
of directing a sequel
to Ridley Scott's masterpiece.
There was a lot of resentment,
and really no understanding, or very little,
of what he was trying to accomplish.
We had people who were, I think,
completely on our side -
John Richardson in practical special
effects, Brian Johnson in visual effects.
There were people
who understood Jim's vision,
but there were quite a few people
who simply looked at him
as the know-nothing, upstart Yank, which drove
Jim crazy, considering he's a Canadian.
(Winston) It was his right hand, his AD.
(Hurd) The leader of the rebellion,
the first assistant director,
not only behind Jim's back but to his face
would call him "Guv'nor" and roll his eyes,
as if Jim hadn't earned the title yet.
We were shooting very long hours
and people were pretty frazzled,
and by our standards in America at the time a
12-hour day is not a long day, it's average,
but 1 2 hours at the time in England
was a very long day,
and there were times
when we'd go into a 14-hour day.
At a certain point
our assistant director, basically, said:
"We're not doing this any more."
So we fired him. And he felt that
he really should be directing the movie.
He was a frustrated director.
He had directed second unit before.
I think he even had directed a small film.
But he really felt that he was better
qualified than Jim was to direct the film.
He went to all the departments
and some cast members
and everyone walked off the set.
It was the most difficult moment
of my entire career, even to this day,
trying to rally everyone back.
In fact, we were able to turn it around
so that the outcome of that mutiny
was that we were united,
after we resolved the issues,
for the first time on the film and going
onto the rest of the production schedule.
We actually were a unified group.
So it was an example of something good
coming out of a really difficult situation.
(Winston) I remember talking to people
and going "This is a wonderful movie."
And hoping that
no one would lose the energy.
Fortunately, because of how you handled it,
it all came together.
Because it was scary. It was very scary.
We were at that point -
what are we gonna do, hire a new crew?
(Hurd) Not that the thought didn't cross
my mind, but England was very busy.
We didn't have the option. There weren't
other key crew members even available.
When you have no options,
you make it work, and we did.
(Winston) This is probably
my favorite movie of my career,
and the only movie where I've experienced
anything like what we went through.
I will also say, on the positive side,
of the English crew...
I brought a handful of guys
from the States.
We started all our designs
and our builds in the States
and then built a workshop in Pinewood
and hired all but a half a dozen of the key
coordinators from my studio from England.
And everybody worked very hard
and did a great job.
They were wonderful artists and committed
and everybody wanted to do a good job.
They just had slightly different
work habits than we did.
I was shocked when suddenly,
at a particular time mid-morning,
everybody would be gone. I'd go "Where
is everybody?" They'd go "They're at tea."
I said "Hello?" Just gone.
(Hurd) The other thing
is that Pinewood Studios
at the time had an entire crew on staff
that were assigned to a movie.
Right now it's four-wall, which means
you hire the crew you want, it's freelance.
But you ended up with the crew that was
assigned to the stages you were working on
and there was no
selection process involved.
It made it really difficult because
some people really were punching a clock.
They didn't want overtime,
didn't wanna do anything
other than work an eight-hour day.
(Cameron) Shooting this film in England
wasn't just a culture clash.
For me, it was also a transition from
a non-union guerilla-filmmaking mentality,
which started at Roger Corman's New World
Pictures and continued on The Terminator,
which had a non-union crew,
to a union picture.
And also the particular way that they work
in England was very, very different,
and so there was an adaptation to that.
And, frankly, l thought there were
a lot of people on the crew that were,
to use a charitable term, comfortable,
and that was completely foreign to me.
I'd been used to working with young,
eager, hard-core, dedicated film folks.
They all had something to prove.
But a lot of the people especially at the
Pinewood Studios at that time were lifers.
They had permanent employment. It didn't
matter what movie they were working on.
And they got pushed on us. If you did
Pinewood, you had to use their people.
It was a whole different mentality. So I
pushed against that as hard as I could.
If I hadn't, we wouldn't
have got the film done
on budget and on schedule,
which we did.
I know probably a lot of people there
at Pinewood at the time didn't care for us,
with our guerilla-filmmaking
ways and styles - we were not polite.
By the end there were a number of them
that came to respect the fact
at least that we knew what we were doing,
which I guess is OK.
(Hurd) The other aspect that was a shock
to those of us who came from
really indie filmmaking -
I started with Roger Corman,
you can't get any more indie -
is that everyone in their family
had done the same job.
This is not, obviously, across the board.
There wasn't the enthusiasm -
"Let's get together and do a movie" -
we were used to.
I think their craftsmanship
was as fine if not even more spectacular
than anything I've seen before or since.
And they did take complete pride in that,
but it really is a different approach
to working.
(Winston) Once you're aware
of the difference in work habit,
you can adjust to it.
You know you've gotta get
the product done.
Everybody wants the same thing.
They just approach it in a different way.
That's all part of our learning curve.
(Hurd) Now it's different also
because there are not people on staff
that are assigned to your movie.
And also the liquid alcohol-based lunch
is not the same any more.
(Cameron) When you take time out,
you do a bit of everything.
You trim shots,
you take out a second here and there.
At this time we weren't cutting on the Avid
yet or any nonlinear digital editing system,
so there was less of a tendency
to nickel-and-dime tiny cuts of 1 0 frames.
Cutting on a Moviola, every cut
had to be a splice that was opened up,
so you tended to make lifts
which were full scenes or partial scenes.
When I cut Titanic,
I made all the lifts I could
and I was still miles out, so I went
through cutting 1 0 frames here and there
and got out another five minutes.
This is rear projection.
For the visual effects on this film, we needed
all these process plates, projection plates,
so the model unit
had to be scrambled well ahead of time,
actually producing finished shots
in a way that we could project on the set.
We knew we wanted a specific look
out of all of these windows.
We wanted to be able to have moisture
on the window and dust and wind
and all these sorts of things
that would degrade the image,
so we wanted to have
these projections done in advance.
I like the feeling of these guys
just working the problem,
just trying to figure it out.
There's always a moment when
there's the thing you know you need to do
and Bishop just steps up and volunteers.
If you're claustrophobic, this is something
you don't wanna try at home,
get yourself welded into a pipe
that's no wider than your shoulders.
When I was a kid,
we had a contest in my neighborhood.
They were always building
new subdivisions.
We used to see who could crawl the furthest
though the water pipes that had been laid.
I won because I have no claustrophobia,
but I got stuck once
about 1 00m into a water pipe.
Had to back out.
That's a little moment from my childhood.
Lance does a curious thing
at the end of that close-up.
I said "What was that?" He said
"Bishop just realized he made a joke."
You can actually see that, if you know that's
what's in his head and you watch that shot.
Bishop realizes after the fact
that he made a joke.
Because he's not human,
he doesn't know if it worked or not.
(Paxton) This was too freaky, I gotta tell you.
I wouldn't have been able to do this, Lance.
- How did you get in there in the first place?
- (Henriksen) Look how you get in.
(Goldstein) You just crawl in.
(Henriksen) You lower yourself in
and then twist around.
(Biehn) It's the shot of you
putting the lid on.
"Don't hurt your finger." That's the thing
you say here, right? That defines him.
(Paxton) You found stuff like that.
You found it from your character.
He was always trying to be of service,
like the gas company.
- (Henriksen) Look at this shot.
- This is it.
(Henriksen) They dragged a camera
on wheels in front of me.
- (Biehn) Is that how they did it?
- Yeah.
With a rope?
(Paxton) I remember watching you
shoot that.
I think you were on another stage. They had
that pipe. I remember watching you do that.
(Henriksen) I never let them
light me that way any more.
It's pretty rough.
(Cameron) I think editorially
it's a fun moment. I like the build.
I didn't do any editing directly
on this film.
Because it's film-based editing, with rapid
cutting, I thought it had really good energy.
You see that cutting now with the Avid cos
you don't have to make each splice manually.
This is the Alamo told with six people.
So the sentry guns are the equivalent
of the first couple of attacks.
I think it's great foreboding.
It's just coming at them like a wave.
If these guns don't stop them,
they're screwed.
I think it works pretty well, but the
studio talked me into taking it out.
So I'm happy to see it restored
in this extended version.
(Hurd) Ray Lovejoy was our editor
and it was a tremendous responsibility.
And this is before you had
all of the Avid and Lightworks
and any kind of digital editing.
There was so much film and we had
a pretty short postproduction schedule
and he did just a tremendous job.
(Cameron) I hired Ray for one simple reason
- cos he had worked with Stanley Kubrick.
It took him a while to really get
what I was trying to do with this movie.
A lot of his early cuts
I didn't really care for.
It's not that there was ever
any tension between us.
I just didn't feel l was
getting what I wanted.
Ray was getting really frustrated. I remember
toward the end he cut the alien queen battle,
the power loader queen battle
at the end of the film.
He was really nervous, cos he hadn't
given me the action cutting that I wanted
and I'd had to mess with it a lot
and there was another editor
who was cutting some stuff,
and I was liking his action cutting
better than Ray's.
Ray is just a dear guy and a really
good editor, but he was struggling with it.
So, finally, he just grabbed all the film,
locked himself in his room,
said "Don't bother me."
Not mean or anything,
but "I just gotta do this."
And he went in and he cut the entire
last eight minutes of the picture.
He showed it to me very nervously.
He cut in a day or two.
He showed it to me very nervously
and I watched the whole thing and I said
"It's perfect. It's absolutely perfect.
Don't change anything." And that was that.
He felt like it was such a huge victory
because he had actually got it.
He had mastered the style for the film.
Sigourney, she's very liberal politically
and despised the idea
of any kind of guns or anything,
and tried to talk me
out of them having weapons.
I said "They're marines.
They'd have weapons."
She said "Do I have to carry a weapon?"
I said "Yes."
She said "Why?" l said "Because it's not
Sigourney Weaver in the film. It's Ripley."
"And Ripley wants to survive."
So I took her out shooting a Thompson
machine gun, out behind the studio,
and she fired off
a 50-round magazine from the hip.
And then she looked up at me with
this sly grin and said "That's really fun."
Another liberal bites the dust.
There were a few things she asked if
she could do when we had our first meeting.
She wanted to die in the film,
she wanted to not use guns
and she wanted to make love
to the alien.
And between the third and fourth film
she got to do all of those things.
But fortunately for this film, I said no to
all of them, even though I was petrified.
I thought she'd bolt from the project,
but she didn't.
She had a lot of good ideas.
But she did have certain specific things
she thought should be done
in the Alien mythos.
When she got to a position of power
on the later films, she made that happen.
(Winston) This scene coming up
with Ripley and Newt,
which is the attack of the facehuggers,
was a really tough scene
to orchestrate, prepare for,
as far as we think
we're now back 1 6 or 1 7 years.
So we don't have
any kind of digital animation
and there's not gonna be
any stop-motion animation,
and these facehuggers
have gotta come to life,
so we created I think
a half dozen different facehuggers
that would do different things
to create the performance coming up,
including our hero,
which had completely articulated hands,
multiple cables that had to be controlled
by six puppeteers for one facehugger.
We had one that would run across the floor.
We called him our pull toy.
We had stunt facehuggers
that we could throw to hit the wall.
We had actually two different heroes.
There's the one that crawls
up over the counter coming at Newt.
And then a completely articulated one
with tongue and fingers
that Ripley would fight off
with all of the cables down her arms
through the whole sequence.
And there's so much that happens in that.
You think of the facehugger
that's coming after them,
and multiple to create that one scene.
(Biehn) This is, to me,
the creepiest part of the movie.
This thing running around,
that sound effect he did of the facehugger.
(Henriksen) The first scenes of this movie
when he did the chestbuster.
The sequel, Alien -
he took care of it in five minutes.
- That first scene. That it was a dream.
- (Paxton) That was great.
(Henriksen) I thought it was so smart.
It was just great.
- His storytelling.
- (Biehn) The sound effects.
(Goldstein) That scrabbling noise.
(Paxton) The way this whole thing was laid
out in the first Alien and the second one,
the whole genesis of the way
it would start out in the pod
and then it turned into the facehugger
and then it turned into the alien.
(Robert) A lot of the shots
of it scuttling along the floor
were done on our miniature stage.
That shot where it just scuttled by was done
right next to the twelfth-scale cargo lock.
At the base of the twelfth-scale cargo lock
there was a little set there.
So Jim would have five or six or seven little
setups poked in between our miniatures.
We'd fog up the stage and get ready to
shoot, but he needed to shoot with no fog,
so we'd clear the stage, he'd shoot his
thing and then we would continue on.
So it was like one giant filmmaking unit but
we were doing two or three miniature shots
simultaneously and he was doing
four or five live-action inserts.
(Dennis) A concentrated dose
of Aliens filming.
(Cameron) It's very hard to see Paul Reiser
as such an evil guy,
after so many years of his TV series.
(Henriksen) He used to hate to ride to work
with me. I used ride to work with him.
- (Biehn) And he didn't like it?
- He hated it. I was like a real primitive.
- He's a sophisticated comic.
- (Paxton) What were you doing?
(Henriksen) I was always
grunting and groaning.
- (Biehn) Smoking, burping.
- He hated everything about me.
(Henriksen) What a boring ride that was.
(Paxton) You've been
carrying this baggage a while.
- This is a good forum.
- (Henriksen) Let it rip, baby.
(Paxton) It was because of
the character he was playing.
He's such a prissy, corporate guy in this.
It's tough in these kind of movies.
(Biehn) Especially when you're young,
if you're playing a good guy,
you're always hanging
with the good guys.
You don't trust yourself as an actor
to be friendly with the bad guys.
(Paxton) "One of the bad guys
might wreck my big scene."
(laughter)
(Biehn) We were too serious as actors
to be able to hang with Paul.
(Henriksen) He was reading the paper
the whole time.
It was like I was interrupting
if I talked to him.
(Paxton) You didn't wanna ride
to work with me?
- I was in a different area.
- (Paxton) You were right round the corner.
- You didn't want me with you.
- Bullshit.
(Cameron) We're yanking
these facehuggers around.
I called them rubber-chicken facehuggers
cos they were these floppy ones.
The crawling one had
a mechanism inside it.
That was shot backwards. We pulled
the tail off and shot it backwards.
There was a pretty good mechanism built
into the ones that are really articulated,
but a lot of the time we were just
yanking them around on fishing line
and doing it in cuts.
People probably wonder why I had him shoot
the window before he jumped through it.
The idea was it's tempered glass.
You have to get the crystal structure of the
glass to shatter before you can go through it.
So this is a bunch of grown people
fighting a rubber chicken, basically.
But, of course, it's the actors
that make the effects real in our minds.
(Biehn) Great sequence. I love the red light
that he uses in this too. The warning light.
That happens in the other sequence too when
the aliens are coming through the roof. Look.
(Carrie) This is another scene that
James Cameron sets up as the family scene.
There's just the three of us there
as a family, ready for Alien 3.
(Cameron) David Fincher did a really
good job photographically and so on.
I think it's really a well-made film,
visually.
It's just kind of a slap in the face
of the fans
who invested in Newt and Hicks
and all of those character relationships.
I understand the instinct, of course,
which is you have to make it your own.
I just don't think you should
make it your own
at the expense of what
people like, personally.
But everybody's gonna make
their own decisions.
But I had to change some things
and make it my own on my film.
And I know that Ridley probably watched it
and wasn't pleased with a lot of things.
He probably wasn't pleased
with the fact that he hadn't made it.
But I think it's tough.
It's tough to see somebody continue on
something that you've started.
But then you learn to just get over it
because that's the nature of this business.
I think the trick to this type of film
is you just take it utterly seriously.
You don't step outside yourself and try to
have fun with it and wink at the audience.
You take it absolutely seriously
and you don't give the audience
a chance to question it.
And if the actors can sell it,
then it works.
This is a distinction. I never got the sense in
the first film that the alien had an intelligence
that allowed it to manipulate
their technology,
but I didn't see that
necessarily as a barrier here
because certainly these creatures
have been around longer.
The alien in the first film
had only been alive for 24 hours.
It was still an infant,
even though it had grown full size.
These aliens have had weeks or months
to figure things out.
There's no reason why they couldn't
figure out the electrical system.
Not that they're technological,
but the rudimentary stuff.
The implication is that
they're pretty clever.
It's clear by the end of the film that the
alien queen knows how to operate an elevator.
(Hurd) It's amazing how such a low-tech
little device that Jim sets up early on
really builds the tension.
You don't have to see them.
You just see that locator
and you realize they're getting closer
with a little sound effect.
(Robert) This is one of
the first films we worked on
that we worked with a video
to look at our effects.
Prior to that you would shoot a shot
and go by your perception at the moment
as to whether it worked or not
and looking at dailies the next day.
You didn't see an instant replay.
But on this film we used a video tap and
offside video camera on some of the shots
to analyze what worked and what didn't.
(McClung) It was fairly expensive
to have a video tap camera.
In most effects stuff,
the cameras used were...
These old Mitchell cameras were great
but they didn't have video tap.
It was an expense
a lot of times you couldn't afford.
- (Goldstein) More welding.
- (Biehn) Just don't look at it.
- (Goldstein) Look away or you'll be blinded.
- (Biehn) Weld it but don't look at it.
(Goldstein) Put your hand there.
Don't look at it.
- (Henriksen) Is this where you bite it?
- (Biehn) Yeah. Well, pretty soon.
(Paxton) I'm gonna keep talking,
even if l'm dead.
(Biehn) I don't know if you remember, Bill.
I had to ask Jim to go after you.
He was just gonna have you being pulled
down. I'm like "Let me go after him."
- It was a nice thing.
- (Paxton) I remember.
(Biehn) I think about how much shooting
we did in this sequence
with those pulse rifles and the full loads.
(Paxton) I was standing to the right of
you, so I got to eat a few of those.
I was catching the shells.
(Biehn) This was a hard-core sequence.
- (Paxton) It was the first time...
- You had the earplugs in.
(Paxton) But it was one of the few times
we really got to shoot those guns off,
which was great
cos we were carrying them all the time.
- This is it right here.
- (Henriksen) This is a great shot.
That one right there.
Looking up and seeing these dudes.
(Paxton) This is great. POV.
(all) Ooh!
(laughter)
(Paxton) There's a whole nest of
them things coming out of there.
They're coming out of the woodwork.
Let 'em have it, Vasquez.
Come on, Hicks. Get your gun off.
(Cameron) The alien head
in the first film was very smooth.
The top was smooth. Underneath
it had a skull shape and a ribbed design.
Originally it was designed to see that through
a transparent surface in the Giger design.
I thought what was under the surface
was more interesting than the final look,
so we just modified it slightly.
We used a lot of strobe lights to
simulate the back blast of their weapons.
Every time they're firing weapons,
we're aiming strobes at the actors,
which created a nice sense of a lot of energy
flying around as they fire these weapons.
- (Biehn) Did you say "motherfucker"?
- (Paxton) I think I did.
I think I've used up my quota there.
That could have been my quota.
(laughter)
(Biehn) "You want some?" That's a good
one. "You want some? Come on, I got it."
- (Paxton) And then I get pulled below.
- (Biehn) Oh, man.
(Paxton) That was good.
(Biehn) And that thing comes up...
(Paxton) There it goes.
- From here on out...
- (Biehn) The movie dies right there.
(Paxton) The movie's
just not quite the same.
- (Henriksen) He had the script for Near Dark.
- (Paxton) This movie just doesn't stop.
(Henriksen) You had the script for Near
Dark and were thinking about that.
(Paxton) The movie just goes into overdrive
from here on out, right to the bitter end.
It just doesn't stop.
(Hurd) There's an editing technique
that Jim likes to use which is blank frames
in between the discharge from the weapons,
sort of whites out the frame.
It really helps the staccato cutting.
(Cameron) I was having them splice together
individual frames of white flash leader.
The negative cutter said -
we did a lot of flash frames
and one-frame cuts in that sequence -
we had more edits
in this reel 1 2 of Aliens
than in any complete film
the negative cutter had done before.
So the whole high-tech war
has degenerated to the point
where they have to follow the little kid
or they're gonna die.
Movie air ducts are always
big enough to get through.
It bears no resemblance to the real world.
The theory is that the audience
has never been inside an air duct.
Air ducts are not big enough
to walk through.
But it's a conceit. It's also a
conceit taken from the first film.
(Carrie) Supposedly,
the way l survived in the colony
was going around everywhere
in the air ducts.
We supposedly played a game
and part of the reason I was called Newt
is because I was so quick in the air ducts
and no one really liked me on the colony
because I beat them at the game.
Fortunately it ended up
saving us from the aliens at this time.
(Winston) For this air-duct set,
we had vertical air ducts
so that we could actually drop
the aliens down with the monofilament,
so that you would feel -
and you'll see it in here -
feel them crawling
on the ceilings and the walls,
that bug aspect of them.
- (Hurd) My cameo's coming up.
- (Winston) Who were you?
(Hurd) Vasquez had never fired a handgun.
Jenette Goldstein hadn't.
She was living in England.
Not a lot of handguns.
For the wide shot she was great, but for
the close-up of her killing the alien,
her recoil wasn't accurate.
Unlike today, when I'm on a set,
I dressed up in suits on this film
and the crew couldn't believe it...
- That's me. That's me.
- (Winston) All right, girl!
(Hurd) All of the close-ups
of the handgun firing at the alien was me.
People couldn't believe it,
since I always dressed up in suits.
I needed something to give myself
the appearance of authority.
When I came in in the fatigues
and fired a gun...
- (Winston) They saw the real Gale.
- They were pretty surprised.
Jim told me that I was in my office and the
crew were saying "What are we gonna do?"
"Who here has ever fired
a handgun before?"
And he said "My wife has."
He said "I'm gonna go get her
and she's gonna do the shot." And I did.
(Cameron) Jenette has very fair skin,
freckles and had hair down
to her waist and blue eyes.
So somehow we managed to see
that if we cut all her hair off
and gave her dark make-up
and brown contact lenses,
she was actor enough to actually
pull off this Hispanic character.
(Winston) That was a tough actual
physical effect. There was nothing optical.
That fireball came flying
through that corridor.
(Hurd) We didn't have digital anything
back then. We didn't have digital fire.
(Carrie) This is cool. It was a chute.
It was about three stories high
and it had a big old curve at the end.
I kept sometimes messing up
so that I could redo it.
(Cameron) Important survival tips in this
film. Never grab the jacket. Grab the hand.
Unless you have a Newt-finder device
in your pocket, then you're OK.
Gene Siskel had a big problem
with this scene
because of the jeopardy
of a little child with an alien monster.
That never occurred to me, but I
wasn't a parent when I made this film.
It probably would bother me more now
because I could empathize
too much with the child.
The thing that never bothered me about
the idea of putting a child in jeopardy
is that somehow you just know inherently
that Ripley's not gonna let her die,
no matter what it takes.
I know they spent a lot of time
on the first film finding a big guy,
building a suit that the tall guy could wear,
but in watching that movie and studying it,
I realized that the alien almost never appears
in the same frame with a person for scale,
and so we just decided to use normal
six-foot-tall people, cos we needed a lot.
We knew we couldn't find
ten seven-and-half-foot-tall guys.
Probably the only exception
is when the alien rises up behind her,
but I figured that wasn't a problem
cos she was small anyway.
We create the scale in our minds anyway.
(Winston) Michael was so good at this.
This shot is in my show reel still.
If you examine it now, you can see the
monofilament on the tail, pulling it up.
I hate to low-tech it,
but it's what it was.
Goodbye.
(Paxton) You just see
the little doll head as it sinks.
(Biehn) That's where Jim over and over
again has those images like that.
(Paxton) There it is right there.
The eyes kind of close.
(Biehn) This is where
they use that A-B smoke on me.
(Paxton) That stuff's nasty.
- (Goldstein) They used that on Near Dark.
- (Henriksen) They've outlawed it.
(Biehn) Hard-core stuff.
(Henriksen) You breathe that in
and you get lung damage.
(Paxton) It's tough
when you're doing these shots.
It becomes all about
if the smoke reacted right.
(Biehn) I've always thought the worst job
on any set is the guy who makes the smoke.
Less smoke, more smoke.
Waft it up, waft it down.
Fire that guy. Get a new smoke guy.
(Cameron) Elevator doors
never close fast enough for me.
It's just a pet peeve
with the way the world is wired.
(Robert) The shot of the vest getting hit by
acid was an insert that was shot on M stage
as we were shooting the dropship
flying out of the atmosphere processor.
As it's blowing up,
Jim was shooting with his back to us.
He was stepping on our track
that the camera ran on,
while it was being photographed.
He would step off the track
and we'd run the camera down the track.
(McClung) And there was A-B smoke
drifting over into our area
which made it hard to breathe.
(Dennis) Miniature on wires here.
(Robert) Again, recalling that these
miniatures are moving very fast in reality.
We're seeing them here slowed down.
(Dennis) We run the camera at high speed for
miniature work to give a lot more scale.
It gives it the size that's needed
to make it feel believable.
If you were to see it as it actually happens,
it would look like the small scale that it is,
so this is why it's done.
(Robert) We'd gone back in after we built
the atmosphere-processor miniature
and before we did this shot we had a whole
crew - well, four or five guys, including us -
running in and adding extra detail because
we were pushing into the interior of it.
So we had a day and a half of heavy-duty
microdetailing going on there.
(Paxton) This movie laid the foundation
for me for a lot of stuff.
Again, it was working for Jim
that was really fantastic.
I remember running into Jim
when he'd been hired to write this.
I was at the airport. He was
handing off a parcel to some courier.
I don't know why. I guess because
they were setting up shop in England.
He said "I'm writing the sequel to Alien."
I said "Write me a good part in there."
I kidded him.
Six months later I tried out for it in
England and I didn't think I'd gotten it.
Your friends are usually
the last people to hire you.
Cos you have no mystique with them.
And then I got a call. I almost took Police
Academy 3 or something, and then I got this.
More money than l'd ever seen in my life.
They hired
Bob Wildcat Goldthwait instead.
(laughter)
I don't know who got the better deal,
but I think I did.
(Cameron) Everybody was looking at the film
as well-made in the sound and visual effects,
but we were pleasantly surprised
when Sigourney got nominated.
Not that we didn't think
her performance was worthy,
but there was no precedent
for a horror film
being honored by the Academy for acting.
The fact they took it seriously
I think still is a real milestone.
(Winston) Interesting thing coming up.
Another shot that Jim stuck me with
but it's really kind of fun
is when we meet the queen alien.
This is gonna come much later.
She ends up back in the elevator shaft.
In fact, the elevator shaft is not nearly
big enough to hold the queen alien,
so only her front half is in the shaft.
The rest of her is sticking
out the back of the elevator on the set,
but you never really
think about it in the movie
when that elevator opens
and the queen comes out,
that she would never be able to fit in it.
And since 90 per cent of the queen
alien stuff in this movie is all full size,
we had to deal with the sets based on the reality
of her size and the reality of the sets.
I never forget Jim coming to me
when he first had written the screenplay.
He said "I've got this idea
for the queen alien."
"We'll get a couple of guys in a suit.
It'll have four arms.
We'll carry it on a crane arm."
"We'll have puppeteers working the legs." I'm
going "He's completely out of his mind."
Then a split second later
"No, it's Jim, so it probably'll work."
- (Hurd) Remember when we did it with the...
- (Winston) The garbage-bag test.
(Hurd) Exactly. Do it first and make sure
it works before you do the design.
(Winston) So we rented
a little crane behind my studio
and built a little body form for
two stunt men, ski poles for arms,
foam-core legs, rod puppets,
foam-core head,
and looked at it
and "You know what? It works."
(Hurd) Same with the power loader.
We did all that in foam core first
to make sure the concept worked.
Unfortunately, it was too heavy
and had to be supported by the crane.
(Winston) By the wires.
But you'd never know that in the movie.
(Hurd) No.
(Winston) The queen,
when she drops out of the dropship,
she's virtually a huge marionette,
and there are wires in the shot
and we never see 'em.
Wires on each of her legs, her entire body,
when she comes down out of it.
It's a 14-foot
hydraulically operated marionette.
I learned to have a great deal of respect
for second unit directors doing this movie
cos I had to shoot second unit,
small shots and big shots.
And to have to make sure
that every light and everything
was exactly the way Jim wanted it
so that it fit in seamlessly
makes you realize that that job,
which fortunately I haven't done
since working with Jim, is a rough job,
because it's not being creative, it's making
sure you're doing what the director wants.
(Carrie) It originally started that Sigourney
was supposed to have run into Paul Reiser
and he did a cocoon scene as well,
and she gave him a grenade.
And later on in the movie,
there's a part where it's a big old boom,
and it was supposed to have been
him setting off the grenade.
But obviously no one really knows any of
that because it was cut out of the movie.
(Paxton) I run into Sigourney once in a blue
moon at an airport lounge or something.
She's always great. She remembers
Louise's name, my wife's name.
- A very thoughtful woman.
- (Henriksen) Gracious.
(Paxton) She made this series what it is.
Without her, it just wouldn't be the same.
Also Ridley Scott and Jim, they both really
showed up loaded for bear on these films.
I've never followed the other movies.
I couldn't tell you much about...
(Henriksen) I thought Ridley was
doing the third and Jim the fourth.
(Paxton) That was David Fincher. I've
seen a lot of his movies and liked 'em.
(Henriksen) Yeah, he's great.
(Cameron) I personally installed Carrie
in this cos I wanted to make sure
it was done in a way that wouldn't hurt her
or create any discomfort.
So I'm smearing this gak all over her and
she looks up at me and says very quietly
"It should be illegal
for you to do this to little kids."
(laughs)
She was just winding me up.
She wasn't serious.
(Carrie) The cocoon was probably one of the
most horrendous scenes that I had to film.
There was a little hole and they made it
just big enough for me to crawl through.
It was all made out of fiberglass and l
couldn't actually even put my feet down.
I would sit in there for what seemed like
hours on end but I doubt it was.
I couldn't rest my feet on it in case it broke.
I couldn't do anything in case it broke.
We just had to keep replaying it
over and over again, and it took days.
When Sigourney
actually tears apart the cocoon,
because it was made out of fiberglass,
she tore her hands all up.
They were all bleeding and everything.
This was just not a fun scene to film.
It took forever.
(Winston) We also had to replicate
Carrie for this
because of all the shots
that Sigourney was gonna have to carry her.
(Hurd) And she was too heavy.
And it was also Sigourney's back.
(Winston) Exactly. So we built
a little replication of Carrie's body.
It was actually a really beautiful dummy
that she carries through much of the scene
after she saves her.
It's not enough to build
a 14-foot queen alien.
It's gotta have a head
that comes out of its helmet-like head.
This was a great shot.
This was a combination of miniature
and then we built the last part of the egg
sac and attached it to the full-sized queen.
This is all full size. This is full-size 14-foot
queen when we see her for the first time.
That's a big puppet.
And the extruding head.
We had to come up with
a new way of doing the teeth,
making them translucent rather than metal,
as with the alien warriors.
When Jim first came to me,
he had a painting of the queen alien.
Just like with The Terminator,
he had already had her designed.
I had some ideas and started doing
some drawings myself, one of the rear legs.
It ultimately ended up
being virtually Jim's original design.
I'll never forget the two of us
sitting on drawing boards at his house
where he would draw one part of her
and I'd draw the other part,
and it would be all coming together.
He's one of the most talented artists
I ever had working for me.
(Hurd laughs)
(Hurd) I think he remembers it
a little differently.
(Winston) You don't think he'd look at it
like that, as an employee of Stan Winston's?
(Hurd) I also love this sequence when
Ripley is communicating with the queen.
"See, I can wipe out your children."
(Winston) I shot that shot.
(Hurd) She wants the queen
to call off her warriors,
and when the queen doesn't,
she goes to town.
(Winston) Kill the eggs.
(McClung) Wasn't there a puppeteer
whose hand was dropping the egg?
(Robert) That was Nigel.
He would push it out.
It was on a plex rod underneath the egg.
Somebody was under the set to place it,
otherwise it would roll over and fall down.
(Dennis) My job was to take that egg
and shove it back in.
(Cameron) I know Sigourney still has
liberal guilt over this whole scene.
But this is the classic
cathartic purging with fire.
You purge the nightmare
by burning it out.
And the idea that this is the only way she's
ever gonna have psychological closure.
Not, by the way, a new idea in films.
And probably one that doesn't have a whole
lot of basis in real human psychology.
It feels right to the audience,
but if you're that traumatized,
it wouldn't help you that much.
But she sure unleashes
holy hell on these guys.
(Robert) We had a sharpshooter fire
a real bullet into the miniature egg sac.
(Dennis) This is a miniature.
That's a front projection shot.
A lot of smoke in the air tends to take
the edge off of it. lt was a bit heavy.
Obscuring the plate.
(Robert) There's a shot here
where the platform the queen is on,
there's a big explosion
when she tosses the weapons belt here,
and the queen, when it falls,
is actually quarter-scale miniature
in which we use a double-mirror setup.
We had a beam splitter in the foreground
reflecting large-scale fire
that was off to the right of the camera
and behind the puppet was another mirror
that was angled off to the left
where we had another very large-scale fire.
(Cameron) We had a full-size alien queen
and then we had this miniature one.
The miniature one flails a little bit.
The alien queen design could be created
so beautifully today with CG animation.
That didn't exist then,
so we had to figure out how to do it
with more conventional means,
so it's a bunraku puppet
more than anything.
(Robert) This electrical-charge effect
was footage we acquired
from Gene Warren from Fantasy II.
He had several hundred feet
he had shot for the first Terminatorfilm.
We needed that type
of generic lightning effects
and we had that film shipped over to us.
(Dennis) It was actually
tesla coil footage.
Give credit where credit's due.
(Hurd) Once again, just the subtle things,
like the countdown,
reminding the characters and the
audience that there's a ticking clock.
(Winston) The huge queen alien
comes round the corner here.
It's one of our tougher shots,
for her to come out around the corner
and see her right here, and looking at her.
Neat performance.
I'll never forget my first conversation
with Steven Spielberg about Jurassic Park
when he said to me
"You built a 14-foot alien, full-size."
"Why can't you do a dinosaur?"
Everything leads to something else.
The water weenie in Abyss
to the T-1 000 in T2.
(Hurd) Everything's R and D
for something you do later on.
(Winston) This is the shot.
The queen just thinking, looking.
A little cock of the head,
knows what she's gonna do.
(Hurd) "I got a plan. I'm not stupid."
(Winston) That woman can act.
(Cameron) The female computer voice that's
counting down is an intentional tie-in
to the first film, to create the same sense
of panic as the clock runs down.
And then this is what you expect to happen,
that Bishop completely betrays them.
But I think what you don't expect
is that he didn't,
that he turns out to be a good guy.
People always expect the worst of others,
never the best.
And so when a character
actually lives up to their promises,
and Bishop said he was gonna stay
and he did,
you don't expect it,
you don't see it coming.
This is a front-screen projection shot.
(Dennis) There's a dropship comes up
behind Ripley on this landing platform.
The element that we shot for that
was shot at high speed.
Because the camera's running
at such high speed,
the actual movement was so fast, it's almost
not possible to move an object that quickly.
(Winston) Look at this.
Big old queen inside that little elevator.
(Hurd) We'll just keep it dark inside.
(Winston) It's a black curtain at the
back of it that she's coming through.
(Dennis) You think it's all lost
and there it is.
It's hard to imagine how fast
that actually moved in real time.
(Robert) Any time the miniature
is supposed to be traveling fast,
it had to be traveling
three, four, five times as fast.
This down-view was extended
with mirrors on the stage floor.
It was not apparent in the shot with
the fireball coming up, the earlier cut,
as you see this set
continuing very far down,
but those are mirrors on the studio floor.
(Dennis) In addition to the pyro,
we used flashbulbs,
buried in the set, to give extra flashes.
(Hurd) This is another instance
where the score is so terrific as well.
When we were in the scoring stage, this
was the last cue that Jamie had finished.
And then there was no...
It was like "OK. And then what?"
"I didn't get around
to the last cue of the film."
And in a miraculous burst of creativity,
he generated the final cue overnight.
(Cameron) I didn't know how to work with
an orchestral composer when I made this.
I don't think James knew
how to work with directors that well.
I think he was a brilliant composer,
but he had a lot to learn and so did I.
By the way, that nuclear explosion
is a big light bulb.
Literally, a light bulb
covered with cotton.
We didn't have any budget for a big effect
there, so we just made something up.
But it didn't create problems
between us personalitywise
but I went to the scoring session
expecting to hear the movie,
and an orchestra started to play
stuff that didn't work.
The music was beautiful, but it didn't
work on a scene-by-scene basis.
I didn't know what to do.
There was no second round.
It was like "Here's your score."
And James went off to another film.
We wound up doing an awful lot
of music editing and moving stuff around.
He was never happy with the outcome even
though he got an Academy Award nomination
cos it didn't reflect what he had created,
and I didn't like the process.
So when we got together on Titanic, I said:
"What can we do
so that doesn't happen again?"
"Cos I like your music
and I want you to do this film."
So we worked out a methodology
by which we'd communicate better.
And that was a great experience,
by contrast.
(Winston) This is a great effect, of the
queen tail coming out through his body.
It's basically a soft tail
that we pulled with a monofilament.
And it works great.
You would never know it.
(McClung) Alec Gillis was throwing...
After Bishop was torn in half here,
you see his torso go one way,
the top part go the other way.
Alec would throw it and it would land
in these goofy, ridiculous positions.
(Winston) Setting up for this one shot
right here was two days of work,
to get that shot there.
(McClung) This shot of it landing
was shot over and over again.
(Robert) I remember seeing the dailies.
(McClung) The arms would land
behind its head.
It was one of those funny moments.
(Dennis) This sequence used a combination of
the full-size and the quarter-scale queen.
Where there was a lot of movement
across the floor, we'd use the miniature.
If it were in place or close-up,
we'd use the full-size.
(Winston) And this is the biggest marionette
in the history of motion pictures.
She is every technology we had.
She's rod puppet, she's hydraulic,
which was new to us, she's a breakthrough,
radio-controlled, wired and rod,
all in that one beast.
(Hurd) And seamlessly intercut.
(Winston) With this miniature puppet
of Doug's.
(Hurd) With a miniature puppet of Ripley.
This sequence in the fight between Ripley
and the power loader and the alien queen,
we used the movie cam which was able to
change the frame rate within one shot,
and were able to start
at 24 frames per second
and then go down
to 1 8 or 20 frames per second,
so that when the internal jaws came out,
they whipped out.
(Cameron) When you analyze this scene,
it's all just quick cuts.
The alien's hand is in one shot
and you see a bit of the head and the hand,
but it's just all done with puppeting.
I think it's actually good.
The intention today would be to do it with
computer graphics and see it more full-figure,
and I think seeing it in bits and pieces
is actually more powerful.
This was a hard shot. This is the
pylon rig. You can see it behind her.
It's like a long crane arm.
(Hurd) I remember seeing the film,
midnight screening on Hollywood Boulevard,
and that line brought the house down.
People stood up and cheered.
Probably the most gratifying moment
of my producing career
was their reaction to that shot.
(Cameron) When we screened this film,
we knew we had a hit.
The audience went crazy.
And it was an industry audience,
so they can go either way.
They'll either be very negative or they'll be
celebratory of a film they think is working.
Once again, you have a mixture of full-size
power loader and queen and miniature.
This is all pretty much full-size here,
which shows you how well-articulated
what Stan Winston's guys did.
(Robert) These shots of the power loader
taking big swings were quarter-scale shots.
That's the kind of action that would
have been very hard to stage successfully
with any kind of dynamics in full scale.
Thinking about it,
this looks like a heavyweight machine,
and it was actually just flimsy plastic.
(Dennis) You'd probably lift a lot of that
if it were in pieces.
(Robert) That whole arm, that claw
mechanism, only weighed a pound or so.
(McClung) It had some sort
of a counterweight,
cos so much weight
is pushed out forward.
You forget again that there was a bodybuilder
inside of there helping to manipulate it.
(Dennis) Basically, Sigourney was standing
on the fronts of his feet, as I recall.
And a quarter-scale version of the airlock
was also made, as well as the full-size,
so, depending on the shots,
the requirements,
you'd use one or the other.
(Cameron) Interesting that
we chose not to score this.
I just felt it had a
greater sense of reality
and it might seem a little over the top
if it was being driven by music,
whereas it plays very real,
somehow, without music.
I think the score cuts in
when the queen grabs her.
That lever's always right there that allows
you to depressure your entire spacecraft.
It's a bit like the button in the Krell lab
that blows up the planet
that you put in the children's
learning room.
(Hurd) And this is so terrific.
(Winston) We had a little trolley
underneath the set that he would ride on.
(Robert) The shot as the queen falls away
was done in miniature.
We had taken pieces of the set up to the
top of the stage and dropped them away.
We had people physically holding a large
sheet of black cloth, sort of fireman-style,
standing on the stage floor, and we dropped
these pieces from the top of the stage.
(Cameron) There's an
interesting thing here.
When Newt slides, Bishop, you see
his body, you see how the gag is done.
Lance is down through the set.
It shows you how people watch a movie.
They watch the hands,
whether he's gonna miss her,
and they don't see a bad visual effect that's
happening on the other side of the screen.
But I was watching it with an audience for
about the fifth time before I saw that myself,
cos I always looked
where I was supposed to look.
(McClung) The queen was stop-motion,
right, coming out of the Sulaco?
(Robert) The exterior shot of the queen
was, I think, puppeted bluescreen.
It's got a bit of a stop-motion quality,
but it's just...
(Dennis) The original thought
was to use stop motion in this film,
but the problems of time as well as
the kind of action that stop motion creates
is different than puppeted.
(Robert) There was also questions
about these slime elements.
The thing was always dripping and there was a
lot of real-time elements that were mixed in
that would have made it hard
to do a stop motion.
But, again, time was a factor and we had
to do a shot a day or every couple of days
and cover things with multiple cameras.
It would have been very impractical
to do it that way.
(Cameron) She recovers
from her traumatic event pretty quickly.
But she's been through a lot so she's
got used to this stuff by now, l guess.
I didn't think
it was appropriate to show Sigourney
in quite the same sexy underwear
she was in at the end of Alien,
I'm sure much to the fans'
disappointment.
(Paxton) It's a movie I'll always be proud
to have been a part of.
It's great to get together and revisit it
after so many years. It holds up.
- It was a great experience.
- (Goldstein) This was my first film.
- (Henriksen) Was that your first film too?
- Yeah. He gave me my first job.
It was amazing to step into that.
(Biehn) You do movies
and always have high hopes,
and it's only a few that turn out
as great as this one.
That's why it's so special.
(Paxton) I think at the time we knew
we had a great script, a great director,
who really knew how
to put this thing on film,
and there was a great camaraderie
amongst all of us.
It was great to have
this common purpose
and know we were making
a great science fiction classic.
There was no question in any of our minds
that we were involved with a great film.
We showed up on the set in London and to
see the stagecraft that they had done.
(Biehn) That's why when people talk to me
about working for Jim Cameron,
that's why it's so great to work with him,
cos you know you're in great hands.
There's a possibility that it's gonna be a
great, great movie, a really good possibility.
(Paxton) We've all had hits and misses
since, but it is a filmmaker's medium.
(Biehn) When you go into a movie like this, you
just give that extra, added whatever it is,
cos you know that there's a shot.
(Goldstein) It surprised me how it went
across lines of people
who love science fiction
but beyond that - you don't have to be a
science fiction genre buff to enjoy it at all,
or it wouldn't have
lasted as long as it has.
(Paxton) And what a challenge,
to be the director of the sequel to Alien,
which, like you were saying earlier, really
revolutionized science fiction films.
This was the first monster to come down the
pike that was so intricate and interesting
in the whole way it evolved, and the
Giger design of the original monster.
To be bold enough to go
"Yeah, I'll write and direct the sequel."
(Henriksen) Tough duty.
(Paxton) I don't think anybody else
could've pulled it off.
(Carrie) I had so much fun
on the Aliens experience.
- (Chris) A once-in-a-lifetime experience.
- (Carrie) Definitely.
Who can say that their name comes up
second in the credits?
Not very many people.
(Winston) Wow.
Did we actually make that movie?
(laughter)
- (Hurd) For 1 8 million dollars.
- (Winston) It wore me out watching it.
(Hurd) It was what? A 60-odd day shoot?
It was like a 65-day shoot.
(Winston) Very proud. We did good.
- (Hurd) Let's do it again.
- (Winston) Hats off to you, Jim.
The man kicks butt, doesn't he?
(Hurd) He's the maestro.
(Cameron) I think in terms
of actual technique,
it's crude compared to films made now.
But I think in terms of storytelling,
it's as good as I'll probably ever be,
which is really what
filmmaking is all about.
It's about the people,
it's about the relationships.
Of course, then they made the third film
and killed everybody.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH - COMMENTARY]