Jeremiah was a bullfrog...
Bullfrog
Was a good friend of mine
Never understood
a single word he said
But I helped him drink his wine
Oh my, my
Yes, he always had
some mighty fine wine
So fine
Singing joy to the world
Joy to the world
All the boys and girls
Joy to the fishes
in the deep blue sea
Joy to you and me
If I were the king of the world
King of the world
I tell you what I'd do
I'd throw away the cars
and the bars and the wars
And make sweet love to you
Sweet love
Singing joy to the world
Joy to the world
All the boys and girls
Joy to the fishes
in the deep blue sea
Joy to you and me...
Key chanre!
Joy to the world
All the boys and girls
Joy to you and me
You and me
Joy to the world
All the boys and girls
Joy to the fishes
in the deep blue sea
Joy to you and me...
Big ending!
Joy to you and me!
Have a very pleasant
summer everyone.
Ms. Fletcher, rehearsal tomorrow
at 4:00.
Oh, and I did send in that
recommendation you requested.
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Holcombe. Bye.
Are you actually
going tomorrow?
Call me a dork,
but I love choir practice.
And I don't want
to let him down.
All right, last day!
Hey, Terri, hey, Terri.
Hey, Matthew.
Hey.
I, uh, I got the concert tickets
that you wanted.
Oh, um,
I've got the money.
Awesome.
There you go.
So, um,
I'll see you
at rehearsal then.
Okay, cool.
See you then.
Okay.
Oh my God!
He's going to spend
the whole next month
hoping he didn't just
get you prernant.
Oh, shut up.
He's so nice.
Play it loud
Raise your voice
Shout it out
We weren't the first
But we're
holding our own...
As hordes of
summer-starved teenagers
descend on unsuspecting
Flagstaff, Arizona,
let's see what these two
poised younr women
have to say about
the last day of school!
I'm outta here, Riverdale!
Yeah, school's out, baby!
All right.
The camera loves you.
So, Lauren, what are
you doing tonight?
Paul, stop hitting
on my friend.
Whatever you're
doing tonight.
Lauren, stop hitting
on my brother. Urh!
Hey, would you tell Mom
I'll be late?
But it's your graduation
barbecue.
I've got places to go, people to see.
Just save me a burnt burrer.
Will you give me a ride home?
Sure.
Play it loud
Raise your voice
Shout it out
Play it loud
Raise your voice
Shout it out
Play it loud
Play it loud...
Thanks, Lauren.
Anytime.
Hey, I'll call you tomorrow.
Okay, have fun tonight.
Play it loud.
So, Terri Boo-berry,
what are you up to this summer?
I'm singing in choir.
Cool.
Yeah, and, um, I'm working
at the restaurant again.
Wow, what fun.
Yeah.
But mostly, I really want to get into
this music summer prorram in August.
Really, which one?
Some music thing in L.A.
Dad! Come on! It's not
just some music thing in L.A.
It's Bristol-Hillman
Music Conservatory.
Only the best summer music
prorram on the West Coast,
maybe even in the whole country.
Terri, don't start.
But Dad, this is
so important to me.
Plus, I already sent
in my application and I sent a CD
because Mom said I could.
That's it! You're not going!
Simon, don't be so closed-minded.
Nina, please.
Terri...
Where've you been?
Hanging out with some of the ruys.
Saying goodbye, that stuff.
Hey, Aunt Nina!
Happy graduation.
Thanks.
Here.
Oh here, I'll take it in.
Hey, what's wrong?
Terri just wants to go
to this great music prorram in L.A.
and your Dad's being his usual
squash-any-good-idea self.
Nina, the prettiest girls
from all the hirh schools go to L.A.
You know what happens
to most of them?
Dad, you don't think Terri's special?
Paul, seriously.
I think she's the most special
human being on the planet.
She's my girl.
That's why she's
not going to L.A.
She's 16, for God's sakes.
What's wrong with you people?
Hundreds of people
apply for this.
If she rets in, it's proof she belongs
there, but you get that, right?
Look, when I was your are,
I thought I knew everything too.
But I've seen a lot more of the world
than you have, Paul.
What parts of the world
have you seen, Dad?
The back and front
of your dad's restaurant?
Okay, okay.
Paul, that's enourh.
Well, just because you're stuck
here, you want everyone stuck with you.
You better watch your mouth
or you're gonna get rrounded.
All right, listen.
Can we please stop fighting?
It's a graduation party.
We're suppose to be celebrating here.
All right?
I can't get
these damn coals to light.
Oh, well here, try this.
What are you doing?
God. Stop. That's it!
You're rrounded! Get in the house.
I just love our family get-torethers.
Uh, I'll be back.
Always have.
So...
I never got a chance to tell you
congratulations on Arizona State.
Thanks.
At least I'm getting outta here.
Aunt Nina, if Terri rets
into that music prorram,
you gotta make sure
she goes.
She'll suffocate staying here.
Yeah, I know.
I was thinking
the same thing.
So you're on my side?
Always.
Hey.
What's going on?
Nothing.
Yeah, right.
There's a light in me
And it's shining bright
I can almost
touch the sky...
The sky.
You're the reason
I believe...
Hello, annoying.
Hey! Easy on the hardware.
What are you doing?
Filming America's most boring teenagers?
And I feel so strong...
Ladies and gentlemen,
tonight on "The Fletcher Experience,"
we have a special treat.
It's my sincere pleasure to present
to you the distinctive vocal stylings
of the one, the only,
Terri Fletcher!
Oh, well, Paul, that is
so very kind of you. Thank you.
This next song
I wrote for my fans.
Something's got
ahold of me
But I will follow
where you go
One more mile to Jericho
The walls will tumble
The walls will tumble--
The music fills the space
And it takes the pain away
And I know
it's gonna be all right.
When you're sad and lonely
Tell Him what you want
Hold Him up and tell Him
what you want.
'Cause I just can't wait
till you write me
You're coming around
Around
Now I'm walking
on sunshine, whoa-oh
And don't it feel good, hey!
Oh, yeah, now
And don't it feel good...
Oh--
Hey, what are you
doing here?
Um, uh...
With all the stuff
that went on this afternoon
I almost forrot to give you
your graduation present.
Three Days Grace?
Yes.
Oh my God! When?
It's tonight.
Oh, no.
Didn't you hear
I was rrounded?
Paul. Come on.
It's not like you never break the rules.
If you don't go,
I can't go either.
Please.
It's Three Days Grace.
Side window? Should we go?
Side window.
All right.
Quiet, quiet!
I can't believe
you sprunr me.
This is a first.
Well, who know when we'll ever
break the law again, right?
I'm not, uh, staying
in Flagstaff Terri.
I lined up a job in Phoenix
and I'm going straight to Arizona State.
I'm not coming back.
Just like that?
I mean...
It's time.
Dad and l...
need...
It's just time.
The only thing I feel bad
about is leaving you here.
No. You don't have to worry about me.
We get along okay.
Yeah, that's what
worries me.
It's more than getting along, Terri.
You please them.
You're like a Stepford daughter out
of a mail-order marazine.
Is that a form of flattery?
After Dad slammed you
on Bristol-Hillman,
you're going to tell me
that didn't hurt?
No, it totally hurt.
Then make a scene!
Break something! Scream!
I... something.
Huh-huh. Tantrums were
never my thing.
Terri, you've got the best
voice I've ever heard,
but if you hanr with the "World
According to Simon Fletcher" any longer,
you're going to be doing
"Cats" at the Y at 40.
And that would suck.
That would suck.
Home!
This house
is not a home...
Oh my God!
This house is not a home.
What's up, Flagstaff?
How you ruys doing, all right?
Yeah.
You said
we'd never get this far
You said your words
Words
We played our parts
Said your two cents
now it's my turn
So sit down, shut up,
are you ready?
So you think you know
How this story goes...
Little help?
Are you ready for this?
Paul, don't-oh my God.
Sit down!
Are you ready for this?
Shut up!
Stand up!
Are you ready for this?
This rame
Are you ready?
Are you ready for this?
Sit down
Shut up
Are you ready for this?
Stand straight!
Are you ready?
Paul, Look out!
Are you ready for this?
Oh! Thank God.
Paul?
No.
Healing nicely.
Still got that headache?
Can you tell me
your birthday?
April 20th.
Let's let Terri
get the next one.
Tell me what month it is.
June.
What's wrong with her?
Why can't she speak?
Terri, tell me what month
it is out loud.
It's June.
That's good.
Now follow this light
with your eyes.
Doc, stop!
Whatever you're doing, just stop.
I wish I was older.
I'm so afraid I'll say something stupid
and make it worse.
Hey, Aunt Nina.
Hi, Terri Boo-berry.
Honey.
Why was this in the trash?
You got in.
Congratulations.
Paul would be so proud of you.
Mom, what are you doing?
If Paul were here,
he would just get
in another screaming fight
with Dad about it.
Okay. Everything
is different now.
Do you still want to go?
I don't want to sing anymore.
I don't believe that,
Terri.
Why don't you let me
handle your Dad about this.
I think Terri should come visit me.
Hmm.
Simon, I really think
she needs to get away
and I'd like her to come to Palm Desert
for the month of August.
A month with you, alone in the desert?
Are you nuts?
It is alone, isn't it?
I'm between ruys right now.
So yes, I'm alone.
Yeah, for the moment.
Well who's going to help me
in the restaurant?
Oh, is that really what
you want to say, Simon?
"Who's gonna help me
with the restaurant?"
Aunt Nina, who said that
you could do that?
I've never lied
to my father before.
Terri, I just think
this is your life.
You deserve
the chance to live it.
Then why
does it feel so wrong?
There's something
about your dad
that I don't think
you know.
He and his friend David both got
football scholarships to UCLA.
Really?
And when graduation
rolled around,
our family restaurant
was doing good,
but our parents weren't.
Neither of us
wanted the restaurant,
but your Dad felt he had
no choice but to take it.
And, uh, his friend David
went on to UCLA.
And he got caught up
in the L.A. scene
and he's been messed up
ever since.
But I know
that if your Dad had taken
that scholarship,
he would have made it.
So, what does that
have to do with me?
I don't know.
Everything?
But it's
your decision, Terri.
He would have wanted
you to have this, honey.
Paul would have wanted
you to have this.
I shouldn't
have snuck him out.
Oh, honey,
it's not your fault,
it's not your fault.
I feel so bad all the time.
No.
I can't do this.
I can't go.
I can't lie to Dad.
It's just too soon.
Honey...
I will tell Dad that you're
really not at Nina's
when the time
is right.
And he's gonna be
mad at first.
But he's gonna realize
it was the right thing to do.
You sure it's the right thing to do?
No.
I'm not sure
of anything.
I just want
you to be happy.
Okay.
I'll do it.
Are you ruys
gonna be okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. We'll be fine.
Uh, I'm taking her
to the train station.
And, uh, Nina will pick her up
on the other end.
We'Il be fine.
Here you go. This is for you.
Dad.
I don't want Nina to pay
for everything, and uh...
You wanna come home early,
you call us, okay?
Okay. I love you.
Me too.
Call me, okay?
Okay.
I want you
to take this.
You just call us
whenever you want.
And make sure you conference
Aunt Nina in when you do,
'cause you know your father,
he's gonna want to talk to her
every once in a while. Okay?
Got it, Mom.
I love you.
Lift off, here I am,
here I go
Stand back,
I'm in control
I'm outta this world,
about to take off
And when I reach the stars,
I still won't stop
'Cause I'm about to rocket....
Hey!
Now it's five, four,
three, two, one, lift-off
Lift-off
Lift-off...
Ow.
I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it.
Thank you.
Sure.
Where did
my jacket go?
Welcome to L.A., baby.
Hop in.
It's rone.
Lift off,
hey you
Get used to my face
I'll be taking
over this place
'Cause the ride has been
A little off track
From now on
I'm on the straightest path
Got that look in my eye
Got my head in the sky,
bye-bye
I'm outta this world
About to take off
And when I reach the stars,
I still won't stop
'Cause I'm about to rocket
all the way to the top
Now it's five, four,
three, two, one
Lift off.
Oh, come on.
Hello?
Hey! Is anyone there?
Oh-hh--
you've got to be kidding me.
Hello!
Sorry, full up.
Hey!
Look. Are you going to make
a habit out of this?
Okay. It's late
and I'm tired
and all I want to do
is get up to my dorm. Okay?
What's the password?
Okay. I think we started off
on the wrong foot.
I'm Terri.
Jay.
It's "monkeys"
by the way.
The password.
Mm-hm.
What room?
Um...
315.
Jay.
There you are.
Send you out for a snack
and you bring home a stray. Shame.
Mmm.
Hey. I'm Terri.
Uh-huh.
I'll catch you later.
Bye.
You know what?
I think I've got it from here. Thanks.
See ya.
Whew.
What?
What was that about? What did I say?
I'm seriously...
315.
Oh.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Hey. I'm Terri,
your new roommate.
Great. And I thought
I had this place to myself.
Now turn out the damn light!
Sorry.
Oh my rosh.
Okay. Okay.
Terri?
Hey. It's me.
Oh, thank God, Terri.
Your dad's called twice already.
Well, the train was late
and my jacket got stolen
and the cab driver was a total jerk.
Are you okay?
I'm fine. Let's just conference
Dad in, okay?
Okay.
Here goes nothing.
Here we go.
Hey. Are you there?
Yeah.
I'm still here.
Theresa, is that you?
Hey, yeah, Dad. It's me.
Is Mom there too?
Yeah, yeah.
She's just
getting on the exchanre--
Hey, honey!
What took you so long?
We've been waiting
for you to call for like four hours.
We're sorry, Simon.
Her train was late.
Oh. Well.
What are you two ladies going
to do on your first big night?
We're watching television.
We're just eating dinner.
What?
eating dinner.
We're watching television.
Which is it?
We're eating dinner
while we're watching television.
right.
I thought you didn't have
a television, Nina.
I thought that was against
your artistic sensibilities.
Oh, well, I-I-I finally
gave in. Sue me.
Uh-uh, it's okay as long as you're safe.
Are you safe, honey?
Yeah. I'm fine.
I'm just totally wiped out.
Now you get some rest.
Call us tomorrow.
And Nina?
Yes?
Don't corrupt my baby.
She's too much
like you already.
Don't worry, Simon.
I'll have her tattooed, with blue hair,
and married to a rapper in no time.
nighty-night.
Good night, Nina.
Night, Theresa.
Good night, Mom.
Good night, Dad. I love you.
Bye-bye.
I love you.
I think that worked.
I think I did it.
Well, Paul,
I'm here.
I hope you're happy.
Hi.
I'm Terri, your roommate.
Yeah. Denise.
Okay, everyone.
Take a seat.
Let's be seated.
In case you bought
that old saw
that those who can't do, teach.
These talented musicians
beside me are your teachers.
But I'd prefer you
to think of them as your ruides.
Hello, and welcome to Bristol-Hillman's
summer music prorram.
I'd like to start
by reminding you
of the larre number
of talented students who applied
but did not get in.
Now,
this summer is not just about
learning your craft.
It's about
testing your limits.
Experimenting.
New experiences. It's about
building up and rocking
the foundation of that
which will give you
your own individual voice.
Now, some basics.
We have a strict 10:00 curfew,
1 1 :00 on the weekends.
Possession of banned substances
will mean immediate dismissal.
Hmm.
This is L.A., people.
Use some common sense.
Travel in pairs.
Lastly, the scholarship.
Three weeks from now,
on the last day of the prorram,
we will have
final performances
where you show us
what you've got.
Now a lucky student will win a $10,000
academic scholarship
for music study.
That's pretty good, huh?
So, work hard.
Have fun.
Get lost.
Later.
Okay.
I gave her three chances.
The chances have come and rone.
Send her back
where she came from.
I don't care!
People, rrab a seat.
My name is Mr. Torvald.
You are my class
and we have three weeks
to learn an incredibly
complex choral piece.
It ain't ever gonna happen,
but let's give it the ol'
collere try, shall we?
There are five solos
in the ensemble.
Only five people will perform solos
in front of this class.
And I will hand them out
in two weeks
based on participation,
exercises
and je nai sais quoi.
If you're not French,
that means,
"Ooh!"
I will also split you up
into rroups of four.
Yes, I still count
on my fingers.
One for each part
in the obnoxiously difficult
contrapuntal harmony
at the end of the book.
This piece is gonna
drive you nuts.
But when you nail it,
it feels good.
You.
You. You.
You. Group one!
Hey, Jay!
Nice hook.
Jump in and pick it up.
Ooh-ooh-ooh, Ooh-ooh-ooh,
yeah...
Ooh-ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh...
ooh-ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh-ooh, yeah
Ooh-ooh-ooh...
Hey.
Is anybody sitting here?
Ooh-ooh-ooh...
Yeah...
Yeah, baby...#
Hey, baby
ta-da-da-da-da...
Ta-da-da da-da dee
Ooh-ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh-ooh, yeah
Yeah, ooh-ooh-ooh
Ooh-ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh
Ooh-hh...#
How many of you
can identify this note?
You there.
What is the note?
A "B?"
B flat!
The ability to know any note when
you hear it is great asset.
Those of you who don't have it must work
that much harder.
Is the same with your
ability to read music.
Your opportunities
are expanded.
If you look
at a piece of music,
see how the notes
are arranred on the pare
and hear exactly
what it is,
each note in your head.
This is something you will
learn to do this summer
in your individual studies
with me.
I'm so sorry. That was me.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm-I'm fine.
I'm sorry. That was my fault.
I was in the way.
No, it's good. It was my fault.
I should really learn to stand.
Okay.
Awesome.
She doesn't even know.
Hey. How's it going?
Couldn't be better.
Should I ask for a single?
Am I bothering you that much?
Hey. Hold up.
I mean, I just get the feeling that
I'm some kinda pain in your butt.
Look, it's not even
like that, all right?
I'm here for that scholarship.
I'm just about hardcore focus.
Well it seems really personal.
Oh, please.
I'm not even trying to hear that.
Look, we're all up against
each other for that money.
So I just gotta be able
to do my thing
and not get caught up
in any personalities.
I don't really mean
nothing by it.
So, we cool?
Yeah. We're cool.
Cool.
Hey, Mr. Torvald.
Hey, Robin.
I wanted to let you know that I tried
those exercises you gave me last summer
and they really helped.
I just wanted to say thank you so much.
My pleasure.
Oh, and I'll have you know
that I'm running for those solos.
Well, I'll keep an eye out for you.
Thank you, Mr. Torvald.
For the Lord God
Omnipotent reirneth
Hallelujah,
hallelujah
Hallelujah, hallelujah
For the Lord God
Omnipotent reirneth
Hallelujah,
hallelujah
Hallelujah, Hallelujah.
Ouch and cut.
Sorry, that was me.
Yeah, we know.
And you are?
Terri Fletcher.
thought I recornized you.
The girl from the DVD.
Terri Fletcher,
the thing is
the theme emerres
from the harmony.
Give me you hand.
Whack!
None of you follow it directly.
Capice?
Good job, Robin.
Whoo-ee!
Okay, let's do it again.
One, two, three, four.
For the Lord God
Omnipotent reirneth
Hallelujah,
hallelujah, hallelujah.
Oh.
Sorry, Mr. Wesson.
I was-I forrot my books at the--
Is your time
that was wasted.
Please go to the stand.
Please sight-read
the first pare.
Ca? Ca...
Support.
Support with your diaphrarm.
Air goes in.
Diaphrarm goes out.
Is okay to look fat.
Sorry.
Hey.
What's up?
She doesn't,
she doesn't know
She doesn't--
she doesn't, she doesn't
She doesn't even know,
know, know
She-she doesn't
even know, know, know, know
Oh!
Thanks anyways.
You're a serious weirdo.
You know that?
It isn't lucky
unless it's face up.
But now it's just a penny
that thinks it's lucky, but it isn't.
Well now it can be lucky
for someone else.
Besides, haven't you ever heard
of making your own luck?
Well, what do you know?
A lucky penny.
So, an Enrlishman in L.A.
Yeah, my parents put an ocean between
them after the nastiest divorce ever.
No joke, people study it.
So, how can you have
a sense of humor about that?
My music became
like a relirion.
It kept me sane.
So, music is your
hirher power.
Pretty much.
I mean, look at this.
This city.
All these people.
All this life
and music.
I'm gonna make music
for them.
I can't think
of a better way to spend my life.
Are you missing home?
A little bit.
I don't know. It's just been really
tourh lately.
Come on.
I just gave you my
"E! True Hollywood Story."
You gotta
give me something.
Um.
Me and my brother
were in a car accident
on the day of his graduation.
And, um,
some drunk driver ran
throurh a red light and--
Hey, Terri!
Come here.
Uh, look, Terri,
I've gotta go.
I've gotta meet
somebody.
Look, say hi
to Denise for me.
Hey.
Hey, was that Jay running off?
Yeah.
Firures. What, was he macking on you?
Not that I could tell.
Well, count your blessings,
'cause I know his rame.
He likes to hit
on nice girls.
And baby, you--
you got a lock on that one.
What?
I mean, look at you.
Look at your hair, your clothes,
the way you talk.
You're like some kinda
retro Brady Buncher.
Shoot, I'm not even
trying to hear that.
Okay, that was cute.
My bad.
I didn't know
you could do this.
Yeah. My teachers are always harping
about how it's bad for me.
You know, how I'm gonna lose my ear.
But I just like how it sounds in here.
Hello.
Oh hi, honey.
Um, Dad wants
to talk to you.
Um, Simon, pick up.
Hey, sweetheart.
How's it going?
Hanging in there?
Yeah, everything's good.
Sure do miss you.
I miss you too, Dad.
What was that? Sounded like a siren.
Uh, no, no. It's nothing.
Well, it didn't sound like nothing.
It sounded pretty close.
The neirhbors are out of town
and their alarm keeps going off
so, I'm gonna go talk
to the police, okay?
I'll call you back. All right, bye.
Okay, bye, honey.
Uh, what, Terri, wait.
Terri?
I'm gonna lose it.
King of Kings
Forever and ever
Hallelujah, hallelujah
And Lord of Lords
Forever and ever
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Yes.
King of Kings
Forever and ever
Hallelujah, hallelujah
And Lord of Lords...
I can never get that note.
I can't believe this.
I can.
Problem, ladies?
Yeah, I think that some of us maybe need
to practice this
a little bit more outside of class.
Meow!
Why don't you let me
worry about that, hmm?
Okay, that's it.
Done for the day.
Go on.
Get outta here.
Ms. Fletcher.
Okay, I give up.
What did you do
with the girl on the DVD?
Excuse me?
The lively, funny, talented girl,
what did you do with her?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
I sent my songs on a CD.
No, there was also a DVD.
It came in late.
We almost didn't see it.
But it's a big part
of the reason why you are here.
Sit down.
Be comfortable.
Okay, Mr. Torvald.
I did not send it.
I really have no idea
what you're talking about.
No? Well.
Let me introduce you
to one interesting, fascinating lady.
Maybe you'll be inspired.
I know we were.
Terri's my sister. And, uh, she's my
favorite person in the whole world.
She like a challenre.
She thrives when she's pushed.
And the people
who can do that,
they don't live
in Flagstaff.
Terri deserves a chance
to learn from the best.
She's already good.
But she could be great.
If you let her in,
you won't be disappointed.
Hey, Terri?
Terri!
Terri.
Are you okay?
Please. It's probably just some
weirdo misfit thing.
No.
The show's over.
Okay, you can go now.
Look, whatever it is,
you can't leave.
It's copping out.
What are you doing here?
Same as everybody else.
The music thing.
Ducking a summer job.
I mean here in my doorway.
Look, come on.
Let's just get outta here.
Come on.
Let's just go.
The bar isn't walking away.
How do I know you won't?
I was sitting
right next to him.
And I don't know why.
But I miss him.
The second I start to feel
like I'm enjoying myself,
this voice comes
inside my head and...
it's like,
"How can you be having
a good time when Paul is dead?"
You can't blame
yourself like that.
You don't understand.
It was my fault.
I got him to sneak out.
I shouldn't
have risked it.
Look, Terri.
Some idiot ran a red light.
It was bad luck.
Messed up timing.
That's all.
You weren't there.
Look, I can't imarine
what you're going throurh.
But I do know
from experience
backing down can
become a way of life.
Don't leave.
Screw the pressure.
Screw the scholarship.
I mean, do your own thing
on your own terms.
And get what
you came here for.
That's what counts.
But Jay, I'm lying to people.
I mean, I had to lie
to get here.
So what.
You got here.
It's not
suppose to be easy.
You're here because you did
what you had to do.
Why do you care
so much?
I don't know.
I like you.
And Robin fits
into that, how?
We met here
last year and...
we had a thing
for a while.
That's all over.
Does she know that?
Yeah, well...
some people hanr on
when they should
just let go.
La-la-la-la-
la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
La-la.
Thank you.
Okay, I'm not doing this
to torture you people.
Just think of this
as a midterm worth,
oh, half your rrade.
Ms. Fletcher?
Please?
La-la-la-la-la
La-la-
la-la-la
La-la-la-la-la...
La-la-la-la-la-la
Ha-ho
O-o-o-o
O-a-a-a-a-a
O-o-o-o-o-o
Hey-a-a-a
yeah-e-a
Yeah!
That was great.
All right, you take the top
of the fourth.
Awesome.
I was talking to Terri. Bing!
Okay, let's take
the third part from the top.
Is everybody ready?
One, two, three, four
Hallelujah,
hallelujah
Hallelujah, hallelujah
Hallelujah.
Hey.
What's this?
I think maybe Giordanni
is not for you.
We try something
else, hmm?
You know, I appreciate
the thought, Mr. Wesson,
but, you know, I'd really like to stick
to the old one.
I'm feeling much better today
and I wanna see if I can keep it up.
Thanks.
Hmm.
You and me
Can't you see
How our hearts are one?
Wha--
What are you doing here?
Oh, uh...
just...
the door was open.
I just heard you playing.
Oh, don't stop.
No, it's, um,
it's okay.
I was, um,
I was finished anyway.
Whatever.
Terri, wait.
I'm sorry, I'm just...
a bit weird
when I'm writing.
Why?
Well...
I-it's just my lyrics.
They're really lame.
I mean, when I sing them.
And I want them to mean
so much more, but--
Well, I've been writing songs
since I was a kid.
But my arrangements sound like
some cheesy Saturday morning
cartoon or something.
Play something for me.
Oh, um.
It's not ready yet.
Come on, whatever happened to that...
"You've got to do your own thing
on your own terms"
junk that you gave
me the other day?
Come on.
Okay.
You and me
can't you see
How our hearts
are one?
Please believe
And don't deceive
Now our journey's
just berun
The sunlight
in your hair
Makes my heart jump
in the air...
Come on.
Okay, wait.
I like the music a lot.
Yeah?
Okay? But what about this?
Yeah, I like that.
Okay?
It's very cool.
When it comes to rap,
you don't even write your stuff
Yeah you make tracks
but I make twice as much.
Oh, spring, when a younr
man's fancy turns to love.
Did you ruys see that?
What?
Oh, it's weird 'cause
there's a hole in my chest
where my heart used to be
'cause someone else
yanked it out and she doesn't even
frirrin' care that she did it.
Are you talking about the girl in
the black sweatshirt?
Dude, she's the hottest
player here.
I heard her in the practice
rooms and she's flawless.
Well, she looked at me
and I just...
oh, man, snap.
Friend, you're hooked.
Hopelessly.
Have you ever even talked to her?
No, I'm working on that.
See, the problem is she won't give
me the time of day.
Well, why don't l
introduce you ruys?
What if I told you
you were the coolest girl ever?
Jay, I like this girl.
You know how to pick them.
I've always said that, haven't I, Jay?
Yeah, he has always said that.
Kiwi seal of approval.
Hi.
Hey, I'm Terri.
Sorry to bother you.
Your name?
Sloane.
I-I know we don't have
any classes torether or anything, but...
um, I just thought
that I'd introduce myself.
Okay.
Okay, so there's
this ruy, right?
And, um, he's really nice
and his name's Kiwi
and he kinda has a crush on you.
So we were wondering
if you wanted to come
hanr out with us on Saturday night?
Kiwi's a weird name.
Why would he have a crush on me?
That's stupid.
Um, I mean, sometimes there's just
nothing you can do about it.
Well, anyway, um, we're gonna meet
in the lobby at 7:00
and, um, we're gonna rrab
a bite to eat, okay?
I ruess.
Great.
Okay.
Really good.
It's kinda weird talking.
Okay, you think and throw it at.
But then, yeah.
You're in.
You beautiful
little petunia.
You-ah! Ah, sacre bleu! Ah!
I got you, man.
Okay, girl.
So talk to me
Now it's you and Jay?
Yeah, kind of.
I mean,
he's really cool.
And what about Robin,
Ms. thing?
He says they're over.
Yeah, right.
That's really cute.
Oh, you like this?
Yeah.
My mom, she runs this funky
little clothing shop.
She's got great taste.
Really?
Yeah, I just wish business
was better thourh, you know?
I mean, even with me working part-time
barring groceries, and you know,
doing what I can
street performing,
we still had crazy trouble
scrapping up the tuition.
I mean, why do you think I'm stressing
that scholarship?
Hey, come here
for a second.
I want you to see
what this looks like.
Really?
Yeah, come on.
You forced me.
Oh yeah, that's fresh.
Oh, do I look like I'm going clubbing?
Oh my God.
Hey, Aunt Nina.
Terri, thank God I reached you!
Your dad called,
I did my thing.
I think he smells a rat.
I don't know how, I don't know why.
But your mother just called
and said he is on his way here, now!
I'll stall him as best I can but is
there any way you can just get here?
Oh my God.
We're dead.
I'm dead.
Hey, Jay!
Okay, thanks.
Good luck, Terri.
I'll see you
tomorrow night, all right?
The desert train is now
boarding on platform 1 2.
We're getting a little break
from the 100-plus temperatures
here in the greater
Palm Springs area.
Wind's out of the northeast
at six miles per hour.
Hey.
Hey, Nina.
Where is she?
Ah, well, um...
there's something
I wanted to talk to you about, Simon.
Oh yeah.
Yeah, um--
Daddy!
I missed you.
Oh, I missed you too.
I need a drink.
Sorry.
They're not coming, man.
I'm telling you.
They're not showing up.
No way. Look,
women are always
fashionably late.
They'll be here.
Okay, they'll be here.
Dude.
Thanks, man.
No, no, no, dude.
Damn it.
No, no, wait, wait, wait!
Don't walk away.
Hey, you ruys,
I'm sorry I'm late.
Hey, Sloane,
you look great.
Yeah.
Come on, let's go.
Um, I think
you should-cool.
No, seriously. I had to pretend to my
dad like I had been there
the whole entire time, and meanwhile
my aunt was remodeling her house,
so when I went to go find the bathroom,
I walked into a closet.
No way.
Yes way.
Yeah, you know, we all
thought you were like some
goody-two-shoes,
but you're like a furitive from the law.
Speaking of which, furitive,
where are you leading us to?
You'll see.
She's good.
Beyond, man.
This one, okay?
You got a smile
so bright
You know you could
have been a candle
I'm holding
you so tight...
Come on you ruys.
Come on.
She's not serious.
No, no, no.
The way you swept me off my feet
You know you could
have been some perfume
Well you could have been
anything that you wanted to
And I could tell
The way you do
the things you do
The way you do the things
you do
The way you do
the things you do
And as pretty as you are
You know you could
have been a flower...
I like to come up here
sometimes to think.
This is really cool.
I love it up here.
Wish I had a place
to think like this.
Well, you play
your cards right,
maybe I'll share
with you.
Maybe?
Maybe.
Depends on what you
come up here to think about.
Stuff.
My dreams.
Music.
The future.
If I have one.
Come on.
Too fast?
Not ready.
Well... cool.
I mean I like you.
A lot.
Yeah, I like you too.
I was thinking of that song
we were working on the other day.
Um-hmm.
I think we should do it for our final
performance piece.
You sing.
I'll play.
We could split
the scholarship
and we could write something
really meaningful.
Okay?
Deal.
Do you want
to try that again?
What?
Something in the way
you throw your hair
Back over your shoulder
Something in the way
you smile
When you're looking
my way
I've got no concerns
The days are long
and the nights get colder
Because it's this
I've got to try
On you, honey
I ain't never wishin'
for the chanre
In my condition
I'm not rich
but I know
That the sun
will shine for me
Ride with me
Won't you take
a ride with me?
Let's go, let's go!
Hey, it's open mic night, ruys.
Boo!
You suck!
Tourh crowd.
Yeah.
Tell me about it.
I'm gonna go see if we can get onto
the list to perform.
What?
Jay, no.
Hey look, we can practice forever,
but sooner or later
we're gonna
have to do it.
We gotta get out of here.
Hey-ey.
All right,
all right.
Stanley Wilson,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let's give a big hand
to Stanley Wilson.
Why are you here?!
You suck, man!
Good job.
I'm so nervous.
Well, look, just--
picture the audience naked.
Okay, bad idea.
All right, next up,
we have Terri and Jay.
Now, it is their first time
here at the Blue Moon,
so let's give them a warm welcome.
Terri and Jay, everyone.
There's a light in me
And--
Let me start over.
Come on, sing something!
There's a light in me
Hey, turn around.
And it's shine--
Look, it's okay.
Turn around.
Sorry.
There's a light in me
And it's shine--
shine
I can't help--
Paul!
Terri! Terri!
Terri, wait, wait!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
I saw--
I just wasn't ready.
I-I was gonna wait.
But, um,
this is for you.
Paul's cross.
The kingdom
of this world
He is become
The kingdom of our Lord
And of His Christ...
And of His Christ.
Good. Nice.
Improving.
We've got 10 minutes left.
I want to run the third section.
Has anybody seen Terri?
I can sing the part, Mr. Torvald, I know
it backwards and forwards.
It's Terri's solo,
so lets wait for her.
But she's not even here. And it's not
like she can sing it anyway.
Terri's worked hard for it.
She deserves it.
No, I deserve this part!
Stop it. Jeez.
Ha-ha.
Well I ruess you have
a new favorite now!
Hey.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa.
What's wrong?
I don't understand.
I don't-I don't see how things can
just go from being so great
one summer to turn
to such crap the next.
I'm sorry, Robin.
Can we talk?
I mean, privately?
Hey, Mr. Torvald.
I'm sorry I missed class.
Well, that's okay.
Are you feeling better?
What?
If you missed my class,
you must be deathly ill.
It's too bad because we were gonna
work on your solo today.
I'm not ready for a solo.
Yes, you are.
Don't you even know how much you've
improved since you've been here?
Okay, but there are much better singers
here, Mr. Torvald.
I'll be the judre of that.
We'll try it again tomorrow.
Look, Terri,
there's people in the class who are
desperate to do this solo,
so if you don't care
about the work,
what have you
been doing here?
This is so humiliating.
You're suppose to be with me.
Look, just--
take it easy.
Worse things
have happened, right?
Yeah, all the time.
Just not to me.
I always get my way.
Is that a bad thing to say?
Well, maybe a little, yeah.
But I thought you liked bad.
Maybe a little bad?
Come on, we got along
really well last summer, didn't we?
People chanre, Robin.
I'm not the same person
I was last summer.
Neither are you.
I don't know.
I think we can be those two people
again. Don't you?
Hey, have you seen Jay?
Uh, heading to the practice room,
I think.
I think I know the problem.
I'm bad.
But I can be better.
Terri, wait!
Terri!
Wait.
Jerk!
Terri!
Jay?
Stay away from me! Terri!
Stupid.
I don't know your face
No more
Or feel the touch
That I adore
I don't know your face
No more
It's just a place
I'm looking for...
Terri, come on, please.
She doesn't want to talk to you.
Just back off.
We might as well
be living
In another town
We might as well
We might
as well
We might as well
Be stranrers...
Be stranrers
For all I know
Of you now
For all I know.
Aw, hey.
You okay?
It's nothing.
I'm sorry if I was hard
on you the other day.
I just want you to know
that I'm here for you
if you need anything.
If you want to talk. Anything.
Okay?
Have you ever lost anyone?
Yeah.
I just can't let this go.
Well, you're an artist
and artists
feel things differently
than rerular people.
Look at Patsy Cline or
Billie Holiday.
You could hear it in their voice.
Or,
Vincent van Gorh. Cut off his ear,
but hey, he could paint.
Vincent van Gorh
killed himself.
That's right.
That's a bad example.
Hey, I'm a music teacher,
not a shrink.
What do you want?
I ruess...
what I'm trying to say
is artists convey emotion.
They make an audience feel
what they're feeling.
You know, that's
what it's all about, right?
You just have to find a way
to take what's in here
and put it in here.
What the hell. Who is it?
It's Jay.
Let me in!
Go away, you jackass!
No, no, no!
I just-please, I just want
to talk to Terri, okay?
Just let me in.
He sounds drunk.
Uh, you think?
Hey, girl,
do not open that door.
Okay, I'm gonna make
him leave, all right?
Jay, you have to leave now.
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay?
No!
Ow!
That hurt a lot.
Shh.
No, it's not what you think.
What's going on?!
I saw you kissing her, okay?
No, no.
Shut up!
You shut up!
Come on, Terri.
I'm trying to sleep.
Sh-I wasn't kissing her.
She was-she was kissing me.
Oh no. He didn't even try
to go there, please.
I'm sure that makes
a lot of sense, Jay,
when you're drunk.
Terri,
I don't care about her.
I care about you.
Boy, who you trying to play?
Terri?
Denise, just chill out, all right?
Look, Terri,
I care about you.
You know I do.
Why would you do that?
Why would you drink?
Because, because I'm--
I'm worthless.
You know what? Don't even try and give
me that self-pity thing, okay?
Terri, look.
Y'all need to relocate.
Okay, well, I'm never going to get him
past the night ruard, so you--
I'll be fine. I'll just--
You have--
You have to help me
get him up to the roof.
This is too much
drama for me.
Shh-hh.
I'm fine.
You're not fine, okay?
Oh wow!
I love this roof!
It's so cool.
Whoo!
Oh, his breath is nasty.
Oh!
I'm spinning.
Help him!
Oh my God.
I'm out.
Thank you.
What did you do?
I don't feel so good.
I'm sure you don't.
In a moment
Everything can chanre
Feel the wind
on your shoulder
For a minute
All the world can wait
Let go of your yesterday
Wake up.
Can you hear it calling?
Can you feel it
in your soul?
Can you trust this longing
Wake up, it's a new day.
And take control?
Fly
Open up the part of you
'Cause it's your time
Time to fly...
I'm really sorry.
Save it.
You're not forgiven yet.
Come on, let's go.
In a moment
Everything can chanre.
Frances!
Do you have the car keys?
Frances?
Car keys?
So I wrote some new lyrics
and now all we have to do is practice,
so we can pull this off.
right.
Here's the music.
Okay, well,
let's start here.
I wanna work on the bridre.
Okay.
It doesn't matter
what people say
And it doesn't matter
how long it takes
Believe in yourself
and you'll fly--
Okay.
It's not-let's, um, go again
and try it a little faster.
Okay.
It doesn't--
Stop.
Okay, for real this time.
Let's go.
It doesn't matter
what people say--
It sounded fine
the first time.
Okay, but "fine" is not going to win us
the scholarship.
Okay, it's gotta be right.
And I'm not gonna give up
until I nail it.
It'll drive me nuts.
It doesn't matter--
it doesn't matter
It doesn't matter
how long it takes
Believe in yourself
and you'll fly hirh.
What?
You did what?
She got accepted, Simon.
Out of all the applicants
in America,
our Terri got in.
You mean she's been there
this whole time?
Did you hear me?
You-you lied to me?
Did you hear? Our daughter...
You and Nina?
got into the best
music school in the country.
All of you lied to me.
All of you.
But Terri wanted to go.
Paul wanted her to go.
Paul!
Terri's singing again.
Why doesn't this matter to you?
What in God's name
is wrong with you, Frances?
What's wrong with me?
We just lost our son.
We were losing the only
child we have left.
I'm not gonna let
that happen.
That's my point.
She's just a child.
She's our child.
And how can I protect her
if she's not here?
I want her home.
I want her home now.
Will you shut up in here?!
You are the loudest,
noisiest, rudest jerk on the planet!
Oh, ow!
Sorry.
Thank you.
Thank you and welcome.
Well, it's time to bring
things to a close.
It's been great fun and we have even
more in store for you.
Today we have a full slate
of final performances.
And some of our performers
will be backed up by members
of the Bristol-Hillman
House Band.
Oh my God!
What?
I don't have Paul's necklace.
No, I can't do this
without him.
Terri? Terri, wait.
No, uh, don't worry. I'll be back.
And give a hand to our first performer,
Miss Robin Childers.
All right!
Yeah!
Let your body move
on the dance floor
Feel the rhythm
as your body rets warm...
Dad?
Pack your things, Terri.
Let's go home.
Daddy, no!
Not a word, Theresa.
Just do it.
Your mother's waiting
downstairs.
Uh-uh--
Just as you head
is spinning
As you slowly start
to lose control.
Go, Robin!
Thank you.
Great performance!
Our next performer
is Mr. Enrelbert Wilson.
Enrelbert?
Come on out, boy!
Kiwi!
Did you hear what I said?
Pack your things.
Dad, you know what? You did this to Paul
and now you're doing this to me.
Don't you dare
bring Paul into this.
Okay, well, I'm not gonna
let you hold me back.
You lied to me, Terri.
And I'm sorry about that.
But I did what
I had to do.
Okay, you don't listen
to anybody, and we're all afraid of you.
She doesn't even know!
She wants the creature
from outer space
Gentlemen
Time is running out.
Dad...
this place is the scariest,
hardest
best thing that has ever
happened to me,
no matter how I got here.
We'll discuss it at home.
I'm not leaving.
Okay, I did this
and I did this for me and I'm gonna
finish it for me.
You can take me home
if you want to, Dad.
But I'm performing
any minute now,
and it would mean the world to me if you
and Mom were there to support me.
I worked so hard here.
And I'm really good.
I want you to hear me.
Please, Dad.
Please, let me stay.
All right, Denise!
Yes!
Yes, that was
wonderful, Denise.
Nice job, Denise!
Thanks.
You were great, girl!
And now last,
but not least,
Theresa Fletcher
and Jay Corran.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm sorry to announce--
it is my sincere pleasure
to present to you the distinctive vocal
stylings of the one,
the only,
Terri Fletcher!
Um--
this song Jay
and I wrote torether,
and, um, I would
like to dedicate it
to my brother,
Paul Fletcher.
I found myself today
Oh I found myself
and ran away
But something
pulled me back
The voice of reason,
I forrot I had
All I know
is you're not here to say
What you always
used to say
But it's written
in the sky tonight
So I won't give up
No, I won't break down
Sooner than it seems
life turns around
And I will be strong
even if it all goes wrong
When I'm standing in the dark,
I'll still believe
Someone's watching over me
I've seen
that bright light
And it's shining
on my destiny
Shining all the time,
and I won't be afraid
To follow everywhere
it's taking me
All I know
is yesterday is rone
And right now
I belong
To this moment,
to my dreams
So I won't give up
No, I won't break down
Sooner then it seems
life turns around
And I will be strong
even if it all goes wrong
When I'm standing in the dark,
I'll still believe
Someone's watching over me
It doesn't matter
what people say
And it doesn't matter
how long it takes
Believe in yourself
and you'll fly hirh
And it only matters
how true you are
Be true to yourself
and follow your heart
So I won't give up
No, I won't break down
Sooner than it seems
life turns around
And I will be strong
even if it all goes wrong
When I'm standing in the dark,
I'll still believe
That I won't give up
No, I won't break down
Sooner than it seems
life turns around
And I will be strong
even when it all goes wrong
When I'm standing in the dark,
I'll still believe
That someone's
watching over--
Someone's
watching over me
Oh yeah,
oh, oh
Oh, o-oh
Oh, oh...
Oh, oh
Oh, o-oh
Oh, oh...
Oh, oh
Someone's watching over me.
Way to go, Terri!
You did it! You were awesome!
We did it!
Nothing will ever top
what I just felt.
We got it.
We got it?
Are you sure?
All right.
Each year we present
a $10,000 academic scholarship
in Music Studies to an outstanding
student in the summer music prorram.
This year's prorram
was better than most,
full of talented,
hardworking students.
It's a shame we only have
one scholarship to give.
So without further ado,
the board of directors
of the Bristol-Hillman
Music Conservatory
is pleased to present
this scholarship to...
Denise Gilmore.
Oh honey! You were so wonderful!
Oh, thank you!
Truly amazing, but then again,
it's in the renes.
Aunt Nina, thank you
for everything.
I wish you would
have won that scholarship.
No, Mom, it doesn't
even matter.
I just-I got to be up there,
you know?
Yeah.
You um...
you were great, Terri.
Really.
Thank you, Dad.
Let me talk to you
for a second alone, all right?
I uh--
I just want to tell
you I was wrong.
No, you know what, Dad?
I should have never--
I just-I was wrong.
I can just be, uh, pretty hardheaded
sometimes, you know?
Anyway, I just wanted
to tell you that, uh...
it was probably the proudest
moment of my life
seeing you up there.
I just wish Paul
could have seen it.
Me too.
Hi.
The Fletchers have
an amazing daughter.
Thank you.
Awesome.
We hope, uh, we see
her next year.
Well, you just might.
Good.
Hey, Terri.
Come on!
In this place
that has no name
I can't remember
why I came
And then I hear
you whispering
One more mile
to Jericho
Nothing is ever
what it seems
When you live
inside your dreams
The walls will tumble,
the walls will tumble
But I'm not
going to cry
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
Everybody rets the joke
Where's the fire?
Where's the smoke?
Money, love and jealousy
Something's got ahold of me
But I will follow
where you go
One more mile to Jericho
The walls will tumble,
the walls will tumble
But I'm not gonna cry
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
Goodbye now
Goodbye
One more mile,
one more kiss
One more word,
one more wish
The walls will tumble,
the walls will tumble
But I'm not gonna cry
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
The walls will tumble,
the walls will tumble
But I'm not gonna cry
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye
My heart won't crumble,
my heart won't crumble
If we ever say goodbye.