Gabby, it's New Year's Eve.
Enough reading.
But, Mom, I'm almost done.
The teen party? I've laid out
your best clothes.
Come get ready.
Can I have my book back?
Thank you.
Come on.
Keep working left, Troy.
Got a guard in
the championship game
we're expecting.
You'll torch 'em!
Am I going left?
Yeah.
He looks middle,
you take it downtown.
Okay, like this?
That's it, man. Sweet.
Let's see that in the game.
Boys?
Don't worry about me.
Did we really fly all this way
to play more basketball?
BOTH: Yeah.
It's the last
night of vacation.
The party, remember?
Right, the party.
The party, New Year's Eve.
Troy, they have a kid's party
downstairs in
the Freestyle Club.
Kid's party?
Young adults.
Now go, shower up.
Come on. One more.
Last one.
Real quick.
There we go.
That's the way to end it.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON JUKEBOX)
Howdy, ma'am.
All right! How about that
for a couple of snowboarders?
(ALL WHOOPING)
Who's gonna rock
the house next?
Huh?
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
I can't sing. No, you go.
And you!
Yeah, come on.
(BLOWING PARTY FAVOR)
Look, I don't sing,
I can't sing. No, guys...
Get up there!
Hey, you know what?
Someday you guys might
thank me for this.
Or not.
(MUSIC STARTS)
♪ Living in my own world
♪ Didn't understand
(CLEARS THROAT)
♪ That anything can happen
♪ When you take a chance
♪ I never believed in
♪ What I couldn't see
♪ I never opened my heart
(VOCALIZES)
♪ To all the possibilities
♪ I know
♪ That something has changed
♪ Never felt this way
♪ And right here tonight
♪ This could be the start
of something new
♪ It feels so right
♪ To be here with you
♪ And now I'm
looking in your eyes
♪ I feel in my heart
♪ Feel in my heart
♪ The start of something new
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Now who'd have
ever thought that
(KIDS CHEERING)
♪ We'd both be here tonight?
♪ Yeah
♪ And the world
looks so much brighter
♪ Brighter, brighter
♪ Oh, with you by my side
♪ By my side
♪ I know that
something has changed
Never felt this way
♪ I know it for real
♪ Real
♪ This could be the start
of something new
♪ It feels so right
to be here with you
♪ And now looking in your eyes
I feel in my heart
♪ The start of something new
♪ I never knew
that it could happen
till it happened to me
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ I didn't know it before
but now it's easy to see
♪ It's the start
of something new
♪ It feels so right
to be here with you
♪ And now looking in your eyes
I feel in my heart
♪ That it's the start
of something new
♪ It feels so right
to be here with you
♪ And now looking in your eyes
♪ I feel in my heart
♪ Feel in my heart
♪ The start of something new
♪ The start of something new ♪
(ALL CHEERING)
Troy.
Gabriella.
But seriously,
you have an amazing
voice. You're a singer, right?
Just church choir is all.
I tried to solo
and nearly fainted.
Really? Why is that?
I looked at the people
staring at me.
Next thing I knew,
I was staring at the ceiling.
End of solo career.
The way you sing,
that's hard to believe.
That was the first time
I did that. It was so cool.
I know! Completely!
You sound like
you've sung a lot, too.
Yeah, sure. My showerhead
is very impressed with me.
KIDS: 10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4,
3, 2, 1.
(ALL SCREAMING EXCITEDLY)
(PARTY FAVORS BLOWING)
I guess I better go
find my mom and wish
her a happy new year.
Yeah, me, too.
I mean, not your mom.
My mom. And dad.
Uh, I'll call you.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Yeah!
Here, put your number in.
Here.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
You, too.
Oh, okay.
There you go.
Just so you know,
singing with you was
the most fun I've
had on this vacation.
So, um... Where do you live?
Gabriella.
(UPBEAT POP SONG PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(GROUP CHEERING)
Troy! How you doing, man?
Hey, Chad, what's up?
Hey, guys, happy new year.
Yeah!
It's a happy
Wildcat new year!
You're the man!
In two weeks
we're going to
the championships
with you leading us
to infinity and beyond.
What team?
Wildcats!
(ALL CHEERING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(BOYS EXCLAIMING)
(BOYS EXCLAIMING MOCKINGLY)
The ice princess returned
from the North Pole.
She spent the holidays
the way she always does.
How's that?
Shopping for mirrors.
(EXCLAIMS)
Behold the zoo animals
heralding the new year.
How tribal.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
Mom, my stomach...
Is nervous on first
day at a new school.
You'll do great.
You always do.
I made my company promise
that I can't be
transferred again
until you graduate.
I reviewed your
impressive transcripts.
Your light will
shine brightly
at East High.
I don't want to
be the school's
freaky genius girl again.
Just be Gabriella.
This way.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Troy! Troy! Hey!
How's it going?
How are you?
Do you remember
the night before?
No, not at all.
All I remember is like,
pink jelly. I...
(BOY EXCLAIMING)
(CHATTERING STOPS)
GABRIELLA: Excuse me.
Hi, Troy.
Hi.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
I trust you all had
splendid holidays.
Check the sign-up
sheets in the lobby
for new activities,
Mr. Bolton.
Especially our
winter musicale.
We will have
singles auditions...
You okay?
Yeah.
...and pairs
auditions for our two leads.
Mr. Danforth,
this is a place of learning,
not a hockey arena.
There is also a final sign-up
for next week's scholastic
decathlon competition.
Chem club
president Taylor McKessie
can answer all of your
questions about that.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Ah, the cell phone menace
has returned to our
crucible of learning.
Is it your phone?
Sharpay and Ryan,
cell phones.
I will see you in detention.
We have zero tolerance
for cell phones in class,
so we will get
to know each other
in detention. Cell phone.
And welcome to East High,
Miss Montez.
Mr. Bolton,
I see your phone is involved.
So we will see you
in detention as well.
That's not a possibility,
Miss Darbus.
Your Honor,
see, 'cause we have
basketball practice,
and Troy...
Ah, that will be 15 minutes
for you, too, Mr. Danforth.
Count 'em.
Could be tough for Chad.
He can't count that high.
Taylor McKessie, 15 minutes.
Shall the carnage continue?
Holidays are over, people.
Way over!
Now, any more
comments, questions?
Jason.
How were your holidays,
Miss Darbus?
(ALL GROANING)
What?
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Sorry, man.
See you in detention.
See you later. It's all good.
She's crazy.
Hey!
I don't...
Believe it.
Well, me...
Either. But how?
My mom's company
transferred her
here to Albuquerque.
I can't believe you live here.
I looked for you at the lodge
on New Year's Day.
We had to leave first thing.
Why are you whispering?
What? Oh, uh... My friends
know about the snowboarding.
I haven't quite told them
about the singing thing.
What's up?
Hey.
Too much for them to handle?
No, it was cool.
But, you know,
my friends, it's, uh...
It's not what I do.
That was, like,
a different person.
So, uh, anyway,
welcome to East High.
Now that you've
met Miss Darbus.
I bet you just can't wait
to sign up for that.
I won't be signing up
for anything for a while.
I just wanna get
to know the school.
But if you sign up,
I'd consider
coming to the show.
Yeah, yeah.
That's completely impossible.
What's impossible, Troy?
I wouldn't think "impossible"
is even in your vocabulary.
Oh, so nice of you to
show our new classmate around.
Oh, were you
going to sign up, too?
My brother and I
have starred in all
the school's productions
and we really
welcome newcomers.
There are a lot of
supporting roles.
I'm sure we could find
something for you.
No, no, no.
I was just looking at
all the bulletin boards.
Lots going on at this school.
Wow.
Nice penmanship.
So, Troy,
I missed you during vacation.
What'd you do?
You know,
um, played basketball,
snowboarding, more basketball.
When's the big game?
Two weeks.
You are so dedicated.
Just like me.
I hope you come watch me
in the musical. Promise?
Toodles!
Toodles.
Dude, you know
that school musical thing?
You get extra credit
just for auditioning?
Who cares?
It's always good
to get extra credit
for college.
Think LeBron James
or Shaquille O'Neal
auditioned for
their school musical?
Maybe.
Troy.
The music in those shows
isn't hip-hop or rock,
or anything
essential to culture.
It's, like, show music.
It's all costumes and makeup.
Oh, dude, it's frightening.
I know. I thought
it'd be a good laugh.
Sharpay's kinda cute, too.
So is a mountain lion.
But you don't pet it.
All right, Wildcats! Pair up!
Let's go! Come on!
(BALLS BOUNCING IN RHYTHM)
♪ Coach said to fake right
and break left
♪ Watch out for the pick
and keep an eye on defense
♪ Gotta run the give and go
and take the ball to the hole
♪ And don't be afraid
to shoot the outside "J"
♪ Just keep your
head in the game
♪ And don't be afraid
to shoot the outside "J"
♪ Just keep your
head in the game
♪ You gotta get
your head in the game
♪ We gotta get our,
get our, get our,
get our head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your head in the game
♪ We gotta get our,
get our, get our,
get our head in the game
♪ Come on, get your,
get your head in the game
♪ We gotta get our,
get our, get our,
get our head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your head in the game
♪ We gotta get our,
get our, get our,
get our head in the game, whoo
♪ Let's make sure
that we get the rebound
♪ 'Cause when we get it
then the crowd'll go wild
♪ A second chance,
gotta grab it and go
♪ Maybe this time
we'll hit the right notes
♪ Wait a minute,
not the time and place
get my head in the game
♪ Wait a minute,
♪ Wait a minute, wait a minute
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ Come on, get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head
in the game, whoo
♪ Why am I feeling so wrong?
♪ My head's in the game
but my heart's in the song
♪ She makes this
feel so right
Should I go for it?
I better shake this. Yikes!
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ Come on, get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ I gotta get my,
get my head in the game
♪ You gotta get your,
get your, get your
♪ Get your head in the game
♪ Whoo! ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
CHAD: What team?
BOYS: Wildcats!
What team?
Wildcats!
Get your head in the game!
(PLAYERS CHEERING)
So, it seemed like you knew
Troy Bolton.
Not really.
He was just showing me around.
Well, Troy usually doesn't
interact with new students.
Uh, why not?
It's pretty much basketball
24/7 with him.
That should be 16 over pi.
Yes, Miss Montez?
I'm sorry,
I was just... Uh...
Shouldn't the second equation
read 16 over pi?
16 over pi?
That's quite impossible.
I stand corrected.
Oh, and welcome aboard.
Catch you later, guys.
Okay.
Troy Bolton was looking
at our audition list.
Again?
He was hanging around
with that new girl
and they were both
looking at the list.
There's something
freaky about her.
Where did she say she's from?
(EXCLAIMS)
Wow! An Einsteinette.
So why do you
think she's interested
in our musical?
I'm not sure that she is.
And we needn't concern
ourselves with amateurs.
But there is no
harm in making certain
that Gabriella's welcome to
school activities that are...
Well,
appropriate for her.
After all,
she loves pi.
Gold! More gold!
Paint, paint! Let's go!
The answer is yes!
Huh?
Our scholastic decathlon
team has its first
competition next week,
and there is
certainly a spot for you.
Where did those come from?
Didn't you put
them in my locker?
Of course not.
Well, we'd love
to have you on our team.
We meet almost
every day after school.
Please?
I need to catch up
on the curriculum here
before I think
about joining any clubs.
Well, what a perfect way
to get caught up.
Meeting with the smartest kids
in school.
What a generous offer, Taylor.
So many new faces
in detention today.
I hope you don't
make a habit of it,
but the drama club can always
use an extra hand.
And while we are working,
let us probe
the mounting
evils of cell phones.
Come on, guys, huddle up!
We got two weeks
to the big game.
(SCATTERED AGREEMENT)
Where's Troy and Chad?
Don't make me ask again.
(SHOUTING)
Where's Troy and Chad?
BOYS: Detention.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
DARBUS: Perhaps
the most heinous example
of cell-phone abuse
is ringing in the theater.
What temerity!
The theater is
a temple of art.
A precious cornucopia
of creative energy.
Where's my team, Darbus?
What the heck are those two
doing in a tree?
It's called crime
and punishment, Bolton.
Besides, proximity to the arts
is cleansing for the soul.
Can we have a talk, please?
And you two, in the gym, now!
If they have to
paint sets for detention,
they could do it tonight,
not during practice.
If these were
theater performers,
would you seek
special treatment?
Darbus, we are days away
from our biggest
game of the year.
And we, Bolton,
are in the midst
of our auditions
for our winter
musicale as well!
This school is about more than
just young men in baggy shorts
flinging balls for touchdowns!
Baskets! They shoot baskets.
Stop! Guys, listen.
You've been
having this argument
since the day you both started
teaching here.
We are one school,
one student body,
one faculty!
Can we not agree on that?
So, Coach,
how's the team looking?
Troy got 'em
whipped into shape?
Oh!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
West High Knights
have knocked us
out of the playoffs
three years running,
and now we are one game away
from taking that championship
back from 'em!
It's time to make our stand.
The team is you.
You are the team.
And this team does not exist
unless each and
every one of you is
fully focussed on our goal.
Am I clear?
Hey, what team?
BOYS: Wildcats!
What team?
Wildcats!
Get your head in the game!
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
TAYLOR: We've never made it
past the first round
of the scholastic decathlon.
You could be our
answered prayer.
I'm focussing on my studies
this semester,
and help my mom
get the new house
organized. Maybe next year.
What do you know
about Troy Bolton?
Troy? Hmm.
I'm not an
expert on that
particular sub-species.
However, unless
you speak cheerleader,
as in, "Oh, my gosh!
Isn't Troy Bolton
just the hottie super-bum?"
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
Oh, he's so beautiful.
See what I mean?
I don't know how
to speak cheerleader.
We exist in an alternate
universe to Troy
the basketball boy.
Have you tried to
get to know him?
Watch how it works tomorrow
when you have lunch with us.
Unless you'd rather
sit with the cheerleaders
and discuss firm nail beds.
My nail beds are history.
Sister!
Still don't understand
this detention thing.
It was my fault.
Sorry, Dad.
Cross court.
Darbus will take
any opportunity
to bust my chops.
That includes yours, too.
Hey, Dad?
Did you ever want to try
something new,
but were afraid
of what your friends think?
Like going left?
You're doing fine.
Well... No.
I mean, what if you wanna
try something really new
and it's a total disaster
and all your
friends laugh at you.
Maybe they're
not your friends.
That was my whole point
about team today.
You gotta look
out for each other.
You're the leader.
There's gonna
be college scouts
at our game next week.
Know what a scholarship
is worth these days?
A lot.
Yeah. Focus, Troy, come on.
Just something for you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
I expect we all
learned our homeroom
manners yesterday,
people, correct?
If not,
we have some dressing rooms
that need painting.
Now, a few announcements.
This morning during
free period will be
your chance for
the musicale auditions,
both single and pairs.
I will be in
the theater until noon
for those of you
bold enough to extend
the wingspan of
your creative spirit.
When's she due back
on the mother ship?
...discussing the importance
of Shakespeare.
What's up, man?
What's up?
The team's
hitting the gym during
free period.
What should we run?
I can't make it.
I gotta catch up
on some homework.
What? Hello, it's only
the second day back.
I'm not even
behind on homework yet.
And I've been
behind on homework
since preschool.
That's hilarious.
I'll catch you later.
Homework? There's no way.
BOY 1: How's it going?
BOY 2: Just hanging out?
Good to see you.
What's he doing?
How's it going, man?
Short cut.
I'm late for class.
MAN: That's good.
Just leave it here.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
This is where
the true expression
of the artist is realized.
Where inner truth is revealed
through the actor's journey...
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Was that a cell phone?
Is it mine?
No, ma'am.
That was the warning bell.
Those wishing to audition must
understand that
time is of the essence.
We have many roles to cast
and final callbacks
will be next week.
First, you will sing
a few bars and I will
give you a sense
of whether or not
the theater is your calling.
Better to hear it from me now
than from your friends later.
Our composer, Kelsi Nielson,
will accompany you
and be available for
rehearsals prior to callbacks.
Shall we?
(PLAYING SLOW MELODY)
♪ It's hard to believe
that I couldn't see
♪ That you were
always right beside me
(SINGING OFF-KEY)
♪ This feeling like no other
♪ I want you to know ♪
Uh-huh. Yes, thank you. Next!
(SINGING MONOTONOUSLY)
♪ It's hard to believe
♪ That I couldn't sneeze...
See
♪ That you were
always right there
next to beside me... ♪
Alan, I admire your pluck.
As to your singing...
That's a wonderful tie
you're wearing. Next!
♪ It's hard to believe
that I couldn't see
♪ That you were
always there beside me
(OFF-KEY)
♪ This feeling's like no other
♪ I want you to know ♪
Uh... Stop.
(OPERATICALLY)
♪ So lonely
before I finally found
♪ What I've been looking
♪ For ♪
Ah... Cyndra.
What courage to
pursue a note that has
not been accessed
in the natural world.
Bravo! Brava!
Perhaps the spring musicale.
(SCOFFS SOFTLY)
(STOPS PLAYING)
(CRASHING)
(MUSIC RESUMES)
GIRL: (SPOKEN)
♪ It's hard to believe
that I could not see
(SPOKEN)
♪ Couldn't see
♪ That you
were right beside me
♪ Beside me
♪ Thought I was alone
♪ Alone
♪ With no one to hold
♪ To hold
♪ But you were
right beside me ♪
♪ Beside me ♪
DARBUS: Well, that was just
very disturbing.
Go see a counselor.
(EXCLAIMS WITH DISGUST)
Next!
Hey!
So you decided
to sign up for something?
Uh... No. You?
No.
Um... Why are you hiding
behind a mop?
Your friends don't know
you're here, right?
Right.
Thank you. Next.
Miss Darbus
is a little harsh.
The Wildcat
superstar's afraid?
No! I'm not afraid. I...
I'm just... Scared.
Me, too. Usually.
DARBUS: And for the lead roles
of Minnie and Arnold
we only have one
couple signed up.
Sharpay and Ryan.
I think it might
be useful for you
to give us a sense of
why we gather in
this hallowed hall.
What key?
Oh, we had our rehearsal
pianist do an arrangement.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(VOCALIZING)
Go!
(RECORDED UPBEAT
MELODY PLAYING)
♪ It's hard to believe
that I couldn't see
♪ You were always there
beside me
♪ Thought I was alone
with no one to hold
♪ But you were
always right beside me
♪ This feeling's like no other
♪ I want you to know
♪ I've never had someone
that knows me like you do
♪ The way you do
♪ I've never had someone
as good for me as you
♪ No one like you
♪ So lonely before
I finally found
♪ What I've been looking for
♪ So good to be seen,
so good to be heard
♪ Don't have to say a word
♪ For so long I was lost,
so good to be found
♪ I'm loving having you around
♪ This feeling's like no other
♪ I want you to know
♪ I've never had someone
that knows me like you do
♪ The way you do
♪ I've never had someone
as good for me as you
♪ No one like you
♪ So lonely before
I finally found
♪ What I've been looking for ♪
(BOTH VOCALIZING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
I told you not to
do the jazz squares.
It's a crowd favorite.
Everybody loves
a good jazz square.
Well...
Are there any
last-minute sign-ups?
Don't be discouraged.
The theater club
needs more than singers.
It needs fans, too.
Buy tickets!
Oh, actually,
if you do the part
with that particular song,
I imagined it much slow...
If we do the part?
(SCOFFS)
Kelsi, my sawed-off Sondheim.
I've been in 17
school productions.
How many of your
compositions
have been selected?
This would be the first.
Which tells us what?
That I need to
write you more solos?
No. It tells us that
you do not offer direction,
suggestion or commentary.
And you should be thankful
that me and Ryan can lift
your music out
of its obscurity.
Are we clear?
Yes, ma'am. I mean, Sharpay.
Nice talking to you.
Any last-minute sign-ups?
We should go.
No? Good. Done.
I'd like to audition,
Miss Darbus.
DARBUS:
Timeliness means something in
the world of theater,
young lady.
The individual
auditions are long over
and there are
simply no other pairs.
TROY: I'll sing with her.
Troy Bolton?
Where is your sports
posse or whatever it's called?
Team.
Ah.
But I'm here alone.
Actually,
I'm here to sing with her.
Yes, well,
we take these shows very
seriously here at East High.
I called for
the pairs audition
and you didn't respond.
Free period is now over.
She has an amazing voice.
Perhaps the next musicale.
(PIANO PLAYING)
So, you're a composer?
You wrote the song
Ryan and Sharpay just sang?
And the entire show?
Well, that's really cool.
I can't wait to hear
the rest of the show.
So, why are you so afraid
of Ryan and Sharpay?
I mean, it is your show.
It is?
Isn't the composer
of a show kind of
like the playmaker
in basketball?
Playmaker?
The one who
makes everyone else
look good.
Without you there is no show.
You're the playmaker
here, Kelsi.
I am?
Do you wanna
hear how the duet's
supposed to sound?
♪ It's hard to believe
that I couldn't see
♪ You were always there
beside me
♪ Thought I was alone
with no one to hold
♪ But you were
always right beside me
♪ This feeling's like no other
♪ I want you to know
♪ That I've never had someone
that knows me like you do
♪ The way you do
♪ And I've never had someone
as good for me as you
♪ No one like you
♪ So lonely before
I finally found
♪ What I've been looking for ♪
(VOCALIZING)
Wow. That's nice.
Bolton, Montez,
you have a callback.
Kelsi, give them the duet
from the second act.
Work on it with them.
All right.
If you guys wanna rehearse,
I'm usually here
during free period
and after school,
and even sometimes
during biology class.
You can come and
rehearse anytime.
Or come to my
house for breakfast.
I have a piano,
we can rehearse there.
After school,
before school,
whatever works.
After basketball class...
What?
SHARPAY: Callback?
(HYPERVENTILATING)
"Callback for
roles Arnold and Minnie
next Thursday, 3:30 p.m.
"Ryan and Sharpay Evans.
Gabriella Montez
and Troy Bolton."
Is this some kind of joke?
They didn't even audition!
Maybe we're being punked?
What?
Maybe we're being
filmed right now.
Maybe we'll get
to meet Ashton!
Oh, shut up, Ryan!
What's wrong?
What?
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
How dare she sign up!
I picked out
the colors for
my dressing room.
She hasn't even
asked our permission
to join the drama club.
Someone's gotta
tell her the rules.
Exactly.
And what are the rules?
(EXCLAIMS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ You can bet there's nothing
but net when I am in
a zone and on a roll
♪ But I got a confession,
my own secret obsession
♪ And it's making me
lose control
♪ Everybody gather round
If Troy can tell his
secret, then I can tell mine.
I bake.
What?
I love to bake!
Strudels, scones,
even apple pandowdy.
♪ Not another sound
Someday I hope to make
the perfect creme brulee.
♪ No, no, no, no
No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ If you wanna be cool
Follow one simple rule
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status quo
♪ Look at me and
what do you see?
Intelligence beyond compare
♪ But inside I am stirring
Something strange is occurring
♪ It's a secret
I need to share
♪ Open up, dig way down deep
Hip-hop is my passion
I love to pop and lock
and jam and break!
Is that even legal?
♪ Not another peep!
It's just dancing.
I think it's
cooler than homework.
♪ No, no, no, no
No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ It is better by far
To keep things as they are
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status quo
♪ Listen well,
I'm ready to tell
♪ About a need
that I cannot deny
♪ Dude, there's no explanation
For this awesome sensation
♪ But I'm ready to let it fly
♪ Speak your mind
and you'll be heard
If Troy wants to be a singer
then I'm coming clean.
I play the cello!
Awesome! What is it?
A saw?
No, dude,
it's like a giant violin!
♪ Not another word
Do you have to
wear a costume?
Coat and tie.
♪ No, no, no, no
No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ If you wanna be cool
Follow one simple rule
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status quo
♪ No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ It is better by far
To keep things as they are
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status quo
♪ This is not what I want
♪ This is not what I planned
♪ And I just gotta say
♪ I do not understand
♪ Something is really...
♪ Something's not right
♪ Really wrong
♪ And we've
gotta get things back
where they belong
♪ We can do it
♪ Gotta play
♪ Stick with what you know
♪ We can do it
♪ Hip-hop hooray
♪ She has got to go
♪ We can do it
♪ Creme Brulee
♪ Keep your voice down low
(WHISPERING)
♪ Not another peep
♪ No
♪ Not another word
♪ Not another sound
♪ No
♪ Everybody quiet!
Why is everybody
staring at you?
Not me, you.
Because of the callbacks?
I can't have
people staring at me.
I can't.
♪ No! No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ If you want to be cool
Follow one simple rule
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status quo
♪ No, no, no
♪ Stick to the stuff you know
♪ It is better by far
To keep things as they are
♪ Don't mess
with the flow, no, no
♪ Stick to the status
Stick to the status
♪ Stick to the status quo ♪
(SCREAMING)
I am so sorry.
You do not want to
get into that, man.
Too much drama.
Yeah.
What is going on here?
Look at this!
That Gabriella girl
just dumped her lunch on me!
On purpose!
It's all part of their plan
to ruin our musical.
And Troy and his
basketball robots
are obviously behind it.
Why do you think
he auditioned?
After all the hard work
you've put into this show.
It just doesn't seem right.
What's up?
What's up? Oh, let's see.
You missed free-period workout
to audition for
a heinous musical.
And now suddenly
people are confessing.
Yeah, and Zeke.
Zeke is baking creme brulee.
What's that?
Oh, a creamy custard
with a caramelized surface.
It's really satisfying.
CHAD: Shut up, Zeke!
Look. Do you see
what's happening here, man?
Our team is coming apart
because of your singing thing.
Even the drama geeks and the
brainiacs suddenly
think that they can
talk to us.
Look, the skater
dudes are mingling.
Yo!
Suddenly people
think that they
can do other stuff.
Stuff that's not their stuff.
You're thinking
about show tunes,
when we've got a playoff game
next week.
Whoa!
Head's up!
(CLEARING THROAT)
(SHUDDERS)
All right.
Cards on the table right now.
Huh?
You're tweaked because I put
your stars in detention
and now you're getting even.
What are you
talking about, Darbus?
Your all-star son
turned up at my audition.
Now, I give every student
an even chance,
which is a long and honorable
tradition in the theater.
Something that you
wouldn't understand.
But if he is
planning some sort of
practical joke in my
chapel of the arts...
Troy doesn't even sing.
Oh, well,
you're wrong about that.
But I will not
allow my Twinkle Town
musicale to be
made into farce.
Twinkle Town?
See? I knew it!
Hey.
I knew it!
Sounds like a winner.
Good luck on Broadway!
Is Sharpay really,
really mad at me?
I said I was sorry.
Look, no one has
beaten out Sharpay
for a musical
since kindergarten.
I wasn't trying
to beat anyone out.
We didn't even audition,
we were just singing.
You won't convince
Sharpay of that.
If that girl could play
both Romeo and Juliet,
her own brother
would be aced out.
I told you it just happened,
but I liked it.
A lot.
Did you ever feel like there's
a whole other
person inside you
just looking for
a way to come out?
Not really, no.
(BELL RINGING)
Let's go.
Hey, Sharpay. I thought since
Troy Bolton's gonna
be in your show...
Troy Bolton is not in my show.
Um... Well,
I thought maybe you
could watch me
play ball sometime.
I'd rather stick
pins in my eyes.
Wouldn't that be
awfully uncomfortable?
Evaporate, tall person!
I bake!
If that helps.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLING EXCITEDLY)
Wow! It's like
a jungle up here.
Yeah, just like
that cafeteria.
Well, I just humiliated myself
into the next century.
No! Come on.
So this is your
private hideout?
Yeah. Thanks to
the science club.
Which means my buddies
don't know it exists.
You pretty much
have the school wired,
don't you, Troy?
Seems to me like
everyone on campus
wants to be your friend.
Unless we lose.
Well, I'm sure it's tricky
being the coach's son.
Makes me practice
a little harder. I guess.
I don't know what he'll say
about the singing.
You worried?
My parents' friends
are always saying,
"Your son's
the basketball guy.
You must be so proud."
Sometimes I don't wanna be
the basketball guy.
I just wanna be a guy.
You know?
I saw the way
you treated Kelsi
at the audition yesterday.
Do your friends know that guy?
To them,
I'm the playmaker dude.
They don't know enough
about you, Troy.
At my other schools,
I was the freaky math girl.
It's cool coming here
and being anyone I wanna be.
When I was singing with you,
I just felt like a girl.
You even looked like one, too.
Remember in kindergarten
how you'd meet a kid
and know nothing about them,
then ten seconds later you
play like you're best friends
because you didn't have to
be anything but yourself?
Yeah.
Singing with
you felt like that.
Well, uh...
I never thought about singing.
That's for sure.
Till you.
So you really
wanna do the callbacks?
Hey, just call me
freaky callback boy.
You're a cool guy, Troy.
But not for the reasons
your friends think.
And thanks for showing me
your top-secret hiding place.
Like kindergarten.
(BELL RINGING)
(BOTH SIGHING)
♪ We're soaring,
we're flying...
(TROY SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
♪ Breaking...
♪ Creating space
between us...
(GABRIELLA
SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR OPENING)
♪ There's not a star
in heaven that we...
♪ Flying
♪ There's not a star
in heaven that we... ♪
Let's go, guys! Make it sharp!
To the chest, come on! Pop it!
Come on, guys. Step with it!
Let's go!
Come on, move it! Let's go!
Come on, guys, focus! Focus!
Get your head in the game!
Move it!
You seen Troy?
No, Coach.
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Again, let's go!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
That's it, guys.
Let's hit the showers.
Good hustle.
Let's see that in the game.
(PLAYERS CHATTERING)
I think I'm
gonna stay a while.
Work on some free throws.
Since you missed practice,
I think your team deserves
a little effort
from you today.
Wow. So this is
your real stage.
Yeah. I guess you
could call it that.
Or just a smelly gym.
Whoa!
Don't tell me you're
good at hoops, too.
You know,
I once scored 41 points
at a league championship game.
No way.
Mmm-hmm.
And the same day,
I invented the space shuttle
and microwave popcorn.
Microwave popcorn.
Ha-ha, funny.
I've been rehearsing
with Kelsi.
Me, too. And by the way,
I missed practice.
So if I get kicked off
the team it'll be
on your conscience.
Hey, I wasn't
the one who told you...
Gabriella, chill.
Hey, that's traveling.
No, that's really
bad traveling.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
COACH BOLTON: Miss, I'm sorry,
this is a closed practice.
Dad, practice is over.
Not till the last
player leaves.
Team rule.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
Dad, this is
Gabriella Montez.
Ah, your detention buddy.
I'll see you later, Troy.
Nice meeting you,
Coach Bolton.
You as well, Miss Montez.
Dad, detention was my fault,
not hers.
You haven't missed practice
in three years.
That girl shows up...
That girl is named Gabriella.
She's very nice.
Helping you miss
practice doesn't
make her very nice.
Not in my book.
Or your team's.
Dad, she's not a problem.
She's just a girl.
But you're not
just a guy, Troy.
You're the team leader.
What you do affects
not only this team,
but the entire school.
And without you
completely focussed,
we're not gonna win next week.
The championship games,
they don't come
along all the time.
They're something special.
Yeah, a lot of
things are special, Dad.
But you're a playmaker,
not a singer, right?
Did you ever think
maybe I could be both?
What?
Let's go.
What spell has
this elevated-IQ
temptress girl cast
that suddenly
makes you wanna be
in a musical?
Look, I just did it.
Who cares?
Who cares? How about your most
loyal best friend?
Quiet in here, Mr. Danforth.
It's him, Miss Falsaff,
not me.
Look, you're a hoops dude,
not a musical singer person.
Have you ever
seen Michael Crawford
on a cereal box?
Who's Michael Crawford?
Exactly my point.
He was the Phantom
of the Opera on Broadway.
Now my mom, she's seen
that musical 27 times,
and put Michael Crawford's
picture in our refrigerator.
Yeah, not on it, in it.
So my point is,
if you play basketball,
you're gonna end up
on the cereal box.
If you're in musicals,
you'll end up in
my mom's refrigerator.
Why in her refrigerator?
One of her crazy diet ideas.
I won't attempt to
understand the female mind.
It's frightening territory.
(SIGHS)
How can you expect
the rest of us to be
focussed on a game
if you're off somewhere
in leotards,
singing Twinkle Town?
No one said
anything about leotards.
Not yet, my friend,
but just you wait.
Look, we need you, Captain.
Big time.
Mr. Danforth.
I tried to tell him,
Miss Falsaff.
Really tried.
Something isn't right.
Hey, look.
We need to talk.
Go.
(WHISPERING) They must
be trying to figure out
a way to make sure
Troy and Gabriella
beat us out.
The jocks rule
most of the school,
but if they get
Troy into a musical,
then they've conquered
the entire student body.
And if those science
girls get Gabriella
hooked up with Troy Bolton,
the scholastic club
goes from drool to cool.
Ryan, we need to
save our show from
people who don't
know the difference
between a Tony Award
and Tony Hawk.
Do you think that'll work?
It's the only way to save Troy
and Gabriella from themselves.
So we on?
Yeah.
Good. So we start
tomorrow then.
Okay, the first thing.
Nice. Let's go.
Cool.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
So, my watch is 7:45 Mountain
Standard time. We synched?
Whatever.
Then we're on go mode
for lunch, 12:05.
Yes, Chad, we're a go.
But we're not
Charlie's Angels, okay?
I can dream, can't I?
(BELL RINGS)
"Spider" Bill Netrine,
class of '72.
He was the MVP in the league
championship game.
Sam Nedler, class of '02.
Also known as
"Sammy Slamma Jamma."
Captain, MVP of the league
championship team.
The "Thunder Clap,"
Hap Hadden, '95.
Led the Wildcats to
back-to-back
city championships.
A legend.
Yes, legends, one and all.
But do you think
that any of these
Wildcat legends became legends
by getting involved
in musical auditions
days before
the league championships?
Get your head in the game!
No.
These Wildcat legends
became legends
because they never took
their eye off the prize.
Get your head in the game!
Who was
the first sophomore ever
to make starting varsity?
BOYS: Troy!
Who voted him team
captain this year?
BOYS: Us!
And who is gonna
get their butts kicked
in Friday's championship game
if Troy's worried
about an audition?
BOYS: We are.
Guys, come on.
There's 12 people on
this team, not just me.
Just 12? Oh, no.
I think you're
forgetting about one very
important 13th
member of our squad.
My dad.
Yes, Troy.
Wildcat basketball champion,
class of 1981.
Champion, father,
and now coach.
It's a winning
tradition like no other.
From lowly Neanderthal
and Cro-Magnon,
to early warriors,
medieval knights.
All leading up to
lunkhead basketball man.
Yes, our culture worshiped the
aggressor throughout the ages
and we end up with spoiled,
overpaid bonehead athletes
who contribute little
to civilization
other than slam dunks
and touchdowns.
That is the inevitable world
of Troy Bolton.
But the path of the mind,
the path we're on,
ours is the path that
has brought us these people:
Eleanor Roosevelt,
Frida Kahlo.
Sandra Day O'Connor,
Madame Curie, Jane Goodall,
Oprah Winfrey
and so many others
who the world reveres.
Uh, but, what is...
I've got Kelsi waiting
for me to rehearse.
Gabriella!
Troy Bolton
represents one side
of evolution.
And our side,
the side of education
and accomplishment,
is the future of civilization!
This is the side
where you belong.
Guys, if you don't
know that I'll put
a 110% of my guts
into that game,
then you don't know me.
But we just thought...
I'll tell you what I thought.
I thought that
you're my friends.
Win together,
lose together, team-mates.
But suddenly the girl...
And the singing.
Man, I'm for the team!
I've always been for the team.
She's just someone I met.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
All right,
the singing thing is nothing.
A way to keep my nerves down.
It means nothing to me.
You're my guys and
this is our team.
Gabriella is not important.
I'll forget about her,
forget the audition
and we'll get
that championship.
Everyone happy now?
Behold lunkhead
basketball man.
So, Gabriella,
we'd love to have you
for the scholastic decathlon.
Did you wanna grab some lunch?
Well, we'll be there
if you wanna come.
Wildcats!
Get your head in the game!
(ALL WHOOPING)
Let's go!
STUDENT: Go, Wildcats!
♪ Everybody sing out
♪ Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands up in the air
♪ That's the way we do it
Let's get to it,
time to show the world
♪ Wildcats, sing along
Yeah, you really
get it going on
♪ Wildcats in the house
Everybody sing out
♪ Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands
up in the air... ♪
ALL: (CHANTING) Troy! Troy!
♪ It's funny when
you find yourself
♪ Looking from the outside
♪ I'm standing
here but all I want
is to be over there
♪ Why did I let myself believe
♪ Miracles could happen?
♪ 'Cause now I have to pretend
♪ That I don't really care
♪ I thought you
were my fairy tale
♪ A dream when
I'm not sleeping
♪ A wish upon a star
that's coming true
♪ But everybody
else could tell
♪ That I confused my feelings
with the truth
♪ When there was me and you
♪ I swore I knew the melody
♪ That I heard you singing
♪ And when you smiled
you made me feel
♪ Like I could sing along
♪ But then you went
and changed the words
♪ Now my heart is empty
♪ I'm only left
with used-to-bes
and once upon a song
♪ Now I know
you're not a fairy tale
♪ And dreams were
meant for sleeping
♪ And wishes on a star
just don't come true
♪ 'Cause now even I can tell
♪ That I confused my feelings
with the truth
♪ Because I liked the view
♪ When there was me and you
♪ I can't believe
that I could be so blind
♪ It's like you were floating
while I was falling
♪ And I didn't mind
♪ Because I liked the view
♪ I thought you felt it too
♪ When there was me and you ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, how you doing?
I wanna talk to
you about something.
And here it is.
I know what it's like
to carry a load
with your friends.
I get it.
You've got your boys, Troy.
It's okay. So we're good.
Good about what?
I wanna talk about
the final callbacks.
I don't wanna do
the callbacks either.
Who are we trying to kid?
You've got your
team and I've got mine.
I'll do
the scholastic decathlon
and you'll win
the championships.
It's where we belong.
Go, Wildcats.
But I...
Me neither.
(WIND INSTRUMENT BLOWING)
Gabriella?
Go Wildcats!
CHAD: Hey, Captain!
BOY: What's with Troy?
Don't worry about it.
(TROY GRUNTING)
(TROY PANTING)
Oh, hey!
Troy! Hey.
Hey, Troy!
CHAD: Hey, um...
We just had
another team meeting.
Oh, wonderful.
We had a team
meeting about how
we haven't been
acting like a team.
I mean us, not you.
About the singing thing...
I don't even
wanna talk about it.
We just want you to know
that we're gonna be there.
Cheering for you.
Huh?
If singing is
what you wanna do,
we should boost you up,
not tear you down.
Yeah. Win or lose,
we're team-mates.
That's what we're about.
Even if you turn out to be
the worst singer in the world.
Which we don't know,
because we
haven't heard you sing.
You're not gonna
hear me sing, guys.
Because Gabriella
won't even talk to me,
and I don't know why.
We do.
I baked these fresh today.
You'll probably
want to try one
before we tell you the rest.
Gabriella, we were jerks.
No, we were worse than jerks
because we were mean jerks.
We thought Troy
and the whole
singing thing was
killing our
chances of having you
on the scholastic
decathlon team.
I heard what he had to say.
I'm on your team now. Done.
No, not done.
We knew that Chad could
get Troy to say things
to make you want to
forget about the callbacks.
We planned it, and we're
embarrassed and sorry.
No one forced
Troy to say anything.
And you know what? It's okay.
We should prepare
for the decathlon.
It's time to move on.
No, it's not okay.
The decathlon is whatever,
but how you feel about us,
and even more, Troy,
that's what really matters.
We tried.
(SOFTLY) Hi, uh...
Just came to say I'm sorry.
Hi, Miss Montez.
I'm Troy Bolton.
Oh, Troy!
(MOUTHING) No.
Um... Gabriella is
kind of busy with homework,
so now's not a good time.
I made a mistake, Miss Montez,
and I would really like
to let Gabriella know that.
Could you tell her
I came by to see her?
I will, Troy.
Good night.
Good night. Thank you.
(DIALING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(PHONE TINKLING)
Hello?
What you heard,
none of that is true.
I was sick of my
friends riding me,
so I said things
to shut them up.
I didn't mean any of it.
You sounded pretty
convincing to me.
The guy you met on vacation
is more me
than the guy
who said those stupid things.
The whole singing thing
is making the school whack.
You said so yourself.
Everyone's
treating you
differently because of it.
Maybe because I don't wanna
only be the basketball guy.
They can't handle it.
That's not my problem,
it's theirs.
How about your dad?
And it's not about my dad.
This is about how I feel.
And I'm not
letting the team down.
They let me down.
So I'm gonna sing.
What about you?
I don't know, Troy.
Well, you need to say yes.
Because I brought
you something.
What do you mean?
Turn around.
♪ This could be the start
of something new
♪ It feels so right
to be here with you
♪ And now looking in your eyes
♪ I feel in my heart
♪ The start of something
♪ New ♪
It's a pairs audition.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(PLAYERS SHOUTING)
(PLAYERS WHOOPING)
Yeah!
Zn 4, and by doing that,
you end up with two
and two. Got it?
BOTH: Yes!
What's happening?
Come here. Go ahead
and put five grams of this in,
and that causes it to change
from an acidic state,
causing the color to change
from pink to blue.
Just like those pH strips.
Oh, gotta go.
See you guys later!
(PANTS)
Whoa!
(GABRIELLA GIGGLES)
TROY: You're late!
GABRIELLA AND TROY:
♪ ...strength to believe
♪ We're soaring
♪ Flying
♪ There's not a star in heaven
that we can't reach
(SCATTING)
♪ Bop bop bop...
TROY: ♪ If we're trying
GABRIELLA AND TROY:
♪ Yeah, we're breaking free
(GASPS)
Wow. They sound good.
(SCOFFS)
TROY: ♪ Like a wave
the ocean just... ♪
We have to do something.
Our callback's on Thursday
and the basketball game
and scholastic
decathlon are on Friday.
Too bad all
these events weren't
happening on the same day
at the same time.
That wouldn't
work out because then
Troy and Gabriella
wouldn't be able to make...
I'm proud to
call you my sister.
I know.
DARBUS:
I don't want to hear anymore
about Troy Bolton
and that Montez girl.
So, if you're
telling me as co-presidents
of the drama club
that changing the callbacks
would be what's best
for our theater program,
I might actually
agree with you.
(SIGHS)
Is that a yes?
SHARPAY:
♪ Bop bop bop, up to the top
♪ And wipe away
your inhibitions
♪ Stomp, stomp, stomp,
do the romp and
strut your stuff
♪ Bop bop bop,
straight to the top... ♪
CHAD: No problem at all.
It was crazy, man.
Callback's the same time
as the game?
And the scholastic decathlon.
Why would they do that?
I smell a rat named Darbus.
I think two rats,
neither named Darbus.
Do you know
something about this,
small person?
Miss Darbus thinks
she's protecting the show,
but Ryan and Sharpay
are only concerned with
protecting themselves.
Do you know what I'll do
to those two show dogs?
Nothing. We're not gonna
do anything to them.
Except to sing, maybe.
Now this is only gonna happen
if we all work together.
Now who's in?
CHAD: You know I'm in.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
ZEKE: A pi pie.
(GASPS)
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, my gosh!
What? Thank you!
Oh, we have
something for you, too.
Yeah, come here, look.
BOTH: Ta-da!
Oh, it's an equation.
PLAYERS: Oh!
That's awful!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Stay right there. Watch.
From our team, to yours.
G-O D-R-A-M-A C-L-U-B.
Exclamation point.
Well, seems we Wildcats are in
for an interesting afternoon.
Go.
G-O-D... Go dra...
Go dra... Go dray...
Ugh!
Drame?
(BELL RINGS)
(STUDENTS SCREAMING
EXCITEDLY)
(DRUMS BEATING)
(SUPPORTERS
CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
How you feeling?
Nervous.
Yeah, me, too.
Wish I could suit
up and play with you.
Hey, you had your turn.
You know what I
want from you today?
The championship.
Well, that'll come
or it won't.
What I want is
for you to have fun.
I know all about the pressure.
Probably too much of it
has come from me.
What I really
want is to see my son
having the time of his life
playing the game we both love.
You give me that,
and I will sleep
with a smile on my face
no matter what the score.
Thanks, Coach...
Dad.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MALE COMMENTATOR:
Welcome to the 10th annual
Scholastic Decathlon.
The East High Wildcats versus
the West High Knights.
(SUPPORTERS CHEERING)
Hello! Right here, right here.
(BOTH VOCALIZING)
Stop!
I trust you.
Energy.
Come on, let's do it.
(ALL CHEERING)
MALE COMMENTATOR:
And now introducing
your East High Wildcats!
Let's go! Go!
...for this championship game
between East High
and West High!
(CLOCK TICKING)
Casting the leads
of a show is both
a challenge and
a responsibility.
A joy and a burden.
I commend you and all other
young artists to hold out
for the moon,
the sun and the stars.
Shall we soar together?
Sharpay and Ryan!
(SALSA MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BOTH VOCALIZING)
♪ I believe in dreaming
Shooting for the stars
♪ Baby to be number one
You've got to raise the bar
♪ Kicking and a scratching
Grinding out my best
♪ Anything it takes to climb
The ladder of success
♪ Work our tails off every day
♪ Gotta bump the competition
Blow them all away
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
♪ Yeah we're gonna
♪ Bop, bop, bop
Bop to the top
♪ Slip and slide
and ride that rhythm
♪ Jump and hop
Hop till we drop
♪ And start again
♪ Zip zap zop
Pop like a mop
♪ Scoot around the corner
♪ Move it to the groove
Till the music stops
♪ Do the bop,
bop, bop to the top
♪ Don't ever stop
Bop to the top
♪ Gimme, gimme,
shimmy, shimmy
Wildcats!
COMMENTATOR: ...the coveted
championship trophy!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
East High wins
the opening, too,
pushing the ball up the court.
(DINGS)
JUDGE: East High.
GABRIELLA: We did it!
Great job!
♪ Shake some booty
and turn around
♪ Flash a smile
in their direction
♪ Show some muscle
♪ Do the hustle
All right, Wildcats, time for
an orderly exit from the gym.
And West High
pushes the ball around
the perimeter on
the offensive end.
Nice ball movement
by West High.
Driving the lane,
shot is up and...
(ALARM BUZZING)
We seem to be experiencing
some technical difficulties.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
We've got a timeout
on the court here.
We have a problem.
Stop the game. Stop the game.
COMMENTATOR:
Referee has signaled timeout.
Everyone, please remain calm.
(EXCLAIMING)
Go, go, go, go.
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN DISGUST)
We'll get this
figured out real soon.
In the meantime,
per safety regulations,
we need to all
make an orderly exit
from the gym, please.
Thank you.
♪ Yeah, we're gonna
bop, bop, bop
♪ Bop to the top
Wipe away your inhibitions
♪ Stump, stump, stump
Do the romp
♪ And strut your stuff
♪ Bop, bop, bop
Straight to the top
♪ Going for the glory
♪ We'll keep stepping up
And we just won't stop
♪ Till we reach the top
♪ Bop to the top ♪
(APPLAUSE)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Oh, hi! Call me.
Do you see why we
love the theater,
people? Well done!
Troy Bolton, Gabriella Montez.
Troy? Gabriella?
They'll be here.
The theater,
as I have often pointed out,
waits for no one. I'm sorry.
Well, we are done here.
Congratulations to all.
(DOOR OPENING)
The cast list will be posted.
Wait! Miss Darbus, wait!
We're ready, we can sing.
I called your names, twice.
Miss Darbus, please! Please!
Rules are rules!
(ALL CLAMORING)
We'll be happy to do it again
for our fellow students.
I don't know
what's going on here,
but in any event,
it's far too late
and we have not got a pianist.
Well, that's showbiz.
We'll sing without a piano.
Oh, no, you won't.
Pianist here, Miss Darbus.
You really
don't wanna do that.
Oh, yes, I really do.
Ready on stage.
(SQUEALS SOFTLY)
Now that's showbiz.
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
(PLAYING SLOW MELODY)
(SHUDDERING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
I can't do it, Troy,
not with all these
people staring at me.
Hey, hey, look at me,
right at me.
Right at me.
Like the first time
we sang together, remember?
Like kindergarten.
♪ We're soaring, flying
♪ There's not a star in heaven
that we can't reach
♪ If we're trying
so we're breaking free
♪ You know
the world can see us
♪ In a way that's different
than who we are
♪ Creating space between us
till we're separate hearts
♪ But your faith
it gives me strength
♪ Strength to believe
♪ We're breaking free
♪ We're soaring
(TEMPO PICKS UP)
♪ Flying
♪ There's not a star in heaven
that we can't reach
♪ If we're trying
♪ Yeah, we're breaking free
♪ Oh, we're breaking free
♪ Can you feel it building
♪ Like a wave the ocean
just can't control?
♪ Connected by a feeling
in our very soul
♪ Very soul
♪ Rising till it lifts us up
♪ So everyone can see
♪ We're breaking free
♪ We're soaring
♪ Flying
♪ There's not a star in heaven
that we can't reach
♪ If we're trying
♪ Yeah, we're breaking free
TROY:
♪ Oh, we're breaking free
♪ Running
♪ Climbing
♪ To get to that place
to be all that we can be
♪ Now's the time
♪ So we're breaking free
♪ We're breaking free
♪ Ooh, yeah
♪ More than hope,
more than faith
♪ This is true, this is fate
♪ And together
we see it coming
♪ More than you, more than me
♪ Not a want, but a need
♪ Both of us breaking free
♪ Soaring
♪ Flying
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
♪ There's not a star in heaven
that we can't reach
♪ If we're trying
♪ Yeah, we're breaking free
♪ Breaking free
♪ We're running
♪ Ooh, climbing
♪ To get to the place
to be all that we can be
♪ Now's the time
♪ So we're breaking free
♪ Oh, we're breaking free
♪ You know the world
can see us
♪ In a way that's different
than who we are ♪
(AUDIENCE ROARING)
STUDENT 1: That was amazing!
STUDENT 2: Amazing, yeah!
MALE COMMENTATOR:
And West High
pushing the ball.
Fast break.
Looking for an open man.
Oh, but it's stolen
by number 14 heading
back the other way!
East High has the ball!
Time is running
down on the clock!
Looking for an open man.
Fake. Swing to the outside.
Ball in the perimeter.
Looks for a man in the inside.
Nice screen.
Shot's up! And it's good!
A 12-foot jump shot as time
expires for the victory!
East High has won
the championship!
Your East High Wildcats
are champions!
Congratulations, East High!
(CHANTING) Troy! Troy! Troy!
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Coming through!
PLAYERS: What team?
SUPPORTERS: Wildcats!
What team?
Wildcats!
Get your head in the game!
Oh, yeah, bro!
I'm proud of you, son!
Thanks, Dad!
Bravo!
Brava!
BOY: Troy, you're the man!
No, you!
Congratulations, Wildcat!
What about your team?
We won, too!
Yo! Team voted you
the game ball. Captain!
Yeah, thank you.
Thanks a lot.
So, you're going with me
to the after-party, right?
Like on a date?
Must be your lucky day.
Chad just asked me out.
Well, congratulations.
I'll be the understudy
in case you
can't make a show, so
break a leg.
In theater that
means good luck.
Hey, Sharpay,
I'm sorry you didn't get
the lead, but I
think you're really good.
I admire you so much.
And, why wouldn't you?
Now, bye-bye.
Wait, I baked you
some cookies.
Ew.
Nice game.
Thanks.
Composer,
here's your game ball.
You deserve it, playmaker.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah!
That's what
I'm talking about.
♪ Here we go!
♪ Together, together,
together everyone
come on, let's have some fun
♪ Together, we're there
for each other every time
♪ Together, together,
come on, let's do this right
♪ Here and now it's
time for celebration
♪ I finally figured out
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ That all our dreams
have no limitations
♪ That's what it's all about
♪ Come on, now
♪ Everyone is
special in their own way
♪ We make each other strong
♪ Each other strong
♪ We're not the same,
we're different in a good way
♪ Together's where we belong
♪ We're all in this together
♪ Once we know that we are,
we're all stars
and we see that
♪ We're all in this together
♪ And it shows when we stand
hand in hand
♪ Make our dreams come true
♪ Everybody now
♪ Together, together,
together, everyone
come on, let's have some fun
♪ Together, we're there
for each other every time
♪ Together, together,
come on, let's do this right
♪ We're all here and speaking
out with one voice
♪ We're gonna rock the house,
yeah, yeah
♪ The party's on,
now everybody make some noise
♪ Come on, scream and shout
♪ We've arrived
because we stuck together
♪ Champions one and all
♪ We're all in this together
♪ Once we know that we are,
we're all stars
and we see that
♪ We're all in this together
♪ And it shows when we stand
hand in hand
♪ Make our dreams come
♪ We're all in this together
♪ When we reach, we can fly,
know inside we can make it
♪ We're all in his together
♪ Once we see there's a chance
that we have and we take it
♪ Wildcats sing along
♪ Yeah, you really
got it going on
♪ Wildcats in the house
♪ Everybody say it now
♪ Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands up in the air
♪ That's the way we do it
Let's get to it
♪ Time to show the world
♪ Hey!
♪ Ho!
♪ Hey! Ho!
All right, here we go!
♪ We're all in this together
♪ Once we know that we are
we're all stars
and we see that
♪ We're all in this together
♪ And it shows when we stand
hand in hand
♪ Make our dreams come true
♪ We're all in this together
♪ When we reach, we can fly,
know inside we can make it
♪ We're all in this together
♪ Once we see there's a chance
that we have and we take it
♪ Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands up in the air
♪ That's the way we do it
let's get to it
♪ Come on, everyone!
Yeah!
Yeah! Go.
Wildcats sing along
Yeah, you really
got it going on
Wildcats in the house
Everybody sing out
Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands up in the air
That's the way we do it
Let's get to it
Time to show the world
Wildcats sing along
Yeah, you really
got it going on
Wildcats in the house
Everybody say it now
Wildcats everywhere
Wave your hands up in the air
That's the way we do it
Let's get to it
Time to show... ♪
(PANTING)
These cookies are genius!
The best things
I've ever tasted!
Will you make some more
for me, Zeke?
I might even make
you a creme brulee.