I do.
No.
You should have killed me, Ethan.
Fate whispers to fighters ...
there was a storm coming.
And fighters whisper back ...
I'm the storm.
lD ENTlTAS DlK ENALl
HUNT, ETHAN M.
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
Solomon Lane the anarchist.
Ever since you caught him two years ago ...
his absence raises
an unexpected result.
Syndicate agents continue
create chaos around the world.
Dvisi Special Activity ClA ...
hunting down Lane's elite network.
But many are still
unknown and free.
The rest of her gang called herself
as '' Apostles. ''
They are wage terror, making them
a more serious threat.
They are the culprit of smallpox
in the Indian region of Kashmir ...
on the border of China and Pakistan,
threatening one-third of the world's population.
The plague has been dammed ...
But intelligence says there are new clients
renting Apostles ...
for a more ambitious operation.
They are contacted by extremists
with the code name John Lark ...
this doomsday designer ...
intend to destroy
the existing world order.
Lark is responsible
for the loss of nuclear experts
from Norway, Nils Delbruuk.
Dr. lizard Delbruuk revoked ...
after he expressed his views
about anti-religion.
Apostles communicate with
Eastern European criminal organization ...
which has three stolen plutonium nuclei
from a rocket base in eastern Russia.
This shows
John Lark and Apostles ...
work together to have
a functioning nuclear weapon.
According to N EST people with knowledge
Delbruuk, wearing existing materia ...
can complete three weapons
as fast as 72 hours.
This tool is portable and can be
sent to anywhere overnight.
In the hands of John Lark and Apostles,
this weapon will be a big threat ...
for millions of people.
Your mission, if you accept it ...
prevent Apostles from getting plutonium
by all means.
If you or another lMF member
caught or killed ...
The Minister will deny your action.
Good luck, Ethan.
This message will crumble in five seconds.
He's late.
- He's never too late.
- He will come.
I do not like it.
There's something out of this guy
which creeps.
Take it easy.
I'm calm.
It does not sound.
Luther, he sounds calm?
He sounded scared.
I am not afraid.
Just had a bad feeling.
You said you were calm.
It could be people feel
calm and anxious at the same time.
- Can not.
- You often do.
- No.
- Yes.
No.
I have to believe this moment
you feel calm ...
Benji.
in the dark alley to buy plutonium
from a psychopath?
Benji, I look after you.
Look, Benji? You're completely safe.
Easy for you to talk, you're in the car.
You want a field assignment.
Tonight I want in the car, Luther!
He's coming.
God.
Prepare the money, Luther.
Good.
Ethan, you hear?
Did you hear?
Are we going to do this or not?
I stay in this business
for the help of a voice in my head.
This voice is never wrong.
And every time you meet ...
this voice says the same thing.
What is that?
There is no.
I'm here to do business.
Have the voice throw a coin.
What is that?
It's a beryllium stick that reacts
with plutonium in the core.
All original.
The money?
The money.
Here comes the money.
Luther, bring the money here.
We need the money, Luther.
Kill them.
Let me take it!
Luther, you hear?
Luther!
Luther, answer.
Luther is not here.
What Apostles can do for you ...
Hunt?
-What do you want?
- You're stuck, Hunt.
Give her plutonium and go.
Benji, bring the car here.
- Can not.
- Benji.
Bring a car here.
Let's make a deal, Hunt.
Give him plutonium
and your friend we did not kill.
No, Ethan! Not for me!
I counted three.
One.
- Two.
- Luther ...
- Forgive me.
- Three.
Sorry. I do not know what else to do.
It is okay.
- You are okay?
- I should have died.
We should all die.
Why not?
Where is the plutonium?
Missing.
If you just joined ...
three big explosions happened together ...
which is a coordinated attack.
This is a live show from Rome,
overlooking the Vatican ...
and our camera is as close as possible.
The pope is believed to be inside the residence
when the explosion happened ...
We also live from Jerusalem
just outside his city.
Also from the holy city of Mecca ...
from USS Ronald Reagan on the Red Sea,
near offshore Saudi Arabia.
Radiation detected ...
shows nuclear weapons used
in this terrible attack.
Ethan ... it's time.
assuming news of casualties
which is suspected to be high.
Reportedly the weapon used ...
requires special knowledge
which few people have.
The question is who is attacking
these three sacred sites? And why?
Attacks occur at the same time,
an hour ago ...
at 04.00 Eastern Wakti.
A few minutes later,
Congress issued an emergency recess ...
and the Capotil Building was evacuated.
The president left Washington
with Air Force One.
The White House declared a state of emergency ...
and the military is on standby one.
Leave us.
Dr. Delbruuk.
We know who you are.
We read the manifesto,
we found your lab.
No peace
without great suffering.
'' The greater the suffering
the greater the peace. ''
This will bring them together.
As they read this manifesto,
they will understand.
No one will read the manifesto.
I guarantee.
What day is it?
How long am I here?
What did you last remember?
I'm driving.
-There's bumped me.
- That was two weeks ago.
- Two weeks?
- Two weeks.
It's yours, is not it?
This is how Lark communicates with you.
- Lark?
- John Lark.
- We know all about him.
- You do not know anything.
There is information on this phone
to find it.
You got the code.
You think Lark is an enemy.
But you...
whoever you are, you are the enemy.
Because you're the system of survival.
- Why suffering goes on.
- Shut up!
We do not care about you.
We want Lark.
- Want to make a deal?
- No, Luther.
Exit.
Give me five minutes with her.
No. We can not do that.
Maybe we should consider that.
If they read the manifesto
on television?
- You can?
- With one call.
If he reads Lark manifesto ...
No.
I'll provide the password code.
Ethan! Ethan!
Think, Ethan. For the sake of many people.
Yes, think.
Sir.
He will not cooperate.
Right, sir.
If you read the manifesto ...
on television.
Sorry, Sir.
Global markets and trade plummeted.
Wait. Reportedly we will accept
additional information.
I just received the document
from Nils Delbruuk ...
a nuclear weapons expert who makes
weapons in this attack.
I was asked to read this manifesto.
'' There is no peace
without great suffering.
'' The greater the suffering,
the greater the peace.
'' People are captivated to destroy themselves
such as moths with candles ...
'' then the defenders of peace ...
Church, government, law ...
'' trying to save humans
of itself. ''
This will not help you now.
"But by preventing disaster,
they postpone peace ... ''
Rice has become porridge.
'' which can only be obtained through
baptism of fire.
'' The suffering that I carry is not
beginning of end. This is the beginning of each other ... ''
Can already be?
'' This is the first step towards
unity of man. ''
Could.
'' The peace I am carrying is
bridge to true peace. ''
Do it.
Could?
GuavaBerry
Certain.
I told you we will succeed.
I do not understand.
The attack did not happen?
Your car crash ...
that was an hour ago.
I hit you.
Just finished...
if we say finished.
AIR RANK OF RAMST ElN, J ERMAN
The phone you opened brought us
to servers in lsl ...
where we unveil communication
between John Lark and this woman:
Alana Mitsopolis, activist and philanthropist ...
dubbed White Widow
for his charity work.
It's just a pseudonym as
arms dealer, money laundering.
Extensive political connections
give him protection.
Lark and Widow meet tonight
to negotiate package shipments ...
which is suspected of our plutonium.
They will meet in a private space
in Grad Palais, Paris ...
during the annual fundraiser.
The details are in the file.
If until midnight Lark did not show up,
Widow will sell to the highest bidder.
So you have ...
two hours to find Lark.
There's something you have to know.
Just get there.
You have a tough choice in Berlin.
Plutonium or your regimen. You choose
your regulation, the world is in danger now.
Disadvantages in yourself ...
makes you can not choose
between one life and millions of lives.
To you it's a weakness.
To me, that's your greatest strength.
So I know you can count on me
to look after me.
Moving here from the ClA is a step
lateral, some say decline.
But I did ...
Because of you.
Do not make me regret it.
Call.
Turn off the engine.
-What are you doing, Erika?
- Maybe this is your mission ...
but this is a CIA plane.
Will not take off without my permission.
We need reliable information,
now.
This is where lMF exists!
lMF is Halloween, Alan.
A group of people wear rubber masks
ask for candy or dijahili.
If he keeps his plutonium
in Berlin, we're not going to discuss this.
- His team can die.
- Yes. Can be.
It's part of the job.
That's why I want my people to come ...
to assess the situation.
Agent Walker, Special Activist.
I've heard of his reputation.
You're wearing a scalpel.
I prefer a hammer.
My or ...
or no one left.
Do not get in the way
get the plutonium.
No Hunt, his team, or anyone else.
White Widow has spies
in every layer of government.
This aircraft is considered commercial so we are
can plunge into France undetected.
Widow meet Lark
in the midnight VlP room.
No one signed in without
electronic tape.
We have a number for RFLD for ribbon
Lark so we can find it ...
with this.
Find the tape,
You found Lark.
So what?
Then...
I use his identity ...
and meet Widow.
He brings us to the package.
People are deceived in this way?
What are your plans for Lark to work together?
I hit him in the crowd.
In 10 seconds, he's just as drunk with
others, confused and easily influenced.
After I borrowed his face,
You take him to the front door ...
and hand him over to Sloane's extraction team.
You can not get rid of me
Easy as that, Hunt.
That's not the point.
Of course that's the goal.
I know you do not want me to come.
But face it:
If you take a hard decision
in Berlin, I will not be here.
If you do not shoot every die
Syndicate agent you find ...
I will not be here.
Yes, I know all about you.
Because of you, there are no living witnesses
to recognize John Lark ...
or Apostles.
If you object to my way,
You may retreat.
'' Your mission, if you accept it. ''
I see, is not it?
Two minutes before decompression.
Get ready.
Widow meet Lark in 30 minutes.
Ten seconds before decompression.
Your oxygen is on?
There is no atmosphere at this altitude.
Do not faint.
The display has a guide system,
follow to the goal.
Open the parachute according to the cue of the system,
not before, let alone after ...
or the last thing crosses your mind
is your knee. Understand?
Very clear.
You need to think again.
- Move out.
- There's a storm. We need...
Simply talk. See you in Paris.
Come on, come on, come on.
Elevation: 7.5 Km.
Walker?
What's up, Hunt? You're afraid of a little lightning?
Elevation: 6 Km.
God damn it.
Walker?
Did you hear?
Come on.
Elevation: 4.5 Km.
Walker.
Walker!
Elevation: 3 Km.
2.7 Km.
Disastrous.
2.4 Km.
2.1 Km.
1.8 Km.
1.5 Km.
1.2 Km.
Walker!
900 meters.
Open the parachute. Open the parachute.
Open the parachute.
God.
You lost your oxygen.
There Widow meets Lark.
Walker!
Tell me again! Where...
Ethan.
- In his man?
- No need.
Raise him up.
Do not be shy.
The more crowded the more exciting.
Come on, we're not rude.
- Can I join?
- We do not bite.
Shit.
- Can you still make a mask?
- Need a face to make a mask.
Sorry. I took aim at his chest.
- Why are you here?
-I am also glad to see you.
Sorry, I'm confused. You...?
Old friend.
Cancel extraction. Status blue code.
Send a cleaning team.
Northern men's room.
You did not answer me.
Why are you here?
Nice. Take it easy.
Look up until the bleeding stops.
What do you want?
Do you want me too?
You're not alone here.
Who sent you?
I can not say.
- What do you want?
- Dating with White Widow.
He's dating the Widow.
You do not look like him.
Hope they never meet.
- Hoping is not a strategy!
- You must be a new person.
No other choice.
White Widow is the only clue.
I must be this person
for five minutes.
- Do not do it.
-What?
What is wrong? What are you keeping secret?
You do not understand what it's involved in.
I do not understand what's involved.
I do not understand what involved?
What do I get involved with?
If you want to meet Widow,
he's gone in three minutes.
- Ethan!
-I will succeed.
My name is Walker.
Oh, yes? Thank you again.
- What do you want?
- Come with you.
- Should not.
-There are people sent to kill Lark.
-I know.
- Not me. Rented. Assassin.
They do not know his face,
just know will meet Widow
They'll think you're Lark
and will kill you.
How do you know all this?
I can not say.
You should not come back.
You should come with me.
This charity begins to honor my mother.
For those who know him
understand its power ...
persistence, intelligence.
But there is another side of him
which many people do not know.
Part of his soul
which brings us all ...
gathered tonight.
Max is a paradox.
GuavaBerry
He is interested in paradoxical things ...
interest that I inherited.
Max had no idea
about our world today.
But he has a dream
will be a different future.
The future is no longer
requires his unique talent.
Everything he learned from the world ...
used to make
the world is getting better.
The future has not yet arrived.
Tonight, your contribution ...
bringing that future
a little closer.
Thank you for coming.
Enjoy the party.
You can not be John Lark.
It is not.
That's an alias.
That's better than John Doe.
Any other names you like?
Any place to talk?
I like '' Lark. ''
It sounds good.
Our time is little.
Honestly, with your reputation,
I expect people ...
which is worse.
Do not be fooled appearance.
I'm so bad.
And to be honest. You're in danger.
Do not touch him.
Quiet. He's my brother.
You're not polite
with our guest, Zola.
Time to go.
Do not make a fuss.
You do not want to be with this guy.
-What did you say?
- You're in danger.
- Who wants to kill me?
- First, Americans.
If that's true, I certainly will know.
Think you're the only one you have
spy in government?
Some people do not want to
this meeting took place.
Can not believe it?
Look around you.
I know your thoughts.
Maybe they're not after you.
Maybe just after me.
Are you ready to take that risk?
You have what I want.
Right now, only me can
get you out alive.
I want to go home now.
The French government accepts
assets of midday.
Tomorrow morning at 6 o'clock brought
to the Minister of Finance by air.
Armed police
will escort this route.
We make a diversion at this intersection.
Light will take
backup route here ...
where we take the assets.
Take his assets?
Assets.
We pay dearly for this information.
They give it all
except the person's name.
He's Solomon Lane.
An English Special Agent who became anarchist.
He collects the defector's agents
for a terror network called Sindikat.
Sabotage, murder,
mass slaughter.
They are very bad.
He was arrested by American agents
two years ago.
Since then, he has lived
endless interrogation ...
moved from the government
to other governments ...
to be responsible
for his crimes.
You look unhappy, Lark.
Maybe I'm not clear.
I went to Paris for plutonium.
There must be a misunderstanding.
I'm just an intermediary.
I connect buyers and sellers.
My seller does not want cash,
so if you want plutonium ...
Free Lane ...
and exchange it.
Correct.
Where do I know the seller got what I want?
Advance as a good faith.
The courier will send two more
in 48 hours ...
instead of him.
Good.
What happens after the redirect?
Kill it all?
- Is that your plan?
- No witnesses.
My aphrodisiac, Lane
will survive this plan?
He's in a steel car.
We get him out after it's safe.
You want plutonium ...
... this is the price ...
Or kill the police
past your limitations?
You're talking to John Lark.
I killed a woman
and children with smallpox.
I have no limits.
Good. Sleep well.
Tomorrow's a busy day.
Seriously.
If you want to free Lane ...
... here's how ...
-I want Lane to set him free,
Not Ethan Hunt.
I want a lark in exchange.
I want Lark to drive us
to plutonium ...
... and Aposiles ...
You might get your chance.
You lupajasad in the men's room,
at the Grand Palais?
I do not think it's Lark.
- Mungin Lark's men.
- Not according to our informants.
Whose information collected?
Hunt.
You've been suspicious for a long time
Lark is an American agent.
People who know our every move,
come and go like a ghost.
You mean Hunt is John Lark?
You set Walker.
You want to save your life.
It will not work.
Think.
What people are always careful about
as Lark is willing to take risks
like that?
Bethadapan with White Widow?
- He'll send a representative.
- Bait.
If he's smart ...
... he told his girlfriend
killing the bait ...
... in front of witness ...
I.
The scream is almost revealed.
Then he pays people to ...
... being Lark ...
... then kill him ...
And by pretending to serve the country ...
That's our secret identity.
- Free to operate, fully supported by the government
America.
- Why?
Why with Hunt?
Why did Lane and the Apostles defect?
They believe in a purpose.
When that goal turns out to be a lie.
They attacked their master.
How many times did the Hunt government,
betray him, deny it?
How many people like that ...
- ... finally feel sick?
- It's a charge ...
...serious...
Can you prove it?
I'm guessing the evidence you need
It is there.
Can Lane gas a village?
which contains 2 thousand people?
Yes.
- Yes he dropped the passenger plane ...
... for killing one person?
Yes.
- Is he really ...
- Hey. Walker.
Any story that makes you cringe ...
... maybe that's right ...
God.
You caught him, right?
How long do you think it lasts
he will keep your identity a secret?
We'll fix the problem later.
.
What did he do?
Come on!
Hurry up.
Come on.
Hurry up!
Hunt? Where are you?
- Do not wait for me!
-What is wrong?
We meet in the garage.
Benji, you hear?
We heard, talk.
Change plan, I got caught.
Pick me up.
We're on our way.
Stop!
Stay where you are.
- Get in the car.
- Do not move.
Raise your hand.
- Go on, please ...
- Everyone, raise your hand.
Go.
Just go, please.
Just go.
Zola wants to talk to you.
- What about him?
- Kill him.
You'll be all right.
Take it easy.
(B ERBlkARA BAHASAASlNG)
We have to go.
Forgive me.
Come on.
My name is Walker.
Your little car?
God!
What was that?
- All out.
-Come on!
.
Come on!
Move out!
That's llsa.
Shut up.
Interesting.
Glad to see you again, Ethan.
Oh, he's alive.
There is a microwave tracker
around his neck.
Understand. You know what to do.
I guarantee it does not hurt.
90 seconds ...
You and Apostles think us
will welcome you ...
... with plutonium ...
I want to say it will not happen.
'' Your mission if you accept it ''
Tell me, Ethan ....
You ever rejected it?
Ever asked who gave you
command, or why?
While you are getting closer ...
- ... ending the world ...
- Strange charges ...
- ... of a terrorist ...
- 60 seconds.
Terrorists are schoolgirls
who seek attention, try
forming public opinion through fear.
I do not care who that person is
think or feel.
According to my experience,
both did not last long.
And that justifies the plant bombing
or dropping ...
... aircraft ...
-Or bind me with a vest ...
- ... explosives ...
- It's an unfinished business ...
- ... my cute friend ...
- Luther?
- A little bit more.
You see the end as clearly as I am, Ethan.
The governments of the world go crazy,
syndicate...
... it is devoted to breaking down
they, brick by brick ...
Syndicates are herds
cowardly killer.
Syndicates are expectations
last civilization!
Opportunities to destroy
old world order.
Hope it's the same because you ...
... and your sad morals ...
You should kill me, Ethan.
The end you've always feared ...
will arrive.
Will arrive!
You will be responsible.
The destruction ...
... of all your good intentions ...
- Time has run out.
- Could.
Wake him up.
You're mine now.
You're full of surprises, Lark.
Your brother's plan is bad
from the beginning.
Your man can die.
And Lane could be shot dead.
I had to improvise.
- Why not say from scratch?
- Because I do not trust your man.
Especially your brother.
Family or how else?
So where is Lane?
- Definitely not in the Seine market.
-There's to me.
She's safe.
Where can I meet Victoria?
You're talking about that woman.
- Women?
- He's with you at the Palais.
Zola saw it again today.
He tried to kill Lane.
He had a chance to kill him,
but not taken.
Why?
We have history.
That's complicated.
I'll make it more complicated for you.
But my family has just gone up.
Somebody killed my parents,
I guess he was the culprit.
I want him, Lark.
You leave it to me.
Or you will not see the kirirnya
and plutonium is given to the highest bidder.
I do not want him to get in our way.
You'll get it.
At the meeting. Not before.
He went to London.
Receive instructions.
I know if you follow him,
you will appear.
You are okay?
- I do not want to hurt you.
-I know you have a reason.
I know.
Step back.
Can not.
You're not at the Palais to kill Lark.
- No.
- You want to protect her.
- Yes.
- You killed him to protect me.
You want Lark to free Lane.
No. You need him to free Lane.
Because you have to kill Lane.
Who told you to?
Ml6.
Why?
After we catch him in London ...
... they try to bring Lane home,
through diplomatic channels ...
Naum too many countries are looking for it.
That kind of person he saw
and know about the British intelligence.
... will not let them be taken away
to foreign governments ...
- Why did they send you?
- This is my way of proving my loyalty.
- This is my way to go home.
- But you're out.
- You're free.
- We're never free.
Two years I was disguised with Lane.
- For them, I'm also a threat like Lane.
-I have to kill him.
Or keep running away.
Tell her where.
I can not help you.
I will find it in any way.
Do not make me step over you.
- Yes?
- You're in London?
Ready to meet the courier?
Yes, where am I supposed to be?
Where to meet?
I pray this is not true.
To defend it, sir, if Ethan ....
- ... not intervention many people can die.
- Yes, Dunn, I'm sure ...
... the people of Paris are good and all over
France will take that into account ...
Then what happen?
... that's where we were told to London ...
- ... and wait for instructions ....
- And what happened?
Now...
... we meet the widow in 20 min ...
He drove us to the courier,
which will swap the plutionium with
Solomon Lane ...
Or, in our scenario ...
- Benji ...
-Affice.
-What did you say?
- Luther and I drove you to the messenger
Walker guarding Lane ....
- ...The original...
- No.
- Why me being Lane?
- Benji ...
- Our mission-my mission ...
... is to find the plutonium,
and I will do it any way.
- Despite having to hand Lane over.
- The original lane.
-I will not let him go.
- If the Apostles know you're cheating them ...
- You'll lose the plutionium again.
- Let us worry about Apostles.
- Currently, there is a bigger problem.
- Bigger problem?
- Ours? llsa Faust Lisa?
Why did he get involved?
- He ordered Ml6 to kill Lane.
Wait, he's in Paris?
- By motorcycle, Ethan he tried
kill us!
- Not us.
- He wants to kill Lane,
he has no choice.
- And He'll kill me.
- I will not let you.
- How to?
- I'm thinking.
- Oh, he's thinking.
- Our time is narrow, must be prepared
for this meeting.
- This meeting is a trap.
White Widow works with ClA.
From the beginning.
He did to keep his business safe.
Getting Plutonium,
Apostles, and John Lark ...
- ... he will be trusted by America ...
- But if Sloane knows this is a trap.
- why did not he say?
- Because in his mind, anyone can be
John Lark ...
... including one of our ...
Now his suspicions were proven.
According to the document, there is evidence of traces
electronics that hook Hunt ...
... with cache theft from CDC ...
Also associate it with recruitment ...
... Doctor Dellbruuk,
and Hunt herself who submitted the plutonium
to Apostles ...
Plus a long history about
defiant behavior ...
... corroborating the ClA statement ....
... that Hunt defected ...
And the search is just to hide
that Lark ...
- ... is me ...
-I admit it, Ethan.
Usually the biggest enemy
is the only self ...
... an allegory ...
Sloane also had questions for him.
Widow offers llsa at no additional cost.
Where does Sloane get this information?
He did not say.
But he gave me a chance to take you ...
... come home from this mission I cancel ...
- ... and surrendered Solomon Lane.
- Do not do that, sir.
- Hunt.
-I know Lane, he has no intention of returning.
- That's why we bring him back.
That's what he wants us to do.
Sir, what do you think happens to be?
Someone accidentally found this?
Lane that sends to Sloane.
Lane knew what his reaction was, like
he knows Widow will hand us over,
understand?
Here, sir.
It's a trap.
- We are directed.
- Hunt! Still two plutonium cores ...
- ... not found!
- And you lost both!
In fact, sir.
We lost ...
- ... the plutonium.
- With respect, sir.
- You're not there.
- As your duty makes excuses for him?
Ethan, do not ...
... worsening circumstances,
I can not protect you anymore ...
...understand?
You can not pursue that plutonium anymore.
- Sir, you can not believe this.
-I'm given the opportunity to ...
... protect you or lMF, that's why ...
... I brought you home ...
If I refuse?
You think he's here for what?
Think you're a suitor?
He's a killer!
Closing number one Erika Slpane!
If you defected,
he is allowed to hunt you
... and kill you ...
That's my job, do not grudge.
Accept it, Ethan.
This time you lost, it's over.
No sir.
No.
I'm not asking you,
I give you orders.
The mission is canceled.
Now!
Stickett, he's your friend ...
Can talk to her ...
Sorry, Sir.
But you did not give me a choice.
15 minutes before meeting Widow,
Only us ....
... who can get his plutonium,
Are you coming or not?
- Come on.
-What are you doing?
- Benji must get ready.
- No, Ethan.
- No time.
Believe me.
You are okay?
Yes, I just ...
... have a bad feeling for this one ...
If no news from us ...
I use my way.
Keep watching him.
Simply playful.
I brought you out.
It is okay.
Just follow the instructions.
The real threat
already in our hands.
Is that so?
Do it.
Where's Lane?
First team on paralyzed send help.
Sir!
There's an injury!
Please!
Sir.
Ethan, I marked Walker, but he ran away.
You have to go after him.
Go.
I'm sorry, sir.
Ethan?
GuavaBerry
Wait!
Catch the bebedah.
Come on, come on, come on.
Yes! Could.
Sorry.
Tell me, Benji, Where's Walker?
About 400 meters west
if you turn right.
My Channel?
I can not.
Why?
Because you are followed.
You mean? By whom?
Where do I know? ClA, Aposties, what's the difference?
Exit from there then right.
Forgive me.
Why is he spinning around?
Cross the road on your left as soon as possible.
Ethan you hear? Go left now.
I do it again.
Now cross the road in front of you.
In the farther! You should be faster.
You caught up with him!
Straight.
Keep straight ahead?
Straight, straight, straight.
Now go right.
Right?
- Now?
- Yes right.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, me...
No, to the left, sorry the screen is locked.
Thanks.
- What are you waiting for?
-I jump from the window!
What do you mean to jump from ...
Sorry. but the picture is two dimensional.
Good luck.
At the end of the bridge to the left,
You almost caught up with him.
Come on, get him! You're on it!
He's in front of you! Catch him!
Can not, huh? Not before
You can plutonium.
No. He still has a plan for you.
You can surrender and
confess yourself John Lark ...
then watch the old world
explode from your little cell.
If you do not want to?
I'm his guardian angel, Hunt.
If I see you again, he dies.
If you try to warn him, he dies.
Know when you lost.
This is the design we find from Dr.
Delburk in Berlin.
It's a five megaton nuclear bomb.
It's stronger than an explosive
during World War II.
To disarm our ordinary
cut the fuse cable here.
Usually?
Walker and Lane have two cores
pulutonium means two bombs.
Both are connected with siyal
the safety risks are very accurate.
If one bomb is disarmed,
other bombs will explode.
It means that once activated,
both bombs can not be stripped.
Countdown is enabled with
remot, which is also a safety.
It means that countdown in start ...
can not stop.
So what is the solution?
We're thinking.
... technically, it's a suicide mission.
What is wrong?
Sit down, please.
For years I've known Ethan ...
He is only serious with two women.
First his wife.
He is married?
It was.
Was it? What happened?
She was kidnapped ...
By someone who wants to harm Ethan.
Calm down, ethan managed to save him.
Then Ethan stopped.
They are happy for some time.
Namu every time there is a thing
bad happens in the world ...
Ethan thought I should be there.
His wife thinks who's keeping it
Ethan's world watch over me?
Both of them know that one day ...
something very bad will happen ...
Because they are together.
So...
- Where is he now?
- He's hiding.
He is good at hiding.
I taught him.
Occasionally he sends a signal
so Ethan knows he's safe.
That makes Ethan power.
Why would you tell me this?
All messed up because of Ethan
do not let me die.
He's a good guy.
He cares about you
More than he admits.
It's one more burden
can he bear this moment.
If you care about her ...
...Go.
No.
Everything is fine?
I am coming along.
I know.
How to find it?
Microwave transmitter.
Can be tracked with
satellites around the world.
Lane had one behind his neck.
We pull it out in paris.
And put our transmitter.
Could.
Activation in snooze 36 hours ...
Who knows Aposties is scanning Lane.
So you're planning on removing it.
Open this way, but yes.
He will sue us into plutonium.
Are you sure?
His plan to send me to jail failed.
I want to be present when the bomb explodes.
- When is this transmitter active?
-I found it.
He headed east over Europe at 500 Knots.
He's in the air.
Let's see the ClA?
ClA in susupi.
I can not believe anyone in this room.
We have to do it ourselves.
Where to go?
How, Benji?
If there is a way to disarm
bomb, I can not find it.
Shit. Ethan, the signal is gone.
Lane must have found our transmitter.
- Where's his last position?
- About 48 kilometers northeast.
He wants us to go there.
Anything in there? - River valley
Nubra. there is only one medical camp.
Humanitarian aid abroad.
Why would Lane target a medical camp?
Smallpox.
-What?
- Smallpox Apostieus triggers smallpox outbreak in Kashmir
Lane must have a reason
to keep the camp there.
But what?
-Affice
-What?
The Nubra River is at the base of the Siache glacier
The nuclear explosion there will irradiate ...
the largest natural irrigation system in the world.
Water seger from China border
to India and Pakistan.
They will make a third
the world population is starving.
The greater the suffering ...
The greater the peace.
I do not understand why Lane
want a medical camp there.
Not important.
The important thing to find a way
to disarm his bomb.
I think I found it.
Maybe.
It will definitely be in bomb operation
Detoantor far distance requires
the shooter's key.
If we take, sitemp engaman will die
and we can cut both fuses.
So one of us should get it
detonator and unplug it.
Yes.
Others cut
fuse on both bombs. Simple.
Yes, but ...
But what?
In order to succeed, we can not pull
the key or cut the fuse ...
Before the countdown starts.
Wait, let me be clear.
The only way to disarm his bomb ...
is to let the countdown start.
Then unplug it.
OK.
Both bombs are now connected to the detonator.
15 minutes should be enough for you
to reach a safe distance.
My escape days ended.
Here is the end of my journey.
I can signal everywhere.
We're in medical camp, X-ray machine, CAT
Radiological signals are everywhere.
Like a needle in a haystack.
We check one by one. Come on
split up, do not turn off the radio.
Ethan?
Julia?
That ...?
Julia!
Does he know?
Hey.
This is my husband, Erik.
- It's ... - Rob. Dr. Thorne. Rob Thorne.
-I work with Julia
- At Massachusetts General Hospital.
- Before New York
- Seriously.
- It is such a coincidence
- Correct
-Are you coming here?
-I...
I'm in Turtuk, not far from here ...
And I heard this place needs help.
Oh
We want to finish, the whole village
already inoculated. But...
What are you doing in Turktuk?
Rob is on vacation.
No. I am working.
You're far from your house.
Yes, thanks to our guardian angel.
Protector?
We run field hospitals outside Darfur
the answer is here.
Then suddenly we can phone
of donors are unknown.
He wants to finance the whole
Option with one condition.
We process it.
You believe that?
Certain.
Yes, all of a sudden.
Suddenly.
That's great.
Before meeting Julia me
never traveled.
Never left New York.
Never leave the hospital.
All day. Not on vacation.
Ethan, I found something.
I'll be head of body at age
50 heart attacks at age 55.
He assures you to release everything.
Helping the needy.
Since then we traveled ...
And my life is so much fun.
I'm happy too.
Thanks.
We have to go a lot to pack.
Let me. You two are talking.
No, I do not want to disturb.
Serious? You have to be here.
I regret your arrival in vain ...
Let's just say, we will pack ...
and kai between you back to Turtuk
so you can chat in the car.
- Yes?
- You are so kind
All right, until later.
Nice to meet you.
I'm sorry, Julia. Forgive me.
Bring both helicopters
No one else can go.
Be careful, be careful.
The bomb is active. But count
backward has not started yet.
The signal is strong, it means the second bomb
and the detonator is not far away.
About half a mile to get there.
They're still here.
Ltuher, take care of this, you two come with me.
Certain. I can.
Do not worry about Luther.
Walker.
{Active Bomb]
Disastrous.
Ethan, countdown on
start We got 15 minutes.
Walker holds his detonator.
Come on!
- We have to evacuate them
- No time.
All of this valley will be destroyed in 15 minutes.
Late!
No.
I'll get the detonator.
- How?
-I think.
Find lane! find the second bomb!
- What does he want?
- Better not see.
How is Luther?
- Trigger everywhere, my hand is not enough
- Just finish it
- Where is ethan?
- He's chasing the detonator
- Where's the detonator?
Luther.
Julia, you do not have to be here.
God.
- This is what I suspect?
- Luther, tell him to leave.
Where can he go?
What can I do for you?
In gear, pliers with red handles.
- You are crazy?
- Just do your business, Benji
This is my business!
Benji, you hear?
Ethan! Where are you?
- In Helicopter chasing Walker
- Wait.
- Why in the helicopter?
- Can you drive a helicopter?
You say helicopter? Why are you in a helicopter?
Anyway ... you found the second bomb?
Still in search, but a show
find it without a detonator.
I know, I'll get it!
If he's in another helicopter ...
- How did you pick it up
- I'll think about it.
You're looking for the bomb, I take care of the detonator.
I will not let you down.
- Be prepared.
- Listen, Ethan, ethan!
Ethan, sign in!
Benji? Benji? Luther?
Anyone!
I can.
What is this? There is air speed.
Air speed.
Power. This is energy.
Loads. How to dispose of the charge?
Power.
Cable peeler.
-I'm a doctor not an electrician
- Sorry, the handle is green.
- Could
- Cable in my left hand.
- The black one?
- My left hand.
- That's your left hand
- Sorry the other cable.
- The red one?
- Yes that is red in my right hand.
Please hold this for me.
God!
Shit!
Go up there!
Correct...
... bastard.
God damn it.
Too dive.
God!
Up. up.
Surface. surface.
- Rise up
-I tried, tried.
Benji did not meet. I think we are
looking in the wrong place.
Signals are everywhere. suitable for
hide it there.
That's it. I know lane
We look it up here ...
... because he wants to.
I went to deesa.
Wait for me.
I found something.
Cut the cable here.
Rotate the bolt and turn it in the same direction
clockwise slowly.
So...
- ...How are you?
- That's it.
Still the same Ethan.
God!
Shit!
No, no, no.
Benji I saw Lane
What? Where?
- At home on the edge of the village
- All right, wait for me.
Wait for me!
No.
Nuclear bomb.
Shit!
Benji, I found the second bomb.
- Lisa, where are you?
- At home
Hey what are you doing?
You are crazy! I do not know
what's down there.
Rise up!
This madman is going to hit us!
Hurry up!
GuavaBerry
Shit!
Benji, come in, we almost
in the next we need to find a second bomb.
You said the second bomb?
- Benji you hear?
-I'm trying
Lisa, where are you?
You can not stop him.
Understand? He can not do anything.
When the time is up. Ethan hunt
will lose everything ...
and everyone ...
which he loves ...
- Lisa
- Benji
- Benji!
- Where are you Lisa?
You do not want to see this.
no, no, no!
Hold on.
I'm so close. Come on!
Why do not you just die?
Luther ...
Go.
Benji where are you?
Luther, we're open. say what to do.
There is a red wire attached to the motherboard.
Cut that cable and the green one
beside him simultaneously.
Ready?
Are you ready?
Cut.
I told you. Can not stop.
There's nothing you can do.
Benji, listen to turn the bolt
counterclockwise.
Yes.
Lift up the panel and you will
see power and ground cables
- for the fuse
- Could
When the time comes, cut the cable
green, do not cut it first.
Well we understand.
Ethan you heard. We are ready to cut the cable.
Ethan, answer.
Where do we know he got the key?
He'll get it.
- But how do you know?
- He'll make it!
We're running out of time. Hope
he just got it.
- We're ready
- We cut in two seconds.
Why two? Why not one?
- Want ptong that close?
- That's a bit we will not get back to.
- Can make a decision?
- Good!
- Cut on one
- Cut on one second?
- Yes one, be prepared.
Three...
Two...
One. now!
Great, man.