There are more people
with genius IQs in China
than people of any kind
in the United States.
- That can't possibly be true.
- It is.
- What accounts for that?
- A lot of people live in China.
But here's my question.
How do you distinguish yourself
in a population of people
who all got 1600 on their SATs?
- They take SATs in China?
- They don't. I'm not talking about China.
I'm talking about me.
- You got a 1600?
- Yes.
I could sing in an a cappella group,
but I can't sing.
- You got nothing wrong?
- I could row crew, or invent a $25 PC.
Or get into a final club.
From a woman's perspective, not singing
in an a cappella group is good.
- This is serious.
- I do like guys who row crew.
Well, I can't do that.
- I was kidding.
- Yes, I got nothing wrong on the test.
- Have you ever tried?
- I'm trying now.
- To row crew?
- To get into a final club.
To row crew? No.
Are you, like, delusional?
Sometimes you say two things at once.
I'm not sure which one to aim at.
- But you've seen guys who row crew, right?
- No.
They're bigger than me.
They're world-class athletes.
You said you like guys who row crew.
I assumed you'd met one.
I guess I meant I like the idea of it.
You know, the way a girl likes cowboys.
- Okay.
- Should we get something to eat?
Would you like
to talk about something else?
No, just since the beginning
of the conversation about finals club,
I think I may have missed a birthday.
There are really more people in China
with genius IQs than the population...?
The Phoenix is the most diverse.
The Fly Club...
- Roosevelt punched the Porc.
- Which one?
The Porcellian, the Porc. It's the best.
Which Roosevelt?
Theodore.
They send a bus to pick up girls who want
to party with the next Fed chairman?
You can see why
it's so important to get in.
Which is easiest to get into?
Why would you ask me that?
I was just asking.
None of them. That's the point.
My friend Eduardo made $300,000
betting oil futures one summer
and won't come close to getting in.
The ability to make money
doesn't impress anybody.
Must be nice.
He made $300,000 in a summer?
- He likes meteorology.
- You said it was oil futures.
You read weather,
predict the price of heating oil.
You think the final club
that's easiest to get into
is where I'll have the best chance.
I... What?
You asked me which was easiest to get into
because you think
that's where I'll have the best chance.
The one that's easiest to get into
would be
where anybody has the best chance.
You didn't ask which was best,
you asked which was easiest.
I was honestly just asking, okay?
I was just asking to ask.
- Mark, I'm not speaking in code.
- Erica.
You're obsessed with finals clubs.
You have finals clubs OCD.
See someone about it
who will prescribe you medication.
You don't care
if the side effects may include blindness.
Final clubs.
Not "finals clubs."
There's a difference between
being obsessed and motivated.
Yes. There is.
- That was cryptic. You do speak in code.
- I didn't mean to be cryptic.
I need to do something substantial
to get the attention of the clubs.
- Why?
- Because they're exclusive.
And fun, and they lead to a better life.
Roosevelt wasn't elected president
because he was a member
of the Phoenix Club.
He was a member of the Porcellian,
and yes, he did.
Well, why don't you just concentrate
on being the best you you can be?
- Did you really just say that?
- I was kidding.
Just because something's trite
doesn't make it less true.
I'll be straightforward.
You might want to be more supportive.
If I get in, I will be taking you
to the events and the gatherings.
You'll meet people
you wouldn't normally meet.
You would do that for me?
We're dating.
Okay.
I'll be straightforward with you
and tell you that we're not anymore.
- What do you mean?
- We're not dating anymore. I'm sorry.
Is this a joke?
- No, it's not.
- You're breaking up with me?
You're gonna introduce me
to people I wouldn't normally meet?
What is that supposed to mean?
- Settle down.
- What is it supposed to mean?
We're able to sit here because
you used to sleep with the door guy.
"The door guy"? His name is Bobby.
I have not slept with the door guy.
The door guy is a friend of mine,
and he's a perfectly good class of people.
What part of Long Island
are you from, Wimbledon?
- Wait. Wait, wait.
- I'm going back to my dorm.
- Is this real?
- Yes.
- Wait. I apologize.
- I have to go study.
- Erica?
- Yes?
- I'm sorry.
- I appreciate that, but I have to study.
You don't have to study. Let's just talk.
- I can't.
- Why?
It is exhausting.
Dating you is like dating a StairMaster.
All I meant is that
you're not likely to currently.
It wasn't about your appearance.
You go to BU.
I stated a fact.
If it seemed rude, I apologize.
- I have to go study.
- You don't.
- Why are you saying I don't have to study?
- You go to BU.
Want to get some food?
I am sorry you are not sufficiently
impressed with my education.
I'm sorry I don't have a rowboat.
We're even.
- I think we should be friends.
- I don't want friends.
I was being polite.
I have no intention of being friends.
I'm under pressure from my OS class.
If we just order some food, I think...
Okay, you are probably going
to be a very successful computer person.
But you're gonna go through life
thinking girls don't like you
because you're a nerd.
I want you to know from the bottom
of my heart that that won't be true.
It'll be because you're an asshole.
Erica Albright's a bitch.
Is it because her family
changed their name from Albrecht?
Or do you think
it's because all BU girls are bitches?
For the record, she may look like a 34C,
but she's getting help
from Victoria's Secret.
She's a 34B, as in barely anything there.
False advertising.
The truth is, she has a nice face.
I need to do something
to take my mind off her.
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
I'm a little intoxicated,
I'm not gonna lie.
- So what if it's not even 10 p.m. Tuesday?
- Billy.
The Kirkland facebook is open
on my desktop.
Some of these people have
pretty horrendous facebook pics.
Oh, no.
Billy Olson's had the idea
of putting some pictures
next to pictures of farm animals,
and have people vote on who's hotter.
Good call, Mr. Olson.
Yeah, it's on.
I'm not gonna do the farm animals.
I like the idea of comparing two people.
Gives it a very "Turing" feel.
People's ratings of the pictures will be
more implicit than, say, choosing a number
to represent each person's hotness,
like on HotOrNot.com.
First thing we need is a lot of pictures.
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't keep
a public centralized facebook.
I have to get all the images
from the houses that people are in.
Let the hacking begin.
First up is Kirkland.
They keep everything open
and allow indexes
in their Apache configuration.
So a little Wget magic
is all that's necessary
to download the entire Kirkland facebook.
Kids' stuff.
Next is Eliot.
They're also open,
but with no indexes on Apache.
I run an empty search,
it returns all images
in the database in a single page.
I can save the page and Mozilla
will save all the images for me.
Excellent. Moving right along.
Excuse me, everybody.
You are at one of the oldest,
one of the most exclusive clubs,
not just at Harvard, but in the world.
I want to welcome you all
to Phoenix Club's first party
of the fall semester.
Lowell has some security.
They require a user name/password combo.
They don't have access
to the main FAS user database.
They can't detect intrusion.
Adams has no security,
but limits the number of results
to 20 a page.
I break out the same script
I used on Lowell, and we're set.
Quincy has no online facebook.
What a sham.
Nothing I can do about that.
Dunster is intense.
There's no public directory.
There's no directory at all.
You do searches.
If a search has more than
20 matches, nothing is returned.
Once you do get results,
they don't link directly to the images.
They link to a PHP that redirects.
Weird. This may be difficult.
I'll come back later.
- Hey, Shark Week's on.
- What?
- Great white, beautiful fish.
- Nice.
Leverett is better.
They make you search,
but you can do an empty search
and get links to every picture.
It's obnoxious that
they only let you view one at a time.
No way I'm going to 500 pages
to download pics one at a time.
It's necessary to break out Emacs
and modify the Perl script.
Here you go.
Done.
Hey, what's going on?
Perfect timing. Eduardo's here,
and he's going to have the key ingredient.
Hey, Mark.
- Wardo.
- You and Erica split up.
- How did you know that?
- It's on your blog.
- Yeah.
- Are you all right?
I need you.
I'm here for you.
I need your algorithm
to rank chess players.
- Are you okay?
- We're ranking girls.
- You mean other students.
- Yeah.
You think this is such a good idea?
- I need the algorithm.
- Mark.
I need the algorithm.
Give each girl a base rating of 1400.
At any given time,
Girl A has a rating R-a,
and Girl B has a rating R-b.
When two girls are matched,
there's an expectation of which will win
based on current rating?
Yeah. And those expectations
are expressed this way.
Let's write it.
One on the left.
- The right.
- Yeah, still the right.
- It works.
- Who should we send it to first?
- Dwyer.
- Neal.
- Who are you gonna send it to?
- Just a couple of people.
The question is,
who are they gonna send it to?
Hey, guys, check this out.
Someone go to the left. Dude, do left.
Look at these girls.
Right or left?
- Left is hot.
- Left? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right or left?
That's my roommate.
- Oh, my God.
- The girl on the left.
This is pathetic.
- Right.
- Left.
- Left?
Oh, shit.
Albright.
He blogged about you.
You don't wanna read it.
Left.
Oh, Latina.
Erica.
Is this yours?
I stole it from a tranny.
Get the hell out of here.
- Left.
- One on the right.
Left.
Man, that's an awful lot of traffic.
You think maybe we shouldn't shut it down
before we get into trouble?
Hello?
Wait, wait, wait. What?
At 4 in the morning?
There's an unusual amount
of traffic to the switch at Kirkland.
You're saying,
it's unusual for 4 in the morning?
No, this would be unusual
for halftime at the Super Bowl.
All right.
I gotta go in.
What's going on?
Harvard's network is about to crash.
You don't think...
I do.
Go see if it's everybody's.
I can't connect.
The network's down.
Unless it's a coincidence,
I think this is us.
It's not a coincidence.
Holy shit.
You were called in front of the Ad Board.
That's not what happened.
You weren't called
to the Administrative Board?
No, back. I mean,
back at the bar with Erica Albright.
- She said all that?
- Mark...
- That I said that to her?
- I read the transcript of her deposition.
Why would you need to depose her?
That's really for us to decide.
You think if I know she can make me look
like a jerk, I'm more likely to settle.
Can we stretch our legs for a minute?
It's been almost three hours.
Frankly, you did spend
an awful lot of time
embarrassing Mr. Zuckerberg
with the girl's testimony from the bar.
- I'm not embarrassed. She made a lot up.
- She was under oath.
I guess that's the first time
somebody's lied under oath.
The site got 2200 hits within two hours?
Thousand.
What?
Twenty-two thousand.
These guys are just freaking fast.
Is there any way
to make this a fair fight?
Jump out and swim.
Think we'd have to jump out and drown.
Well, you could row forward
and I could row backward.
We're genetically identical.
Science says we'd stay in one place.
Just row the damn boat.
- You guys hear about this?
- What?
Two nights ago, a sophomore choked
the network from a laptop at Kirkland.
- Really?
- At 4 a.m.
How?
Set up a website where you vote
on the hotness of female undergrads.
What were we doing that none of us heard?
A three-hour low-rate
technical row before breakfast.
Full course load. Studying.
Another three hours in the tank
and then studying.
Not sure how we missed it.
- How much activity was on this thing?
- Twenty-two thousand page requests.
Twenty-two thousand?
Cam, this guy hacked
the facebook of seven houses.
He set up the whole website
in one night, while he was drunk.
Twenty-two thousand?
- How do you know he was drunk?
- He was blogging simultaneously.
Know what I think?
Way ahead of you.
This is our guy.
Cameron Winklevoss.
W-I-N-K-L-E-V-O-S-S.
"Cameron" spelled the usual way.
Tyler Winklevoss.
Tyler spelled the usual way.
My last name is the same as my brother's.
Mr. Zuckerberg,
this is an Administrative Board hearing.
You're being accused
of intentionally breaching security,
violating copyrights,
violating individual privacy
by creating the website www.Facemash.com.
You're also charged with
being in violation of university policy,
on distribution of digitized images.
Before we begin our questioning,
you're allowed to make a statement.
Would you like to do so?
I...
You know, I've already apologized
in The Crimson to the ABHW,
to Fuerza Latina,
and to any women at Harvard
who may have been insulted,
as I take it that they were.
As for any charges stemming
from the breach of security,
I believe I deserve
some recognition from this board.
- I'm sorry?
- Yes.
I don't understand.
Which part?
You deserve recognition?
I've pointed out
some pretty gaping holes in your system.
- Excuse me, may I?
- Yes.
Mr. Zuckerberg, I'm in charge of security
for all computers on the Harvard network,
and I can assure you
of its sophistication.
That level of sophistication
led us to you in less than four hours.
- Four hours?
- Yes, sir.
That'd be impressive,
but if you knew what to look for,
you'd have seen it
written on my dorm window.
So?
Six months academic probation.
Wow, well,
they had to make an example out of you.
They had my blog.
I shouldn't have written that thing
about farm animals. That was stupid.
But I was kidding.
Doesn't anybody have a sense of humor?
- I tried to stop you.
- I know.
How do you do this thing where
you manage to get all girls to hate us?
- And why do I let you?
- I know.
You can't do that.
Wardo, I said, I know.
Okay, let's look at a sample problem.
Suppose we're given a computer
with a 16-bit virtual address
and a page size of 256 bytes.
The system uses one-level page tables
that start at address hex 400.
Maybe you want DMA on your 16-bit system.
Who knows?
The first few pages are reserved
for hardware flags, etc.
Assume page-table entries have
eight status bits.
The eight status bits would then be...
Anybody?
And I see we have our first surrender.
Don't worry, Mr. Zuckerberg.
Brighter men than you
have tried and failed this class.
One valid bit, one modified bit,
one reference bit,
and five permission bits.
That is correct.
Does everybody see how he got there?
Mark?
You Mark Zuckerberg?
Yeah.
- Cameron Winklevoss.
- Hi.
Tyler Winklevoss.
Are you guys related?
That's good.
- Funny.
- We never heard that before.
What can I do for you?
- Did I insult your girlfriends?
- No, you didn't. Actually, I don't know.
- Yeah, we never asked.
- We should do that.
No.
We have an idea
we want to talk to you about.
You got a minute?
You look like
you spend some time at the gym.
- We have to.
- Why?
We row crew.
Yeah, I've got a minute.
Great.
- You ever been inside the Porcellian?
- No.
We can't take you past the bike room,
because you're not a member.
I've heard.
You want a sandwich or something?
Okay.
- Mark, right?
- Yeah.
- This is Divya Narendra, our partner.
- Hi.
We were really impressed with Facemash.
When we checked you out,
you also built CourseMatch.
I don't know CourseMatch.
You go online and see
what courses your friends are taking.
It's really smart, man.
- Mark.
- Yeah.
We were talking about CourseMatch.
It was kind of a no-brainer.
You invented something in high school too?
An app for an MP3 player
that recognizes your taste in music.
Anybody try to buy it?
Microsoft.
Wow, how much?
Didn't sell it. Uploaded it for free.
- For free?
- Yeah.
Why?
We have something
that we've been working on for a while.
We think it's great.
It's called the Harvard Connection.
You create your own page.
Interests, bio, friends, pics.
People can go online,
see your bio, request to be your...
How's it different
from MySpace or Friendster?
Harvard.ed...
The most prestigious
e-mail address in the country.
Whole site's
based on the idea that girls...
Not to put anything indelicately...
Girls wanna go
with guys who go to Harvard.
Divya and my brother
put things indelicately.
Difference between
what we're talking about
and MySpace, Friendster,
or other social networking sites...
Is exclusivity.
- Right?
- Right.
- Yeah.
- We'd love for you to work with us.
We need a gifted, creative programmer.
And you've been taking it in the shins.
Women's groups are ready
to declare a fatwa.
But this could help
rehabilitate your image.
Wow, you would do that for me?
We'd like to work with you.
Our first programmer graduated
and went to work for Google.
Our second programmer
just got overwhelmed with schoolwork.
We need you to build the site,
write the code. We'll provide the...
I'm in.
What?
Awesome.
That's what you said?
It was three or four years ago.
I don't know what I said.
- When did you come to Eduardo?
- I don't understand that question.
Do you remember answering
in the affirmative?
The affirmative?
When did you come to Eduardo
with the idea for Facebook?
It was called The Facebook then.
This doesn't need to be difficult.
I'm currently in the middle
of two different lawsuits.
Did you answer affirmatively
when Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss
and Divya Narendra
asked you to build Harvard Connection?
Did you say yes?
I said I'd help.
When did you approach Mr. Saverin
with the idea for The Facebook?
I wouldn't say I approached him.
- Sy.
- You can answer the question.
At a party at Alpha Epsilon Pi.
What's that?
The Jewish fraternity.
It was Caribbean Night.
It's not that guys like me
are generally attracted to Asian girls.
It's that Asian girls are
generally attracted to guys like me.
I'm developing an algorithm
to define the connection
between Jewish guys and Asian girls.
I don't think it's that complicated.
They're hot, they're smart.
They're not Jewish, and they can't dance.
Hey, Mark's here.
Mark.
Be right back.
I came up with something.
I gotta tell you something
that you won't believe.
What?
I got punched by the Phoenix.
- Are you kidding?
- No.
I mean, it's just the first
of a four-step process,
but they slid the invitation
under my door tonight.
I go to my first punch party tomorrow.
So...
You got punched by the Phoenix.
Yeah, you know,
it was probably just a diversity thing.
It was just a diversity thing.
Just ride that horse until...
What did you
wanna talk to me about? Mark?
- Yeah.
- You came up with something?
I think I've come up with something.
Come outside and let's talk.
It's 20 degrees outside.
I can't stare
at that loop of Niagara Falls,
which has absolutely
nothing to do with the Caribbean.
- People came to Facemash in a stampede.
- Yeah.
Not because
they saw pictures of hot girls.
Anywhere on the Internet,
you can see hot girls.
Yeah.
It was because they saw pictures
of girls that they knew.
People want to go online
and check out friends.
Why not build a website that offers that?
Friends, pictures, profiles.
Whatever you can visit. Browse around.
Maybe someone you met at a party.
But I'm not talking about a dating site.
I'm talking about taking
the entire social experience of college
and putting it online.
I can't feel my legs.
I know.
I'm totally psyched about this too.
- But, Wardo?
- Yeah?
"It would be exclusive."
You have to know the people
on the site to get past your own page.
Like getting punched.
Now, that's good.
It's like a final club,
except we're the president.
I told him, I thought it sounded great.
It was a great idea.
There was nothing to hack.
People would provide
their own pictures, their own information.
And people had the ability to invite,
or not invite, their friends to join.
See, in a world
where social structure was everything,
that was the thing.
It was a big project,
and he would have to write
tens of thousands of lines of code.
I wondered why he was coming to me,
not his roommates,
Dustin Moskovitz and Chris Hughes.
They were programmers.
We're gonna need a little start-up cash
to rent the servers and get it online.
So that was why.
- Did he offer terms?
- Yes.
We'll split it, 70/30.
Seventy for me, 30 for you
for putting up the $1000
and handling everything
on the business end.
- You're CFO.
- And you said?
I said, "Let's do it."
Okay. Did he add anything else?
Yes.
It probably was a diversity thing.
But so what?
- Why do you think he said that?
- Gretchen, whose discovery is this?
- Sy, let me continue my questioning.
- What are you suggesting?
That I was jealous
Eduardo got punched by the Phoenix,
and began a plan to screw him
out of a company I hadn't invented yet.
- Were you?
- Gretchen.
- Jealous of him?
- Stop typing.
- Off the record.
- You did your homework.
You know money
isn't a big part of my life.
But at the moment,
I could buy Mount Auburn Street,
take the Phoenix Club,
and turn it into my ping-pong room.
I'll let you know how the party is.
We recognize that you're a plaintiff
in one suit involving Facebook,
and a witness in another.
Yes, sir.
At any time in the weeks
prior to Mark's telling you his idea,
did he mention Tyler Winklevoss,
Cameron Winklevoss,
Divya Narendra or Harvard Connection?
Yes, he said,
they'd asked him to work on their site,
but that he looked at what they had,
and decided it wasn't worth his time.
He said, even his most pathetic friends
knew more about
getting people interested in a website
than these guys.
"These guys," meaning my clients.
Yes. He resented...
Mark resented that your clients thought
that he needed
to rehabilitate his image after Facemash.
Mark didn't want to rehabilitate anything.
With Facemash,
he'd hacked into the Harvard computers,
thumbed his nose at the Ad Board,
gotten a lot of notoriety.
Facemash did exactly
what he wanted it to do.
Were you aware that
while Mr. Zuckerberg built The Facebook,
he was communicating with the plaintiffs?
Not at the time, I wasn't, but...
It really didn't have much to do
with the Winklevosses' dating site.
- How do you know? You weren't even there.
- Ty.
Were you aware
that while Mr. Zuckerberg
was building The Facebook,
he was leading the plaintiffs to believe
he was building Harvard Connection?
A conclusion not found in evidence.
We are about to find it in evidence.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler Winklevoss,
November 30th, 2003.
"I read over all the stuff you sent me
re: Harvard Connection.
It seems like
it shouldn't take too long to implement.
So we can talk about it after
I get all the basic functionality up,
tomorrow night."
From Mark Zuckerberg
to Cameron Winklevoss, December 1st, 2003.
"Sorry I was unreachable tonight.
I just got three of your missed calls.
I was working
on a problem set for my systems class."
From Mark Zuckerberg
to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss,
December 10, 2003.
"This week has been pretty busy
thus far with classes and work,
so I think it's probably best
to postpone the meeting."
"I'm also really busy tomorrow."
Anybody else feel like
there's something up with this guy?
Tell him okay, but we do have to
meet up before we all go off for break.
I know, I know.
Yeah, watch out.
Hey, Mark.
I need a dedicated Linux box
running Apache with a MySQL back end.
Gonna cost a little more money.
- How much more?
- About 200 more.
- Do we need it?
- Gotta handle the traffic.
- Do it.
- I already did.
Hey, guess what?
I made the second cut.
That's good. You should be proud of that.
Don't worry if you don't make it further.
I'll get out of here.
From Mark Zuckerberg
to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss
and Divya Narendra,
December 15th, 2003.
"I have a CS problem set
that I'm getting started with.
It should be about 15 hours of coding,
so I'll be busy tomorrow night."
"I won't really be free to meet
until next Wednesday afternoon."
"I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
I've basically been in the lab
this whole time, and also I"
"won't be able to do Saturday,
as I have to meet up with my parents."
As the plaque reads, this is John Harvard,
founder of Harvard University in 1638.
It's also called the Statue of Three Lies.
What are the three lies?
Mr. Dowd.
The three lies. First...
Shit.
Take your pants off.
I know.
Mr. Saverin.
One, Harvard was founded
in 1636, not 1638.
Two, Harvard was
not founded by John Harvard.
Three, that is not John Harvard.
Who is it?
It's a friend of the sculptor,
Daniel Chester.
Keep your jacket on.
Thirty-nine days after Mr. Zuckerberg's
initial meeting with my clients,
and he still hadn't completed work
on Harvard Connection.
But on January 11th, 2004,
Mr. Zuckerberg registered
the domain name The Facebook
via Network Solutions.
To the best of your knowledge, had he even
begun work on Harvard Connection?
Not to my knowledge. No.
What in the world is this?
"Hey, Cameron,
I'm still a little skeptical that
we have enough functionality in the site
to really draw the attention
and gain the critical mass necessary
to get a site like this to run.
We'll speak soon"?
This is the first time
he mentioned any problem?
Yes, it was.
You sent 36 e-mails to Mr. Zuckerberg
and received 16 e-mails in return.
This was the first time
he indicated he was not happy.
That's correct.
He had 42 days
to study our system and get out ahead.
Do you see any of your code on Facebook?
- Sy, could you?
- Did I use your code?
You stole our whole goddamn idea.
Fellas.
- Match.com for Harvard guys?
- Can I continue my deposition?
You don't need a forensics team
to get to the bottom of this.
If you guys were
the inventors of Facebook,
you'd have invented Facebook.
I can't wait to stand over your shoulder
as you write us a check.
No shit.
Let's continue.
February 4, 2004.
Mark.
There is a girl in your art history class.
Her name is Stephanie Attis.
Do you happen to know
if she has a boyfriend?
Have you ever seen her with anyone?
And if not, do you happen to know
if she's looking to go out with anyone?
Dustin.
People don't walk around
with a sign on them that says...
Mark?
We were supposed to meet at 9.
Have you slept yet?
I have to add something.
What?
Shit, that looks good.
That looks really good.
It's clean and simple.
No Disneyland, no "live nude girls."
But watch.
What'd you write?
"Relationship status. Interested in."
This is what drives life at college.
"Are you having sex or aren't you?"
It's why people take certain classes,
sit where they sit, and do what they do.
And at its center, you know,
that's what
The Facebook is gonna be about.
People will log on because
there's a chance they're actually...
Gonna get laid.
Meet a girl. Yes.
- That is really good.
- And that was it.
- What do you mean?
- It's ready.
- It's ready? Right now?
- Yeah, that was it.
And here's the masthead.
- You made a masthead.
- Yeah.
- "Eduardo Saverin, co-founder and CFO."
You have no idea what
that will mean to my father.
Sure I do.
So when's it going live?
Right now. Get your laptop out.
What? Why do we need my laptop?
You got e-mails
for everybody at the Phoenix.
Yeah, I'm not sure if it's gonna be cool
with them that I spam their e-mails.
- This is not spam.
- No, I know it's not spam.
If we send it to our friends,
it'll just bounce around Dworkin.
I haven't gotten in yet.
These guys know people.
And I need their e-mails.
- Sure.
- Good.
Give me the mailing list.
Jabberwock12.listserv@harvard.edu.
These guys.
They're literary geniuses because an
obvious Lewis Carroll reference is in...
- They're not so bad.
- I'm just saying.
Yeah, you're right.
The site's live.
You know,
let's go get a drink and celebrate.
I'm buying.
Mark.
Mark, are you praying?
Whatever happened
to Cole Porter and Irving Berlin?
It's a Valentine's Day theme.
They're playing love songs.
Good point. Cole Porter and Irving Berlin
never wrote any love songs.
Honey, you should put your laptop away.
Seven different people
spammed me the same link.
- KC.
- What is it?
I don't know.
But I hope
it's Cats That Look Like Hitler.
I can never get enough of that.
No, it's not.
Div.
What?
This isn't mine.
Okay, what is wrong?
It's fine. It's fine. It's fine.
Hey.
Not now. We need 20 minutes.
Okay.
Just wanted to let you know
that Zuckerberg stole our website.
Mark Zuckerberg?
He stole our website.
It's been live for more than 36 hours.
Mr. Hotchkiss?
Ty, lawyer's on the phone with Dad.
I'm here with Tyler
and our business partner Divya.
"Welcome to The Facebook,
an online directory
that connects people
through different social networks.
You must have
a harvard.edu address to register."
I called earlier.
I'm looking for Mark Zuckerberg.
Yes, he's quoted a couple times.
I can read it to you.
"'Everyone's talking about a universal
facebook within Harvard, ' he says."
"He" meaning Mark.
"'It's silly that it'd take the university
a couple years to get around to it.
I can do a classier job.
I did it in a week.'"
Tell him Divya Narendra called.
- I know, that's how he talks.
- Appreciate it.
"As of yesterday evening, Zuckerberg said,
over 650 students had registered
to use TheFacebook.com.
He said he anticipated that 900 students
would've joined the site by this morning."
Divya just read that 650 students
signed up for it on the first day.
God, if I was a drug dealer,
I couldn't give free drugs
to 650 people in one day.
And this guy doesn't have three friends
to rub together to make a fourth.
Yes, Mr. Hotchkiss, we'll put
all this together and e-mail it to you.
Well, you won't be able
to go on the website yourself.
Because you don't have a Harvard...
It would just be easier
for us to e-mail it to you.
I'm sure you're right. He's a good guy.
He's very bright.
I'm sure he didn't mean to do
what he did.
Thank you very much.
And Dad... All right, love you too.
- This is a good guy?
- We don't know that he's not a good guy.
He stole our idea,
lied to our faces for a month and a half.
- He never lied to our faces.
- He never saw our faces.
Fine, he lied to our e-mail accounts,
and he gave himself a 42-day head start,
because he knows
what apparently you don't:
Getting there first is everything.
I'm a competitive racer.
You don't need to school me
in the importance of getting there first.
That was your father's lawyer?
His in-house counsel.
He'll look at all this.
If appropriate,
he'll send a cease-and-desist letter.
- What will that do?
- Wanna hire an IP lawyer and sue him?
No, I wanna hire the Sopranos
to beat the shit out of him with a hammer.
- We don't have to.
- Right.
We could do that ourselves.
I'm 6'5", 220, and there's two of me.
- I'm with this guy.
- Whatever.
Calm down
until we know what we're talking about.
How much more information
are you waiting for?
We met with Mark three times.
We exchanged 52 e-mails.
We can prove that he looked at the code.
- What is that on the bottom of the page?
- "A Mark Zuckerberg production."
- On the home page?
- On every page.
I need a second
to let the classiness waft over me.
- We don't know...
- Cam, they wrote:
"Zuckerberg said,
he hoped the privacy options
would help restore his reputation
following student outrage
over Facemash.com."
That's exactly what we said to him.
He's giving us the finger in The Crimson.
While we wait for
Dad's lawyer to look this over,
we can get something in the paper,
so people know...
- What?
- That this is in dispute.
We're not starting a knife fight
in The Crimson.
- And we're not suing anybody.
- Why not?
I don't understand. Why not?
He's gonna say it's stupid.
What, who, me?
Say it. Why not?
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard.
This is Harvard,
where you don't plant stories,
and you don't sue people.
You thought he'd be the only one
who thought that's stupid?
During the time
when you say you had this idea,
did you know Tyler and Cameron
came from a family of means?
- "A family of means"?
- Did you know their father was wealthy?
I'm not sure why you're asking.
It's not important
you be sure why I'm asking.
- It's not important to you.
- Sy.
Did you know that they came from money?
I had no idea
if they came from money or not.
In one of your e-mails to Mr. Narendra,
you referenced
Howard Winklevoss' consulting firm.
If you say so.
Howard Winklevoss founded a firm
with assets in the hundreds of millions.
You also knew
Tyler and Cameron were members
of a Harvard final club
called the Porcellian.
They pointed that out.
- Excuse us for inviting you in.
- To the bike room.
Please. So it's safe to say,
you were aware that my clients had money.
Yes.
Let me tell you why I'm asking.
I'm wondering why, if you needed
$1000 for an Internet venture,
you didn't ask my clients for it.
They had demonstrated
an interest to you in that kind of thing.
I went to my friend for money because
that's who I wanted to be partners with.
Eduardo was the president
of the Harvard Investors Association.
He was also my best friend.
Your best friend is suing you
for $600 million.
I didn't know that. Tell me more.
Eduardo, what happened
after the initial launch?
Would you mind
addressing him as Mr. Saverin?
- They're best friends.
- Not anymore.
We already went through this on...
Never mind.
Mr. Saverin,
what happened after the initial launch?
It exploded.
Everybody on campus was using it.
"Facebook me" was a common expression
after two weeks.
And Mark?
And Mark was the biggest thing
on a campus
that included 19 Nobel laureates,
15 Pulitzer Prize winners,
two future Olympians, and a movie star.
Who was the movie star?
Does it matter?
No.
...at Out of Town News and picked up
that copy of Popular Electronics magazine
with the MITS Altair kit on the cover.
It was a beautiful day.
I was in my Radcliffe dorm room.
He brought that magazine up,
showed it to me, and said,
"Look, it's gonna happen without us.
We've gotta start now."
And I said,
"Okay. Let's get BASIC out there."
Now, most of you think you know
the rest of the story, but you may not.
The beginnings
of this industry were very humble.
That kit computer on the cover of
that magazine had an 8080 processor in it.
Unless you paid extra for
a 1K memory board, you got 256 bytes.
So the challenge when I wrote BASIC
wasn't just to run at 4 k-bytes,
but I also had to leave room for the users
to run their programs in 4 k-bytes.
Your friend.
- Is that Mark Zuckerberg?
- Yeah.
- He made The Facebook.
I mean, it's both of ours. We're...
Yeah, we... Yes.
Cool.
- I'm Christy Ling. This is Alice.
- Hi.
Well, very nice to meet you.
Facebook me when you get home.
Maybe we can all go out and grab a drink.
Certainly.
Absolutely do that.
She said, "Facebook me,
and we can all go for a drink later,"
which is stunningly great for two reasons.
One, she said, "Facebook me."
- The other...
- They wanna have drinks later.
Yes, have you ever heard
so many good things
packed into one regular-sized sentence?
Excuse me, Mark?
Yeah?
I'm Stuart Singer. I'm in your OS lab.
Sure.
- Awesome job with The Facebook.
- Awesome job.
Thanks.
- I'm Bob.
- How you doing?
I could swear he was looking at you
when he said the next Bill Gates
could be right in this room.
I doubt it.
I showed up late.
I don't even know who the speaker was.
It was Bill Gates.
Shit, that makes sense.
All right. Thanks, guys.
- Are you a moron?
- Are you stupid?
You can't tell Bill Gates
is in front of you?
- I wasn't wearing my contacts.
- Can I get a Glock and kill you?
Time to monetize the thing.
What were their names?
- Hear what I just said?
- When?
I said, it's time to monetize the site.
What does that mean?
Means it's time for the website
to start generating revenue.
I know what the word means.
How do you wanna do it?
- Advertising.
- No.
Well, we got 4000 members.
Because The Facebook is cool.
If we install pop-ups
for Mountain Dew, it won't be cool.
I wasn't thinking Mountain Dew,
but at some point,
talking as the business end
of the company, the site...
We don't even know what it is yet.
We don't know what it is.
We don't know
what it can be, what it will be.
We know that it is cool.
- That's a priceless asset I won't give up.
- So when will it be finished?
It won't be finished. That's the point.
The way fashion's never finished.
- What?
- Fashion. Fashion is never finished.
You're talking about fashion? You?
I'm talking about the idea of it.
It's never finished.
Okay, but they manage
to make money selling pants.
Mark, what is this?
- What?
- This.
A cease-and-desist letter.
What were their names?
- Who?
- The girls.
When did you get this?
Ten days ago. After we launched the site.
- Jesus.
- The girls. What were their names?
The Winklevoss twins are saying
that you stole their idea.
I find that
a little more than mildly annoying.
Well, they find it
to be intellectual property theft.
- Look.
- Why didn't you show me?
It was addressed to me.
They say we stole The Facebook
from Divya and the Winklevosses.
- I know what it says.
- Did we?
Did we what?
Don't screw around with me now.
Look at me.
It says we could face legal action.
No, it says I could face legal action.
This is from a lawyer.
They feel they have grounds.
The lawyer is
their father's house counsel.
- Do they have grounds?
- Our thing is cool and popular.
Harvard Connection is lame.
I didn't use any of their code, I promise.
I didn't use anything.
A guy who builds a nice chair
doesn't owe money
to everyone who ever has built a chair.
They had an idea, I had a better one.
- Why didn't you show me this?
- Didn't think it was a big deal.
Okay.
So if there's something wrong,
if there's ever anything wrong,
you can tell me.
I'm the guy that wants to help.
This is our thing.
Now, is there anything
that you need to tell me?
No.
What are we doing about this?
I went to a 3L at Student Legal Services.
He told me to write them back.
And what did you say?
"When we met in January,
I expressed my doubts about the site.
Where it stood with graphics,
how much programming was left
that I had not anticipated."
"The lack of hardware
we had to deal with site use,
the lack of promotion that would go on
to successfully launch the website."
This was the first time
you raised any of those concerns, right?
I'd raised concerns before.
- Bullshit.
- Not to us.
Gentlemen, I'm talking about
at the meeting in January
to which this letter is referring.
Yeah.
Let me rephrase this.
You sent my client 16 e-mails.
In the first 15,
you didn't raise any concerns.
Is that a question?
In the 16th e-mail, you raised concerns
about the site's functionality.
- Were you leading them on for six weeks?
- No.
Then why didn't you raise
any of these concerns before?
- It's raining.
- I'm sorry?
It just started raining.
Mr. Zuckerberg,
do I have your full attention?
No.
Do you think I deserve it?
What?
Do you think
I deserve your full attention?
I had to swear an oath
before we began this deposition.
I don't wanna perjure myself,
so I have a legal obligation to say no.
Okay, no.
You don't think I deserve your attention?
If your clients wanna sit on my shoulders
and call themselves tall,
they have a right to try,
but there's no requirement
that I enjoy listening to people lie.
You have part of my attention.
The minimum amount.
The rest of my attention is
back at the offices of Facebook,
where my colleagues and I
are doing things
that no one in this room,
including and especially your clients,
are intellectually
or creatively capable of doing.
Did I adequately answer
your condescending question?
Well, I have 12:45.
Why don't we say that's lunch?
Back at 2:30.
So, what were their names?
Their names were Christy and Alice.
And they wanna have drinks tonight.
You're not supposed to be in here.
This is a men's room.
Oh, my God.
I don't care.
Hey, man, sorry.
Couple girls are freshening up in there.
Sweet.
We have groupies.
I'll be right back.
Mark, where you going? Mark.
Erica?
Hi.
I saw you from over there.
I didn't know you came to this club.
- First time.
- Mine too.
Could I talk to you alone?
I think I'm good here.
I just... I'd love to talk to you alone,
if we could just go some place.
Right here is fine.
You hear about
this new website I launched?
No.
- The Facebook?
- You called me a bitch on the Internet.
That's why I wanted to talk to you.
- On the Internet.
- That's why I came over.
Comparing women to farm animals.
I didn't end up doing that.
Didn't stop you from writing it.
As if every thought that tumbles
through your head was so clever
it would be a crime
for it not to be shared.
The Internet's not written in pencil,
it's written in ink,
and you published that
Erica Albright was a bitch,
right before you made some ignorant crack
about my family's name, my bra size,
and then rated women
based on their hotness.
- Is there a problem?
- No, there's no problem.
You write your snide bullshit
from a dark room,
because that's what the angry do nowadays.
I was nice to you.
Don't torture me for it.
If we could go somewhere for a minute...
- I don't wanna be rude to my friends.
- Okay.
Okay.
Good luck with your video game.
Hey, that was great.
That was the right thing to do.
You apologized, right?
We have to expand.
Sure. Mark?
Is he mad about something?
Okay, we are expanding
to Yale and Columbia.
Dustin, you share the coding work with me.
Chris, you're in charge
of publicity and outreach.
Start by getting a story
in the BU student newspaper, The Bridge.
They hate doing stories about Harvard.
Somebody will be a computer science major.
Say Mark Zuckerberg
will do 10 hours of free programming.
- Why do you want a story in the BU paper?
- Because I do.
Here's the arrangement.
Eduardo is CFO, and owns 30 percent.
Dustin is vice president
and head of programming.
His 5 percent of the company
will come from my end.
Chris is director of publicity.
His compensation will depend on
how much work he ends up doing. Questions?
- Who are the girls?
- Sorry. They're Christy and Alice.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Is there anything we can do?
- No, that's it.
- Yale and Columbia, let's go.
- And Stanford.
- What?
- Stanford.
It's time for them
to see this in Palo Alto.
You don't want any lunch?
No.
You're welcome to some salad.
No, thank you.
This must be hard.
Who are you?
Marylin Delpy.
I introduced myself when we first...
I mean, what do you do?
I'm a second-year associate at the firm.
My boss wanted me
to sit in on the deposition phase.
What are you doing?
Checking in
to see how it's going in Bosnia.
Bosnia. They don't have roads,
but they have Facebook.
You must really hate the Winklevosses.
I don't hate anybody.
The Winklevi aren't suing me
for intellectual property theft.
They are suing me
because for the first time in their lives,
things didn't work out
how they were supposed to for them.
He's expanding.
- What?
- To Yale, Columbia, and Stanford.
It's in The Crimson tomorrow.
- Really?
- Yep.
Looks like that cease-and-desist letter
really scared the shit out of him.
I want to file for injunctive relief
and take the site down.
Every minute the site is up,
Harvard Connection becomes less valuable.
I want an injunction. I want damages.
I want punitive relief.
- And I want him dead.
- I want those things too.
Why aren't we doing anything?
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard?
- You're not thinking how it'll look.
- How will it look?
Like my brother and I
are in skeleton costumes,
chasing Karate Kid
around a high school gym.
Cam, he's violated
Massachusetts state law.
When he goes to Connecticut, New York,
and California, he'll violate federal law.
By the way,
he's in violation of Harvard law.
There's no such thing as Harvard law.
Wait. Yeah.
There is.
Harvard Student Handbook.
Every freshman is issued one.
- In this book it says...
- You can't steal from another student.
It's what we needed. We'll go to Summers.
You can't get a meeting
with Larry Summers.
My brother and I
pay tuition at this school.
We carry a 3.9 GPA at this school.
We've won trophies for this school.
And we'll be rowing in the Olympics
for this school.
I want a meeting
with the goddamn president of this school.
Why Stanford?
Why do you think?
I'm sorry.
I'm late for biochem.
Okay.
You don't know my name, do you?
Is it Stanford?
I should just kick your ass.
How do you go to a party
and meet someone...?
Amelia Ritter, but you prefer Amy.
You're from Orinda.
Your father's in commercial real estate
and your mother's 10 years sober.
What's my major?
Trombone.
Really?
I remember something about a trombone.
French.
Your major's French.
- And yours?
- Mine?
- I don't have one.
- You haven't declared?
I don't go to school.
- You're kidding.
- No.
Well, where did you go to school?
William Taft Elementary,
for a little while.
Seriously?
You're not like 15 years old, are you?
No.
- Wait, you're not like 15, are you?
- No.
So, what do you do?
I'm an entrepreneur.
You're unemployed.
I wouldn't say that.
What would you say?
That I'm an entrepreneur.
What was your latest preneur?
Well, I founded an Internet company
that let folks download
and share music for free.
Kind of like Napster?
Exactly like Napster.
What do you mean?
I founded Napster.
Sean Parker founded Napster.
Nice to meet you.
You're Sean Parker?
You see, the shoe's on the other...
- Foot?
- Table, which has turned.
I just slept with Sean Parker?
You just slept on Sean Parker.
You're a zillionaire.
Not technically.
What are you?
Broke. Not a lot of money in free music.
Even less when you're being sued by
everyone who's ever been to the Grammys.
This is blowing my mind.
I appreciate that.
I gotta hop in the shower
and get ready for class.
Biochem, even though
you're a French major whose name is Amy.
You passed.
I'm a hard worker.
There's juice
or anything else you can find.
Help yourself.
Mind if I check my e-mail?
Yeah, go ahead.
Amy.
Jesus.
- Amy, can you come out here?
- Yeah?
Just a second.
There's a snake in here, Amy.
What?
- Where?
- There's no snake.
I need to ask something.
Are you kidding me?
I could've been killed.
How?
By running too fast,
and getting twisted in the curtain.
What do you need to ask me?
I went to check my e-mail,
and there's a website open.
Yeah, after you passed out last night,
I went on The Facebook for a little bit.
- What's that?
- The Facebook?
Stanford's had it for like two weeks now.
It's really awesome,
except it's freakishly addictive.
Seriously, I'm on the thing
like five times a day.
Mind if I send myself an e-mail?
Yeah, is everything okay?
Everything's great.
I just need to find you, Mark Zuckerberg.
I've never been in this building before.
This building's 100 years older
than the country it's in,
so do be careful.
We're sitting in chairs.
Yes.
Very good. You can go in now.
That's their own stupidity.
I should've been there.
Darkness is the absence of light,
and the stupidity
in that instance was the absence of me.
Catherine,
I've got students in my office now.
Students. Undergrads.
I don't know.
From the looks of it, they want
to sell me a Brooks Brothers franchise.
All right, bye-bye.
- Good morning.
- Sir, I'm Cameron Winklevoss.
This is my brother, Tyler.
And you're here because...
Either of you can answer.
- I thought you were reading the letter.
- I've read it.
We came up with an idea for
a website called Harvard Connection.
We've since changed the name to ConnectU.
Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea...
I understand.
And I'm asking
what you want me to do about it.
Sir, in the Harvard Student Handbook,
which is distributed to each freshman,
under the heading "Standards of Conduct
in the Harvard Community,"
it says the college expects all students
to be honest and forthcoming
in their dealings
with members in this community.
Students are required
to respect public and private ownership.
Instances of theft,
misappropriation, or...
- Anne?
- Yes, sir?
Punch me in the face. Go ahead.
...or unauthorized use
will result in disciplinary action,
including the requirement
to withdraw from the college.
You memorized that instead of doing what?
What my brother and I came here today
to ask of you, respectfully...
Sir, it's against university rules
to steal from another student.
You spoke to your House Master?
Yes, the House Master made
a recommendation to the Ad Board.
But the Ad Board won't see us.
You tried dealing with
the other student directly?
Mr. Zuckerberg hasn't responded
to our e-mails or phone calls
for the last two weeks.
He doesn't answer his door at Kirkland.
The closest I've come
to seeing him face-to-face
is when I chased him
through Harvard Square.
- You chased him?
- I saw him, and I know he saw me.
I went after him, and he disappeared.
- I don't see this as a university issue.
- Of course it's a university issue.
There's a code of ethics
and an honor code.
You enter into a code of ethics
with the university, not each other.
I'm sorry, President Summers.
What you just said makes no sense to me.
I'm devastated by that.
My brother means, if Mark Zuckerberg
walked into our dorm room
and stole our computer,
it's be a university issue.
I really don't know.
This office doesn't handle petty larceny.
This isn't petty larceny.
This idea is potentially worth
millions of dollars.
- Millions?
- Yes.
You're letting
your imagination run away with you.
Sir, I don't think
you're in a position to make that call.
I was the U.S. Treasury Secretary.
I'm in some position to make that call.
Letting our imaginations run away with us
is what we were told to do
in your freshman address.
Then I suggest
that you let your imaginations
run away with you on a new project.
- You would?
- Everyone at Harvard invents something.
Harvard undergraduates believe
that inventing a job
is better than finding a job.
So I'll suggest again that the two of you
come up with a new new project.
I'm sorry, sir, but that's not the point.
Please, arrive at the point.
You don't have to be
an intellectual property expert
to understand right and wrong.
You're saying that I don't?
- Of course not, sir.
- I'm saying that.
- Really?
- Sir.
Anne, how did they get this appointment?
Colleagues of their father.
Let me tell you something,
Mr. Winklevoss, Mr. Winklevoss,
since you're
on the subject of right and wrong.
This action, this meeting,
the two of you being here is wrong.
It's not worthy of Harvard.
It's not what Harvard saw in you.
You don't get special treatment.
- We never asked...
- Just start another project?
- Like a diorama for a science fair?
- If you have a problem with that...
- We never asked for special treatment.
- The courts are always at your disposal.
Anything else I can do for you?
- Take the Student Handbook and shove it...
- Ty.
Thank you for your time, sir.
Whoops, broke your 335-year-old doorknob.
Eduardo, spring break,
you and Mr. Zuckerberg went to New York.
- Yes.
- What was the purpose of the trip?
Well, as CFO, I had set up
some meetings with potential advertisers.
Who paid for the trip?
It was paid for out of the $1000 account
I had set up a few months earlier.
At this point, your $1000 was the only
money that had been put into the company?
- Yes.
- How did you feel the meetings went?
- They went terribly.
- Why?
Mark was asleep.
I was not asleep.
Can I rephrase my answer?
I wish he'd been asleep.
So we're in 29 schools now,
with over 75,000 members.
People who go on The Facebook
tend to stay on longer
than almost any other website.
Now here's the most impressive statistic.
Ninety-one percent of people
who try it once come back.
- If you'll allow me...
- Excuse me one second.
What sound is he making?
Is that like a tsk?
It wasn't a tsk.
It was...
Like a glottal stop.
Almost a gag reflex.
Guys, what is this?
There was one more meeting
scheduled for the New York trip.
Yes, a dinner,
set up through my girlfriend at the time.
Would you say that
Mark was excited about this meeting?
Yes. Very.
- They're not gonna card us.
- They might.
- Look around.
- It'll be embarrassing.
- Tell him they're not gonna card us.
- They're not gonna card us.
- Mark.
- You gonna talk about ads again?
Unless you're
the Ballet Theater of Hartford,
the purpose of a business
is to make a profit.
It isn't a business yet.
That's tough for me, because my job...
Never mind.
He's 25 minutes late.
He founded Napster when he was 19.
He can be late.
- He's not a god.
- Then what is he?
He's 25 minutes late.
I think Wardo's jealous.
I honestly wasn't jealous.
I was nervous.
- Why?
- I didn't know him at all.
But I had done a search
and I'd asked around.
And he struck me as kind of a...
A wild card.
Why?
He crashed out of two pretty big
Internet companies in spectacular fashion.
- He has a reputation with drugs.
- He also founded the companies.
We don't need him.
He's here.
No, no, take your time.
- And he does own a watch.
- Stop it.
Hey.
- I'm Sean Parker.
- How do you do?
You must be Eduardo,
and Christy, and Mark.
- Great to meet you.
- You don't have anything in front of you.
- No.
- Tori.
- We were waiting.
- Hey, baby boy.
- Can you bring out some things?
The lacquered pork
with that ginger confit. Tuna tartare?
And lobster claws. That'll get us started.
Christy, what do you like to drink?
An appletini.
Great. Four of those.
From that point on, it was a Sean-athon.
The question was,
"What did you talk about?"
He took us through
his episode with Napster.
I didn't wanna spend my 20s
as a professional defendant.
Who knew? The music industry
doesn't have a sense of humor.
We tried to sell the company
to pay the 35 million
they said we owed in royalties,
but I guess to them,
that was a little like
selling a stolen car
to pay for the stolen gas.
So we said screw it, declared bankruptcy.
But you made a name for yourself.
And you are dry.
- Tori.
- No, no, I'm good.
Then he went on
to his second business venture,
which was an online Rolodex
that he got thrown out of by Case Equity.
And I wanted to do it nice this time.
I put on a tie and I shined my shoes.
But nobody wants
to take orders from a kid.
Let me tell you what happens to
a 20-year-old at the top of a hot dot-com.
- I'm not a psychiatrist, but...
- I'm glad we got that on the record.
You're not a psychiatrist, but what?
A psychiatrist would say
that he was paranoid.
They'll hire private detectives
who'll follow you day and night.
You're a target for high-priced escorts.
I can't prove it,
but I know they tap my phones.
Whatever it is that's gonna trip you up,
you've done already.
Private behavior is a relic
of a time gone by.
And if somehow you've managed
to live your life like the Dalai Lama,
they'll make shit up.
Because they don't want you,
they want your idea.
They want you
to say "thank you" while you...
Excuse me... Wipe your chin and walk away.
- That's what happened to you?
- And delusional.
Yes.
But there'll be payback at Case.
I brought down the record companies
with Napster. Case will suffer too.
Sorry, you didn't bring down
the record companies. They won.
- In court.
- Yeah.
You wanna buy a Tower Records, Eduardo?
And he told story after story
about life in Silicon Valley,
and parties at Stanford, and down in LA,
and friends who'd become millionaires.
But mostly how Mark had to...
He had to come to California.
And then he got around to The Facebook.
So tell me about your progress.
Well, we're in 29 schools now.
We got over 75,000 members.
- Tell me about the strategy you're using.
- Okay.
For instance, we wanted Baylor, in Texas,
but Baylor already had
a social network on campus,
so instead of going right after them,
we made a list
of every school in 100 miles.
Put The Facebook there first.
The Baylor kids saw
their friends on our site and we were in.
The Little Bighorn. Smart.
- Thanks, that was mine.
- Easy.
You know what? Settle an argument for us.
I say we start making money
from The Facebook.
Mark doesn't want advertising.
Who's right?
Well...
Neither of you yet. The Facebook is cool.
That's what it's got going for it.
- Yeah.
- You don't wanna ruin it with ads.
- Ads aren't cool.
- Exactly.
Like you're throwing the greatest party,
and someone says it's gotta be over by 11.
That's exactly right.
- You don't know what the thing is yet.
- Exactly.
How big it can get, how far it can go.
This is no time to take your chips down.
A million dollars isn't cool.
- You know what's cool?
- You?
"A billion dollars."
And that shut everybody up.
And that's where you're headed.
A billion-dollar valuation.
Unless you take bad advice, in which case
you may as well have come up with
a chain of successful yogurt shops.
When you go fishing, you can catch
a lot of fish or you can catch a big fish.
Ever walk into a guy's den
and see a picture of him next to 14 trout?
- No, he has a 3000-pound marlin.
- Yep.
- Good analogy.
- Okay.
We all know marlins
don't really weigh 3000 pounds.
Have you seen big ones?
No, but I don't think he's holding
a marlin the size of a Range Rover.
That would be a really big fish
and a very strong guy.
We're getting away from the point.
I don't have a dog in this fight.
I'm just a fan who came to say hi.
He owned Mark after that dinner.
He picked up the check,
told Mark they'd talk again soon,
and he was gone.
But not before he made
his biggest contribution to the company.
Drop the "The."
Just "Facebook."
It's cleaner.
Shit.
Goodbye, sweetie.
Yeah.
That's gotta be some kind
of land speed record for talking.
You wanna end the party at 11.
- I'm trying to pay for the party.
- There won't be a party unless it's cool.
So, what do you think?
Sure, let's drop the "The."
I meant to catching the marlin
instead of the 14 trout.
Doesn't that sound good?
If you're a trout.
I'll enter this into the record.
Incorporation papers for Facebook,
an LLC registered in Florida.
- Why Florida?
- It's where my family lives.
And ask the respondent to stipulate
that the articles of incorporation
state the ownership as follows:
65 percent for Mark Zuckerberg,
30 percent for Eduardo Saverin
and 5 percent for Dustin Moskovitz.
Yeah, we stipulate.
- And that was April 13th, 2004.
- You can mark it.
You have anything here?
Yes. Thank you.
Mr. Saverin, have you ever done anything
that might be considered
legitimate grounds for termination?
No.
You never did anything
to embarrass the company
or even seriously jeopardize it?
- No.
- No?
No.
You were accused of animal cruelty.
- Wait.
- You weren't?
This is not happening.
I have here an article from The Crimson...
Jesus Christ.
- I can't have this.
- Come on, man.
This is bullshit.
This is another club playing a prank.
I'd gotten into the Phoenix.
I'd been accepted.
And as part of my initiation,
I had to, for one week,
carry with me at all times
and take care of a chicken.
They identify you
as one of the founders of Facebook.
"Junior Eduardo Saverin..."
I'm no expert, but being connected
to torturing animals is bad for business.
I did not torture the chicken.
I don't torture chickens. Are you crazy?
No, and settle down, please.
I have here an article from The Crimson...
- This is scathing.
- 956.
I was having dinner in
the Kirkland dining hall with Mark,
and I had the chicken with me.
I had to have the chicken
with me at all times.
This was college.
- Somebody's gonna have to answer for this.
- 969.
The dining hall
was serving chicken for dinner,
and I had to feed my chicken, so I...
I took little pieces of chicken,
and I gave it to the chicken.
Someone must have seen me.
Next thing I knew,
I was being accused of forced cannibalism.
I didn't know you couldn't do that.
I dealt with
the various animal rights groups.
the associate dean of the college.
- This was all resolved.
- 988.
Someone from the Porc
or the Fly must've reported it.
For all I know, it was the Winklevosses.
All right, just forget about it.
This is absurd.
I'm being accused of animal cruelty.
- It's better to be accused of necrophilia.
- It is better.
Now I have to explain this to my father.
I have to explain this to everybody.
What is happening on that?
I have my final for Contemporary Art.
I haven't been to class.
- I have to write about four paintings.
- That's a Facebook page?
I opened it under an alias,
posted the paintings, asked for comments.
Once in a while,
I stir the pot to get debate going.
Mr. Zuckerberg was cheating
on his final exam?
- I'd rather not answer that, Gretchen.
- And why not?
Because I'm not suing him
for cheating on his final exam.
That's not what friends do.
You just told us he was cheating.
You told your lawyers
I was torturing animals?
No, he didn't tell us about it at all.
Our litigators are capable
of finding a Crimson article.
When we raised the subject with him,
he defended you.
Nine ninety-three. We are so close.
Oh, yeah, that reminds me,
we're gonna need more money, Wardo.
Yeah, no, I agree.
More servers, more help.
I'm interviewing two interns
to come to Palo Alto.
- We have to pay them something.
- What?
I found a house for rent
two blocks from the Stanford campus.
It is perfect. It's got a pool.
When did you decide
to go to California for summer?
When did I actually decide?
Was it in the middle
of the Sean Parker Variety Hour?
He was right,
California's the place we've gotta be.
What, you're Jed Clampett?
You got The Beverly Hillbillies in Brazil?
Yeah, got the show in Brazil.
It was genius.
- What is your problem with Sean?
- He doesn't bring anything to the table.
He doesn't have money.
Dustin's a better programmer.
- He's got connections to VCs.
- We don't need VCs, we need advertisers.
- I have connections to VCs.
- No real players.
And as somebody who's
just really embarrassed the company...
- It was the Winklevosses, Mark.
- Hang on.
Hit "refresh."
One hundred fifty thousand and four.
One hundred fifty thousand members, Wardo.
- Congratulations.
You don't think it was strange
that he was followed
by private detectives?
- Who came up with nothing.
- Enough to get him out of the company.
- Drugs, girls.
- We don't know that's true.
- You read about it.
- I read about you torturing birds.
Okay, don't fish eat other fish?
The marlins and the trout?
What's he talking about?
I'm interviewing interns
at 10 tomorrow night in the CS lab.
Get on board with this.
You know,
I don't really know what else to say.
You can do one more.
One more.
- Wardo.
- Yo, Mark.
What's going on?
They have 10 minutes
to access a Python web server,
expose its SSL encryption,
and intercept all traffic over its port.
They're hacking.
Yes, behind a Pix Firewall Emulator.
But here's the beauty.
- I didn't understand anything you said.
- I know.
What's the beauty?
Every tenth line of code,
they drink a shot.
Hacking's stealth, so every time
the server detects an intrusion,
the candidate responsible
has to drink a shot.
I ran a program that has a pop-up window
appear simultaneously
on all five computers.
The last to hit the window drinks a shot.
Plus every three minutes
they all drink a shot.
- Three minutes.
- Drink now.
Hey, can I ask,
what part of the intern's job
will they need to do drunk?
You're right, a more relevant test might
be keeping a chicken alive for a week.
That was mean.
- Here.
- What is this?
I opened a new account
and put $18,000 in it.
Will that get you through the summer?
- Done.
- Mark?
Right here.
Welcome to Facebook.
- $18,000?
- Yes.
In addition to the $1000
you'd already put up.
- Yes.
- A total of $19,000 now.
- Hang on.
I'm checking your math on that.
Yes, I got the same thing.
May I continue?
After expressing misgivings
about Mr. Zuckerberg taking the company
and moving it
to California for the summer,
why did you put $18,000
in an account for his use?
I figured we were partners.
I wanted to be a team player.
I figured Mark, Dustin,
and the new interns could work on the site
while I was generating
advertiser interest in New York.
But mostly I figured,
how much could possibly go wrong
in three months?
Go, go, go.
- I didn't die.
- I know.
- I made it.
- You did.
Okay, ready?
- That was like an eight.
- That was like a two.
- It was better than that.
- Yeah.
- I'm okay.
- You sure?
Yeah.
Yikes.
- That's the doorbell.
- I didn't know we had a doorbell.
- Andrew, get the door.
- No, he's wired in.
That's gonna cut
into your security deposit.
- Andrew.
- Not now.
Good boy.
- Sean?
- Mark?
- Do you live here?
- Yeah.
- Do you?
- Across the street.
- We saw the chimney.
- Yeah.
- Is anybody hurt?
- No. You live across the street?
I'm Sharon.
This is my... Sharon.
She lives across the street.
I was helping move out.
- We saw the chimney.
- We had a zip line to the pool.
You came to California.
- Yeah.
- You made the right choice.
Here you go.
Sharon?
- Sorry. I didn't know...
- No problem.
- Here you go.
- No, wait.
This house and this team are great.
It's exactly what it should be.
I'm Sean Parker.
Oh, he's wired in.
That's what I'm talking about.
Where's Eduardo?
He got an internship in New York.
Eduardo didn't come out?
I was crashing there for a bit
while I take care of some things,
but she's done for the summer,
so she's back at her parents' place.
- The homeless rock star of Palo Alto.
- All right.
What's your plan for the summer?
Mark?
Sorry, I was looking at the architecture.
I asked what your plan...
A hundred schools
by the end of the summer.
- We're gonna go to the restroom.
- Okay.
I'll go with you.
Your date looks so familiar to me.
- She looks familiar to a lot of people.
- What do you mean?
A Stanford MBA named Roy Raymond
wants to buy his wife lingerie,
but he's too embarrassed
to shop for it in a department store.
He comes up with an idea
for a high-end place
that doesn't make you feel like a pervert.
He gets a $40,000 bank loan,
borrows another 40,000 from his in-laws,
opens a store,
and calls it Victoria's Secret.
Makes a half million dollars
his first year.
Starts a catalog, opens three more stores,
and after five years,
he sells the company to Leslie Wexner
and The Limited for $4 million.
Happy ending, right?
Except two years later,
the company's worth $500 million,
and Roy Raymond jumps off
the Golden Gate Bridge.
Poor guy just wanted to buy his wife
a pair of thigh-highs, you know?
Was that a parable?
My date's a Victoria's Secret model.
That's why she looks familiar to you.
- God.
- Don't be impressed by all this.
I read your blog.
You know, no, that was for web cretins.
You know why I started Napster?
The girl I loved in high school was
with the co-captain
of the varsity lacrosse team,
and I wanted to take her from him.
So I decided
to come up with the next big thing.
- I didn't know that.
- Napster wasn't a failure.
I changed the music industry
for better and for always.
It may not have been good business,
but it pissed a lot of people off.
And isn't that
what your Facemash was about?
They're scared of me, pal.
They're gonna be scared of you.
What the VCs want is to say,
"Good idea, kid.
The grown-ups will take it from here."
But not this time. This is our time.
This time, you're gonna hand them
a business card that says,
"I'm CEO, bitch."
That's what I want for you.
So where the hell is Eduardo?
- He's in New York.
- Sucking up to ad execs.
- He's got an...
- An internship.
The company's here.
A billion-dollar company's here.
- Do you live and breathe Facebook?
- Yes.
I know you do.
Wardo wants to be a businessman.
For all I know, he's gonna be a good one.
But he shouldn't be in New York,
kissing Madison Avenue's ass.
This is a once-in-a-generation,
"holy shit" idea.
And the water
under the Golden Gate is freezing cold.
Look at my face,
and tell me
I don't know what I'm talking about.
Do you ever think about that girl?
What girl?
The girl from high school
who was with the lacrosse thing.
No.
If you guys are gonna talk
about bandwidth, we need shots.
- A hundred schools by the end of summer?
- Yeah.
Tell you what. Gesture of good faith.
While you're getting into 100 schools,
I'll put you on two continents.
Two...
If you don't have a place to crash,
you should come and live with us.
Let's line up some shots.
Excuse me.
Yes, sir.
You can take this away
and bring back the 1942.
Absolutely, Mr. Parker.
Attention.
Go.
At the barrier, Hollandia is
leading Harvard University by one length.
Approaching the grandstands,
Hollandia maintains a lead
of three-quarters of a length.
Come on.
Whatever.
- Mr. Winklevoss.
- Tyler.
- Tremendous race.
- Thank you.
- And this is my brother, Cameron.
- Excellent.
Sir? His Royal Highness Prince Albert.
Your Highness,
Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss.
Of course. Brilliant race.
I've never seen a race that close.
Yes, Your Highness.
My grandfather, Jack Kelly,
was one of the premier rowers of his day.
I've been coming to Henley for 30 years.
I'd never seen a race that close.
Have you? Have you seen a race that close?
No, Your Highness.
Mile-and-a-half races are
more commonly won by a boat length or two.
Yes, that's absolutely right.
Brutally close.
May I introduce my teammates?
I'm sorry. You'll have to excuse us.
On to the Dutch.
Sorry you flew out here to see that.
Wouldn't have missed it, brother.
How was the royalty?
I wanted him
to tell me how close the race was.
Just brutal, brutally close.
Brutally excruciating. Jesus.
He's prince of a country
the size of Nantucket. Relax, it's fine.
- Boys. Divya.
- Dad.
- Mr. Winklevoss.
- That was a tough beat.
I'm sorry that
you and Mom flew here to see that.
No, never apologize to me
for losing a race like that.
Never apologize to anyone
- Boys.
- Mr. Kenwright.
Dad, this is Mr. Kenwright,
head of the host family for this week.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- Good to meet you.
I had a phone chat with my daughter.
She and her friends
are already talking about the race,
which they've just seen
via their computers.
A new website called Facebook.
Do you have this in America?
I'm gonna find your mother.
- I say something wrong?
- She doesn't go to school in the States?
No, Cambridge. Major in French literature.
I wasn't aware there was such a thing.
They have Facebook at Cambridge?
And Oxford
and the London School of Economics,
where her friends are.
That's awesome.
Good race, boys.
Take the bitter with the better, eh?
I'm gonna watch the race film.
If this is online, I wanna see it.
Stop it.
Stop it, Cam.
Knock it off.
I don't mind that we lost
to the Dutch today by less than a second.
That was a good race.
That was a fair race.
And they'll see us again.
What I mind, and what you should mind,
is showing up on Monday
for a race that was run on Sunday.
We tried talking to him ourselves,
writing a letter, the Ad Board,
and talking
to the president of the university.
Now, I am asking you for the last time,
let's take the considerable resources
at our disposal
and sue him in federal court.
Come on.
I need a real drink.
Screw it.
Let's gut the fucking nerd.
That's what I'm talking about.
No, no, no...
But check it out, I saw him today.
Manningham, Mitchell Manningham,
my Case Equity guy.
Hang on. Are you guys
using Spikes or Ghost Missiles?
We're just shooting at each other.
Use Sweet Kamikazes.
Like we know what that is.
I saw him getting into his Turbo Carrera,
and he saw me too.
I know he did.
Don't. Don't sweat it. I'm on a landline.
Bong hit.
Does anybody hear that banging?
You don't hear anything.
You're writing code.
Dude, somebody's at the door.
It's not a dish best served cold.
It's best served immediately
and relentlessly.
I'm gonna call you back.
What's up?
Mark was supposed to pick me up
at the airport. I've been calling him.
He was on a 36-hour coding tear,
so he took a nap for a couple of hours.
What happened here?
Not happened. Happening.
- The next big thing.
- Hey, Wardo.
Hey, man.
- Back to work.
- Okay.
The more bad I get at this,
the more wasted I get.
- I mean, the more wasted that I get...
- We understand.
How old are they, Sean?
It's not polite to ask.
Sean, how old are they?
You think you know me, right?
I've read enough.
Know how much I've read about you?
Nothing.
- Wardo.
- Hey, man.
- I waited an hour for you at the airport.
- What time is it?
Midnight, or 3 a.m. in New York,
where I just came from.
You gotta see the new stuff we got.
Dustin, show him the Wall.
I'm calling it the Wall.
Forget the Wall.
Tell him about the meeting I set up.
You know Peter Thiel?
- Nope.
- No reason you should.
He just runs a $2-billion hedge fund
called Clarium Capital.
- He set up meetings?
- Thiel might make an angel investment.
I don't care if he's an actual angel.
Why is he setting up meetings?
You've had a long flight.
No, I had a long wait
on the tarmac at JFK,
then a long wait
at the passenger unloading zone at SFO,
and in between there was a long flight.
I'm the business end of this company.
And he is a house guest,
living here rent-free
on a very generous grant
from the Eduardo Saverin Foundation.
I heard about your big-ticket ad buys.
Gary's Tuxedos.
- Hey.
- Harvard Bartending Course.
You're a step away
from bagging Snookies Cookies, I feel it.
- You wanna talk to me alone for a minute?
- Sure.
Wait, which one am I?
Bong hit.
- I'm so high.
- No, you're not.
So how's it going?
How's the internship? How's Christy?
How's the internship?
Yeah.
Mark, Jesus, I quit the internship.
We talked about this on the phone.
I quit on my first day.
I do remember you saying that.
So how is Christy?
Christy's crazy.
Is that fun?
No. I mean, she's actually psychotic.
She's insanely jealous, she's irrational,
and I'm frightened of her.
Still, it's nice you have a girlfriend.
I do not want that guy representing
himself as part of this company.
You gotta move here.
It's where it's all happening.
- Hear what I said?
- Connections, energy...
Mark, you got...
I'm afraid if you don't come,
you'll get left behind.
I want... I need you out here.
Please, don't tell him I said that.
- What did you say?
- It's moving faster than we ever imagined.
- What did you mean?
- It's moving fast. Sean thinks we have...
- He's not part of this company.
- We have 300,000 members.
- I'm aware of that.
- We're in 160 schools, five in Europe.
- I'm the CFO.
- We need more servers than I expected.
We need more programmers and more money.
He set up the Thiel meeting.
He set up meetings all over town.
- He set up other meetings?
- Yes.
- Without me knowing.
- You're in New York.
I'm in New York,
riding subways 14 hours a day.
- Trying to find advertisers.
- How's it going so far?
What did you mean, "get left behind"?
- Hi.
- Can I help you?
I'd like to freeze this bank account
and cancel all existing checks
and lines of credit.
- May I see some ID, please?
- Yeah, sure.
Sean, he'll be right with you.
No problem.
This is where
they filmed Towering Inferno.
That's comforting.
Hey, guys. Come on back.
- She offer you some waters?
- Oh, yeah. We're cool.
Sean, how are you? Come on in.
- You must be Mark.
- Hi.
We took a look at everything,
and congratulations.
We're gonna start you off
with a $500,000 investment.
Maurice is gonna talk to you
about some corporate restructuring.
We'll file as a corporation in Delaware,
come up with a stock structure
that allows for new investors.
Now, let me ask you something.
Who's Eduardo Saverin?
Jesus Christ.
- When did you get back?
- You scared me. I need you to knock.
When did you get back?
I got back this afternoon.
When were you gonna call me?
Chris, it was kind of a rough trip,
and I was tired...
Yeah, or answer one of my 47 texts.
Did you know I sent 47 texts?
I did, and I thought
that was incredibly normal behavior.
Are you mocking me?
I brought you a present.
Why does your status say "single"
on your Facebook page?
What?
Why does your relationship status
say "single" on your Facebook page?
I was single when I set up the page.
And you just never bothered to change it?
- What?
- I don't know how.
Do I look stupid to you?
No, calm down.
You're asking me
to believe the CFO of Facebook
doesn't know how to change
his relationship status on Facebook?
It's embarrassing, so take it
as a sign of trust that I would tell you.
- Go to hell.
- Take it easy.
No, you didn't change it
so you could screw Silicon Valley sluts
every time you go see Mark.
Not even remotely true,
and I promise, the Silicon Valley sluts
don't care what anyone's
relationship status is on Facebook.
Please, open your present.
Your phone does work.
It's Mark.
Okay, this is gonna be tricky.
Open your present. It's a silk scarf.
Have you ever seen me wear a scarf?
This'll be your first.
Yeah.
- You froze our account?
- I did.
- You froze the account.
- To get your attention.
You jeopardized the entire company.
Your actions could've destroyed
everything I've been working on.
- We have been working on.
- Without money, the site can't function.
The difference between Facebook
and everybody else,
we don't crash ever.
If the servers are down for even a day,
our reputation is irreversibly destroyed.
- Look.
- Users are fickle. Friendster proved that.
Even a few people leaving
would reverberate through the user base.
The users are interconnected.
That is the point.
College kids are online
because their friends are online.
If one domino goes,
the other dominoes go. Get it?
I am not going back
to the Caribbean Night at A-E-Pi.
Holy shit.
What is wrong with you?
Did you like being nobody?
Did you like being a joke?
Wanna go back to that?
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
That was the act of a child,
not a businessman, not a friend.
You know how embarrassing it was
for me to try to cash a check today?
I won't go back to that life.
- Maybe you were frustrated.
- Yeah.
- Maybe you were angry.
- I was.
But I am willing
to let bygones be bygones,
because, Wardo, I've got some good news.
I'm sorry.
I was angry, and maybe it was childish,
but I had to get your attention.
Wardo, I said, I got some good news.
What is it?
Peter Thiel made an angel investment
of half a million dollars.
What?
Half a million dollars.
And he's setting us up in an office.
They wanna reincorporate the company.
They wanna meet you.
They need your signature
on some documents.
Get on the first flight
back to San Francisco.
I need my CFO.
I'm on my way.
- Wardo?
- Yeah?
We did it.
Wardo?
You're going back there already?
Yes.
And also I'm breaking up with you.
Somebody stop her.
Four documents.
First two are
common stock purchase agreements,
allowing you to buy stock
in the newly reincorporated Facebook,
as opposed to the old shares,
which are now worthless.
The third is an exchange agreement,
allowing you
to exchange old shares for new shares.
And then finally
a voter holding agreement.
How many shares of stock will I own?
- 1,328,334.
- Jesus Christ.
That represents
a 34.4-percent ownership share.
Why the increase
from the original 30 percent?
You may need to dilute it
to award shares to new investors.
- I love working with business majors.
- I'm telling you.
- Economics.
- Right.
You should know that Mark has already
taken his percentage from 60 down to 51.
Well, Mark doesn't care about money
and he needs to be protected.
Dustin Moskovitz owns 6.81 percent.
Sean Parker, 6.47 percent.
- I can live with that.
- And Peter Thiel, 7 percent.
Would you like to use my pen?
Eduardo?
Please, repeat the question?
It's an outrageously leading question.
You want to hear it twice?
- Yes. Would you read it back, please?
- Well, go ahead.
"Counsel: 'When you signed the documents,
were you aware
that you were signing
your own death certificate?"'
No.
It was insanely stupid of me not to have
my own lawyers look over all the...
In all honesty,
I thought they were my lawyers.
I was your only friend.
You had one friend.
- My father won't even look at me.
- Okay.
Did Mr. Zuckerberg say anything
to you after you signed the papers?
There was a lot of handshaking,
a lot of congratulations.
He'd already told me that he
wouldn't be coming back to school
for at least a semester,
so we were saying goodbye for a while.
Then before I left he said...
You gotta come back.
Somewhere around
the end of November or early December.
Peter's throwing a party
when we hit a million members.
It'll be out of control.
You gotta come for it.
A million members?
Yeah.
Remember the algorithm
on the window at Kirkland?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll be here.
You sure about this?
You're 20 minutes late.
Walk in, say you overslept,
and didn't have time to get dressed.
They're gonna pitch you.
Case Equity will pitch you.
They'll beg you to take their money.
You're gonna nod, nod, nod...
And then you're gonna say,
"Which one of you is Roth?"
No, not Roth. Manningham.
"Which one of you is Mitchell Manningham?"
He'll say, "I am."
And then you say,
"Sean Parker says, 'Fuck you.'"
Walk out.
Okay.
In late November,
I got the e-mail from Mark
telling me to come out
for the millionth-member party.
What else did the e-mail say?
That we had to have a business meeting.
That Mark and Sean had played
some kind of revenge stunt on Case Equity,
and Manningham was so impressed,
he was now making an investment offer
that was hard to turn down.
So I went to California,
and I went straight to the new offices.
I didn't know whether to dress
for the party or for the business meeting,
so I kind of dressed for both.
- But it didn't matter.
- Why not?
Because I wasn't called there
for either one.
What were you called there for?
An ambush.
Mr. Saverin. Hey, right over here.
Hey, man.
- How are you?
- Good. How are you?
- Good, good, good.
- Good to see you.
At first I thought he was joking.
Giving me more contracts to sign.
But then I started reading.
Wait, what is this?
Well, as you know, we had
some new investors that have come in...
What is this?
Mr. Saverin.
Mark.
- Mark?
- He's wired in.
- Sorry?
- Is he?
- Yes.
- How about now? You still wired in?
- Call security.
You issued 24 million new shares of stock.
You were told that if new investors...
How much were your shares diluted?
How much were his?
What was Mr. Zuckerberg's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Mr. Moskovitz's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Sean Parker's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What was Peter Thiel's
ownership share diluted down to?
It wasn't.
And what was
your ownership share diluted down to?
Point-zero-three percent.
- You signed the papers.
- You set me up.
You blame me because
you were the business head of the company,
and you made a bad deal
with your own company?
It's like I'm not part of Facebook.
Won't be like that.
You're not part of Facebook.
My name's on the masthead.
- You might wanna check again.
- Because I froze the account?
Think we'd let you
parade around in ridiculous suits?
- Pretending you run this company?
- Sorry, my Prada's at the cleaner's.
Along with my hoodie
and my fuck-you flip-flops,
you pretentious douchebag.
Security's here. You'll be leaving now.
- I'm not signing those papers.
- We will get the signature.
This isn't about me
getting into the Phoenix.
You... You did it. I knew you did it.
You planted that story about the chicken.
- I didn't plant the story.
- What's he talking about?
- You had me accused of animal cruelty.
- What's the chicken?
I'll bet what you hated the most
is that they identified me
as a co-founder of Facebook.
Which I am. You better lawyer up, asshole.
Because I'm not coming back
for 30 percent.
I'm coming back for everything.
- Get him out of here.
- It's okay, I'm going.
Hang on.
Almost forgot.
Here's your $19,000.
I wouldn't cash it, though.
I drew it on the account you froze.
I like standing next to you, Sean.
It makes me look so tough.
Well...
That's it.
That's our show for tonight, people.
I wanna see everyone here
geared up for a party.
Walk into that club
like it's the Macy's Parade.
Mackey, put it up on the big screen.
We've gotta almost be there.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
You were kind of rough on him.
That's life in the NFL.
You didn't have to be that rough on him.
- Listen, I put him...
- Sean.
You didn't have to be that rough on him.
He almost killed it.
I'll send flowers.
Speaking of flowers,
I'm putting together a party
after the party at Kappa Eta Sigma.
Ashleigh's a sister.
- Ashleigh?
- The intern.
Yeah, I know who she is. Are you guys...?
Ashleigh? Me? No.
Well, a little bit.
Why?
- No, nothing, I just...
- Excuse me. Mark?
- We were just talking about you.
- You're doing a really good job.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
These came in for you.
Just put them on my desk.
What's the package?
Nothing.
- Mackey.
- Yes, sir.
Refresh.
Sweet.
And you're not a hugger.
I know.
One million.
Who's got champagne, huh?
I've got champagne.
The next transformative development,
a picture-sharing application.
A place where you view pictures
that coincide with your social life.
It is the true digitalization
of real life.
- You can use a CD.
- You can do it off of me.
You don't just go to a party anymore.
You go to a party with a digital camera.
Then your friends relive the party online.
And tagging. The idea...
Would this be easier without the bra?
It's worth finding out.
All right, shut the music down.
The party's over.
Everybody, go home.
I've spent hours watching
what people do when they log on.
- They check their friends' status updates.
- Wait. Why did the music stop?
Check to see which friends
changed their profiles, their photos.
What happened to the music?
We lived on farms.
Then we lived in cities.
Now we're going to live on the Internet.
Sean, stop.
I think something's going on downstairs.
Ladies and gentlemen,
can I have your attention, please?
It's time for you to go home.
The party is over.
Then it's all good.
- It's the cops.
- What?
Shit. Shit.
- Shit, shit, shit.
- Okay, it's okay. Be cool.
Good to see you, officer.
What can I do for you?
What's going on?
Was the music too loud?
We were having a celebration.
Miss, button your blouse.
I can tell them to turn the music down.
That's not mine.
We're gonna need identification.
Keep your hands where we can see them.
Oh, my God.
You got anything else in your pockets?
No, sir. No.
- Don't be stupid, now.
- I don't, I don't. I...
What's this?
That's an EpiPen.
- And this?
- That's my inhaler.
How old are you?
Twenty-one.
- Twenty-one.
- I'm 21.
Lying only makes it worse.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have lied.
Hello.
Listen, something's happened.
Shit.
No, it's all right.
It's gonna be all right.
I posted bond,
and I wasn't doing anything.
I've got allergies.
Interns.
It was just a party.
This is gonna be news, Sean.
It's gonna be online any second.
I know.
You know with an intern...
No, it's cool. I have it under control.
I will get it under control.
I will call someone
and see what the next move is.
But this is gonna be news now.
You don't think
Wardo was involved, do you?
- I mean, do you think...?
- No.
Or Manningham. One of them. Somebody.
Somebody sent the coke in there,
because it got in there.
You believe me. This is gonna be fine.
Right?
Go home, Sean.
Mark?
Mark.
We're done for the day.
Yeah. Yeah, I was just sitting here.
What happened to Sean?
He still owns 7 percent of the company.
All you had all day was that salad.
Do you wanna get something to eat?
I can't.
I'm not a bad guy.
I know that.
When there's emotional testimony,
I assume 85 percent of it is exaggeration.
And the other 15?
Perjury.
Creation myths need a devil.
What happens now?
Sy and the others are having a steak
on University Avenue.
Then they'll come back to the office,
and start working on
a settlement agreement to present to you.
- They're gonna settle?
- Oh, yeah.
- You're gonna have to pay a little extra.
- Why?
So these guys sign
a nondisclosure agreement.
They say one unflattering word in public,
you own their wife and kids.
I invented Facebook.
I'm talking about a jury.
I specialize in voir dire, jury selection.
What a jury sees
when they look at a defendant.
Clothes, hair,
speaking style, likability...
Likability.
I've been licensed to practice law
for all of 20 months,
and I could get a jury to believe
that you planted the story
about Eduardo and the chicken.
Watch what else.
Why weren't you
at Sean's sorority party that night?
- You think I called the police?
- Doesn't matter.
I asked the question.
Now everybody's thinking it.
You've lost your jury
in the first 10 minutes.
Farm animals.
Yeah.
I was drunk and angry and stupid.
And blogging.
Pay them.
In the scheme of things,
it's a speeding ticket.
That's what Sy will tell you tomorrow.
Would anybody mind if I stay
and use the computer for a minute?
I can't imagine it would be a problem.
Thanks.
I appreciate your help today.
You're not an asshole, Mark.
You're just trying so hard to be.